<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><resolution xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm/2.0 https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/2.0/uslm-2.0.0.xsd" xml:lang="en" class="mimicGPOPrint">
<meta><dc:title>115 SJRES 1 ENR: Approving the location of a memorial to commemorate and honor the members of the Armed Forces who served on active duty in support of Operation Desert Storm or Operation Desert Shield.</dc:title><dc:type>Senate Joint Resolution</dc:type><docNumber>1</docNumber><dc:creator>United States Senate</dc:creator><processedBy>GPO Locator to USLM Converter 3.0.2, compiled on  2018/06/20 02:20:00;Stage2.20180611</processedBy><dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher><dc:format>text/xml</dc:format><dc:language>EN</dc:language><dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights><docStage>ENR</docStage><congress>115</congress><session>1</session><publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta><preface><dc:type>S. J. RES.</dc:type><docNumber>1</docNumber><congress style="-uslm-lc:I665502" value="115">One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session style="-uslm-lc:I665503" value="1">AT THE FIRST SESSION</session><enrolledDateline style="-uslm-lc:I665504">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolledDateline></preface>
<main>
<longTitle>
<docTitle style="-uslm-lc:I665505" class="centered fontsize18">Joint Resolution</docTitle>
<officialTitle style="-uslm-lc:I665511" class="centered fontsize8">Approving the location of a memorial to commemorate and honor the members of the Armed Forces who served on active duty in support of Operation Desert Storm or Operation Desert Shield.<br verticalSpace="08pt"/></officialTitle>
</longTitle>
<preamble><recital style="-uslm-lc:I650127">Whereas <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s8908/b/1">section 8908(b)(1) of title 40, United States Code</ref>, provides that the location of a commemorative work in Area I, as depicted on the map entitled “Commemorative Areas Washington, DC and Environs”, numbered 869/86501 B, and dated June 24, 2003, shall be deemed to be authorized only if a recommendation for the location is approved by law not later than 150 calendar days after the date on which Congress is notified of the recommendation;<br verticalSpace="03pt"/></recital><recital style="-uslm-lc:I650127">Whereas section 3093 of the Carl Levin and Howard P. “Buck” McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s8903">40 U.S.C. 8903 note</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Public Law 113–291</ref>) authorized the National Desert Storm Memorial Association to establish a memorial on Federal land in the District of Columbia, to honor the members of the Armed Forces who served on active duty in support of Operation Desert Storm or Operation Desert Shield; and<br verticalSpace="03pt"/></recital><recital style="-uslm-lc:I650127">Whereas the Secretary of the Interior has notified Congress of the determination of the Secretary of the Interior that the memorial should be located in Area I: Now, therefore, be it<br verticalSpace="03pt"/></recital><resolvingClause style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</resolvingClause></preamble>
<section class="inline">
<content class="inline"> That the location of a commemorative work to commemorate and honor the members of the Armed Forces who served on active duty in support of Operation Desert Storm or Operation Desert Shield authorized by section 3093 of the Carl Levin and Howard P. “Buck” McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s8903">40 U.S.C. 8903 note</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Public Law 113–291</ref>), within Area I, as depicted on the map entitled “Commemorative Areas Washington, DC and Environs”, numbered 869/86501 B, and dated June 24, 2003, is approved.</content>
</section>
</main>
<signatures>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></signature>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Vice President of the United States and  President of the Senate.</role></signature>
</signatures>
</resolution>