<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><resolution xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm/2.0 https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/2.0/uslm-2.0.0.xsd" xml:lang="en" class="mimicGPOPrint">
<meta><dc:title>115 SCONRES 2 ENR: Concurrent Resolution</dc:title><dc:type>Senate Concurrent Resolution</dc:type><docNumber>2</docNumber><dc:creator>United States Senate</dc:creator><processedBy>GPO Locator to USLM Converter 3.0.2, compiled on  2018/06/20 02:20:00;Stage2.20180611</processedBy><dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher><dc:format>text/xml</dc:format><dc:language>EN</dc:language><dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights><docStage>ENR</docStage><congress>115</congress><session>1</session><publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta><preface><dc:type>S. CON. RES.</dc:type><docNumber>2</docNumber><action>
<actionDescription style="-uslm-lc:I665516">Agreed to</actionDescription>
<date date="2017-01-03">January 3, 2017</date>
</action><congress style="-uslm-lc:I665502" value="115">One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session style="-uslm-lc:I665503" value="1">AT THE FIRST SESSION</session><enrolledDateline style="-uslm-lc:I665504">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolledDateline></preface>
<main>
<longTitle>
<docTitle style="-uslm-lc:I665505" class="centered fontsize18">Concurrent Resolution</docTitle>
</longTitle>
<resolvingClause class="inline" style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  Resolved by the Senate (the House of Representatives concurring),</resolvingClause>
<section class="inline">
<content class="inline"> That the two Houses of Congress shall meet in the Hall of the House of Representatives on Friday, the 6th day of January 2017, at 1 o’clock post meridian, pursuant to the requirements of the Constitution and laws relating to the election of President and Vice President of the United States, and the President of the Senate shall be their Presiding Officer; that two tellers shall be previously appointed by the President of the Senate on the part of the Senate and two by the Speaker on the part of the House of Representatives, to whom shall be handed, as they are opened by the President of the Senate, all the certificates and papers purporting to be certificates of the electoral votes, which certificates and papers shall be opened, presented, and acted upon in the alphabetical order of the States, beginning with the letter “A”; and said tellers, having then read the same in the presence and hearing of the two Houses, shall make a list of the votes as they shall appear from said certificates; and the votes having been ascertained and counted in the manner and according to the rules by law provided, the result of the same shall be delivered to the President of the Senate, who shall thereupon announce the state of the vote, which announcement shall be deemed a sufficient declaration of the persons, if any, elected President and Vice President of the United States, and, together with a list of the votes, be entered on the Journals of the two Houses.</content>
</section>
</main>
<signatures>
<signature><notation type="attestation" style="-uslm-lc:I650113">Attest:</notation><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Secretary of the Senate.</role></signature>
<signature><notation type="attestation" style="-uslm-lc:I650113">Attest:</notation><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Clerk of the House of Representatives.</role></signature>
</signatures>
</resolution>