<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="legislativeReport.css"?>
<legislativeReport  xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.1.1.xsd" xml:lang="en">
    <!-- This is sample content for the purposes of illustrating the elements used in USLM for legislative reports. This file should not be used
            for any other purposes as it is incomplete and may not be accurate. -->
    <reportMeta>
        <dc:title>H. Rept. 118-728: FOSTERING THE USE OF TECHNOLOGY TO UPHOLD REGULATORY EFFECTIVENESS IN SUPERVISION ACT</dc:title>
        <dc:date>2024-11-01</dc:date>
        <dc:type>House Legislative Report</dc:type>
        <docNumber>728</docNumber>
        <congress>118</congress>
        <session>2</session>
        <citableAs>H. Rept. 118-728</citableAs>
        <citableAs>House Report 118-728</citableAs>
        <citableAs>CRPT-118hrpt728</citableAs>
        <committee>Committee on Financial Services</committee>
        <currentChamber>House</currentChamber>
        <genre>legislative</genre>
        <cboCostEstimateLine>Y</cboCostEstimateLine>
        <accompanies>118hr7437</accompanies>
    </reportMeta>
    <reportPreface> 
        <layout class="reportHeader">
            <row><column class="topLeft"><congress>118th Congress</congress></column><column rowspan="2" class="leftBracket">}</column>
                <column rowspan="2" class="middle"><currentChamber>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</currentChamber></column>
                <column rowspan="2" class="rightBracket">{</column><column class="topRight smallCaps"><dc:type>Report</dc:type></column></row>
            <row><column class="bottomLeft italic"><session>2nd Session</session></column><column class="bottomRight"><docNumber>118–728</docNumber></column></row>
        </layout>
        <reportTitle>FOSTERING THE USE OF TECHNOLOGY TO UPHOLD REGULATORY EFFECTIVENESS IN SUPERVISION ACT</reportTitle>
        <action><date date="2024-11-01">November 1, 2024.—</date><actionDescription class="inline">Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the 
State of the Union and ordered to be printed</actionDescription></action>
        <action><actionDescription><sponsor bioGuideId="YYY">Mr. McHenry</sponsor>, from the <committee>Committee on Financial Services</committee>, submitted 
the following
<longTitle><docTitle>R E P O R T</docTitle>
<accompanies>[To accompany <affected><dc:type>H.R.</dc:type> <docNumber>7437</docNumber></affected>]</accompanies>
<cboCostEstimateLine value="Y">[Including cost estimate of the Congressional Budget Office]</cboCostEstimateLine></longTitle>
</actionDescription></action>
</reportPreface>
    
    <reportMain> 
        <recommendation>The Committee on Financial Services, to whom was referred the bill (H.R. 7437) to require certain supervisory agencies to assess their technological vulnerabilities, and for other 
            purposes, having considered the same, reports favorably thereon with an amendment and recommends that the bill as amended do pass.</recommendation>
        <toc>
            <heading>CONTENTS</heading>
            <headingItem><target>Page</target></headingItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Purpose and Summary</label><target>3</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Background and Need for Legislation</label><target>3</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Related Hearings</label><target>4</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Committee Consideration</label><target>4</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Committee Votes</label><target>5</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Committee Oversight Findings</label><target>7</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Performance Goals and Objectives</label><target>7</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Congressional Budget Office Estimates</label><target>7</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">New Budget Authority, Entitlement Authority, and Tax Expenditures </label><target>8</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Federal Mandates Statement</label><target>8</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Advisory Committee Statement</label><target>8</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Applicability to Legislative Branch</label><target>8</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Earmark Identification</label><target>9</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Duplication of Federal Programs</label><target>9</target></referenceItem>
            <referenceItem><label leaderAlign="right" leaderChar=".">Section-by-Section Analysis of the Legislation</label><target>9</target></referenceItem>
        </toc>
        <legislativeSegment role="amendment"><p>The amendment is as follows:</p>
    <amendmentInstruction><content>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the 
following:
<amendmentContent><section><num>SECTION 1. </num><heading>SHORT TITLE.</heading>
        <content>This Act may be cited as the “<shortTitle>Fostering the Use of Technology to Uphold Regulatory Effectiveness in Supervision Act</shortTitle>”.</content>
</section>
    <section><num> SEC. 2. </num><heading>FINDINGS.</heading>
    <chapeau>Congress finds the following:</chapeau>
   <paragraph><num> (1) </num><content>Banking regulators continue to examine and monitor 
    depository institutions without access to real-time 
    information.</content></paragraph>
   <paragraph><num> (2) </num><content>Risk surrounding technology procurement may present 
    challenges for updating supervisory technology.</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(3) </num><content>To ensure that prudential supervision is effective and 
    sustainable in the digital age, agencies must leverage new 
    technologies to allow for the financial monitoring necessary to 
    preserve a safe and sound banking system.</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(4) </num><content>New technological tools are also necessary in order for 
    agencies to effectively fulfill mandates other than prudential 
    supervision, including their mandates to assure consumer 
    protection and monitor Bank Secrecy Act compliance.</content></paragraph>
   <paragraph><num> (5) </num><chapeau>Agencies’ reliance on outdated technology creates 
    vulnerabilities for the financial system, causing—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>difficulties in collecting, compiling, and 
    analyzing relevant information about risks and 
    noncompliance at supervised firms;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>reliance on information that is inaccurate, 
    incomplete, or not timely;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(C) </num><content>reliance on limited and outdated tools for data 
    analysis;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(D) </num><content>difficulties in using data to identify risk 
    trends;</content></subparagraph>
   <subparagraph> <num>(E) </num><content>difficulties in producing accurate and timely 
    reports;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(F) </num><content>inadequacy of cybersecurity safeguards; and</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(G) </num><content>failure to detect illegal activities.</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(6) </num><content>The rapid expansion of financial firms’ use of artificial 
    intelligence may generate opportunities to improve the 
    financial system while also introducing a range of risks, 
    making it essential that agencies be equipped with the 
    technology and skills needed to analyze these opportunities and 
    potential risks.</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(7) </num><content>While agencies assess their supervisory capabilities on 
    an ongoing basis, it is imperative that there be a unified goal 
    to enhancing supervisory technologies that ensures effective 
    and sustainable oversight in the digital age.</content></paragraph></section>
    
 <section>   <num>SEC. 3. </num><heading>TECHNOLOGICAL VULNERABILITIES AND PROCUREMENT PRACTICES 
    ASSESSMENT.</heading>
    
    <subsection><num>(a) </num><heading>In General.—</heading>
    <paragraph><num>(1) </num><heading>Technological vulnerabilities assessment.—</heading><chapeau>Each covered 
    agency shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the 
    enactment of this section, assess how existing technological 
    systems used by the covered agency prevent the covered agency 
    from conducting real-time supervisory assessments of entities 
    over which the covered agency has supervisory authority, 
    including effects stemming from—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>core information technology infrastructure;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>technology used to supervise entities, including 
    supervisory technological tools; and</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(C) </num><content>technology for monitoring general market risks 
    using reported data and external data.</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
   <paragraph><num> (2) </num><heading>Procurement practices assessment.—</heading><chapeau>Each covered agency 
    shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment 
    of this section—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>assess the procurement rules and protocols 
    adhered to by such covered agency when such covered 
    agency acquires or develops new technological systems; 
    and</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>identify any challenges created by such 
    procurement rules and protocols, including the impact 
    such rules or protocols have on the ability of the 
    covered agency to test new technological systems.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection>    <num>(b) </num><heading>Report.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the completion of the 
    assessments required under subsection (a), and every 5 years 
    thereafter, the covered agencies shall coordinate and jointly submit to 
    the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and 
    the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a 
    report that includes the following with respect to each covered 
    agency—</chapeau>
    <paragraph><num>(1) </num><content>a general overview of hardware and software used for 
    information gathering and advanced analytics during supervision 
    activities, including products purchased from technology 
    vendors and products developed by the covered agency or 
    contractors of the covered agency;</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(2) </num><chapeau>a description of the procurement practices and protocols 
    of the covered agency, including a description of—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>whether such processes are voluntarily adhered to 
    or mandated; and</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>any challenges resulting from such practices and 
    protocols and relevant factors, if any, that have 
    impacted the covered agency’s ability to obtain new 
    technology;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
   <paragraph><num> (3) </num><chapeau>a general overview of the portion of workforce of the 
    covered agency that is engaged primarily in technology 
    development within the covered agency, including—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>an overview of the ability of the covered agency 
    to recruit and retain appropriate technology experts;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>employee self-reported workforce data; and</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(C) </num><content>a description of the degree to which the covered 
    agency relies on contractors to design, develop, or 
    deploy technology and perform technology-related tasks;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(4) </num><content>a description of the processes used by the covered agency 
    to obtain information from entities supervised by the covered 
    agency and general information about market trends and risks;</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(5) </num><content>a description of the ways in which the covered agency 
    shares information or system access with other covered 
    agencies;</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(6) </num><chapeau>an evaluation of the level of ease or difficulty 
    experienced by the covered agency, including any legal or 
    regulatory challenges, when—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>sharing data with other government agencies; or</content></subparagraph>
        <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>collecting data from entities supervised by the 
    covered agency;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(7) </num><content>an evaluation of cost for supervised entities to modify 
    systems to share data with covered agencies; and</content></paragraph>
    <paragraph><num>(8) </num><chapeau>a description of any plans the covered agency has that 
    relate to how the covered agency will implement future upgrades 
    to the technology used by the covered agency to supervise 
    entities supervised by the covered agency, including—</chapeau>
    <subparagraph><num>(A) </num><content>a general description of any planned upgrades;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(B) </num><content>the anticipated timeline for any planned upgrades;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(C) </num><content>the costs of any planned upgrades;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(D) </num><content>any concerns about access to needed resources;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(E) </num><content>intended efforts for hiring and training 
    individuals as part of any technological upgrades;</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(F) </num><content>any aspects of any planned upgrades that should 
    be addressed on an interagency basis; and</content></subparagraph>
    <subparagraph><num>(G) </num><chapeau>any anticipated challenges and solutions 
    associated with entities supervised by the covered agency adapting to new reporting requirements, 
    including—</chapeau>
    <clause><num>(i) </num><content>estimates of transition costs; and</content></clause>
    <clause><num>(ii) </num><content>estimates of any potential cost reductions.</content></clause>
    </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
     <subsection><num>(c) </num><heading>Covered Agency Defined.—</heading><content>In this section, the “covered agency” 
             means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal 
             Deposit Insurance Corporation, Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and the National 
             Credit Union Administration.</content></subsection></section>
    </amendmentContent>
</content></amendmentInstruction>
</legislativeSegment>
        <segment role="purpose">
            <heading>PURPOSE AND SUMMARY</heading>
            <p>Introduced on February 23, 2024, by Representative Erin 
                Houchin, H.R. 7437, the Fostering the Use of Technology to 
                Uphold Regulatory Effectiveness in Supervision (FUTURES) Act, 
                aims to help modernize technology systems within federal 
                agencies responsible for regulating banks and credit unions, 
                enhancing their capacity for effective supervision and 
                oversight. H.R. 7437 would require the Federal Reserve System 
                (Federal Reserve), Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation 
                (FDIC), Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC), 
                Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), and the National 
                Credit Union Administration (NCUA), to assess their internal 
                supervisory technologies as well as their ability to upgrade 
                these technologies, as necessary. H.R. 7437 is cosponsored by 
                Representatives Bill Foster, French Hill, and Brittany 
                Pettersen.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>BACKGROUND AND NEED FOR LEGISLATION</heading>
            <p>H.R. 7437 builds on the Government Accountability Office’s 
                (GAO) September 2023 report titled “Agencies Can Better 
                Support Workforce Expertise and Measure the Performance of 
                Innovation Offices.” In that report, the GAO recommended that 
                the CFPB, FDIC, Federal Reserve, NCUA, and the OCC collect 
                staff skillset data and incorporate leading workforce planning 
                practices. Further, the report recommended that the CFPB, NCUA, 
                and OCC develop performance measures for their innovation 
                offices and develop performance metrics for their supervisory 
                technology strategic objectives.</p>
            <p>The GAO report also discussed the critical challenges 
            agencies face in developing and retaining a qualified workforce 
            able to address technological developments by regulated 
            entities while ensuring the agencies themselves are effectively 
            deploying technology to enhance their own supervisory 
            capabilities. Separately, an independent report titled 
            “Financial Regulators’ Dilemma: Administrative and Regulatory 
            Hurdles to Innovation,” conducted by the Alliance for 
            Innovative Regulation (AIR), identified several issues and 
            hurdles that financial regulators face in staying abreast of 
            technological advances.</p>
            <p>The FUTURES Act, by requiring a comprehensive assessment of 
            procurement practices and technology usage, will shine a light 
            on the challenges our financial regulators face and pave the 
            way for solutions. It is imperative to ensure our financial 
            regulators utilize cutting-edge technological tools as well as 
            attract and retain personnel with the necessary expertise. By 
            sharing experiences and challenges, the report will equip us 
            with the necessary knowledge to develop solutions that 
            modernize their capabilities. Technology modernization will 
            lead to efficiencies that can help level the disproportionate 
            regulatory costs and ensure our financial regulators have the 
            tools they need to effectively supervise regulated entities.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>RELATED HEARINGS</heading>
            <p>Pursuant to clause 3(c)(6) of rule XIII, the following hearings were used to develop H.R. 7437:</p>
                <p>The Subcommittee on Digital Assets, Financial Technology and Inclusion of the Committee on Financial 
                Services held a hearing on October 25, 2023, titled “Modernizing Financial Services Through Innovation and 
                Competition.”</p>
                <p>The Subcommittee on Digital Assets, Financial 
                Technology and Inclusion of the Committee on Financial 
                Services held a hearing on December 5, 2023, titled 
                “Fostering Financial Innovation: How Agencies Can 
                Leverage Technology to Shape the Future of Financial 
                Services.”</p>
                <p>The Subcommittee on Digital Assets, Financial 
                Technology and Inclusion held a Field Hearing on 
                December 8, 2023, titled “Connecting Communities: 
                Building Innovation Ecosystems Across America.”</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>COMMITTEE CONSIDERATION</heading>
            <p>The Committee on Financial Services met in open session on 
                April 17, 2024, and ordered H.R. 7437 to be reported favorably 
                to the House as amended by a voice vote, a quorum being 
                present. Before the question was called to order the bill 
                favorably reported, the Committee adopted an amendment in the 
                nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Houchin by voice vote.</p>
        </segment>
        <votesInCommittee>
            <heading>COMMITTEE VOTES</heading>
            <p>Clause 3(b) of rule XIII of the Rules of the House of 
            Representatives requires the Committee to list the record votes 
            on the order to report legislation and amendments thereto. H.R. 
            7437 was ordered reported favorably to the House as amended by 
            a voice vote, a quorum being present.</p>
           <p> An amendment offered by Ms. Waters, no. 3, was not agreed 
            to by a recorded vote of 22 ayes to 28 nays (Record vote no. 
            FC-129), a quorum being present.</p>
            <figure><figCaption>scan of vote tally goes here</figCaption><img alt="vote tally sheet"/></figure>
        </votesInCommittee>
        <segment>
            <heading>COMMITTEE OVERSIGHT FINDINGS</heading>
            <p> Pursuant to clause 3(c) of rule XIII of the Rules of the 
                House of Representatives, the findings and recommendations of 
                the Committee, based on oversight activities under clause 
                2(b)(1) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives, 
                are incorporated in the descriptive portions of this report.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading> PERFORMANCE GOALS AND OBJECTIVES</heading>
            <p>Pursuant to clause 3(c)(4) of rule XIII of the Rules of the 
                House of Representatives, the goal of H.R. 7437 is to require 
                prudential regulators to individually assess their internal 
                supervisory technologies, as well as their ability to upgrade 
                these technologies, as necessary.</p>
        </segment>
        <estimatedCosts>
            <heading>CONGRESSIONAL BUDGET OFFICE ESTIMATES</heading>
            <p>Pursuant to clause 3(c)(3) of rule XIII of the Rules of the 
            House of Representatives, the following is the cost estimate 
            provided by the Congressional Budget Office pursuant to section 
            402 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974:</p>
            <figure><figCaption>scan of CBO table goes here</figCaption><img alt="scan of results"/></figure>
            <cboCostEstimate><p>H.R. 7437 would require federal financial regulators to 
            assess how their technological systems prevent them from 
            conducting real-time supervision of regulated entities and how 
            their procurement rules limit the testing of new technologies. 
            Federal financial regulators under the bill include the 
            Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), Federal Deposit 
            Insurance Corporation (FDIC), Federal Reserve, National Credit 
            Union Administration (NCUA), and Office of the Comptroller of 
            the Currency (OCC). In addition, the bill would require those 
            agencies to jointly report to the Congress every five years on 
            multiple issues, including their use of hardware and software, 
            procurement practices, and information technology workforce.
            In total, CBO estimates that the administrative costs for 
            the agencies to implement the requirements in H.R. 7437 would 
            increase direct spending by $3 million and reduce revenues by 
            $1 million over the 2024-2034 period.</p>
            <p>Using information about the cost of similar provisions, CBO 
            estimates that each agency would need about two employees, at 
            an average annual cost of $260,000 per employee, to complete 
            the assessments and reports.</p>
            <p>Expenditures for the CFPB, FDIC, NCUA, and OCC are 
            classified in the budget as direct spending. The NCUA and OCC 
            collect fees from financial institutions to offset their 
            operating costs, and those fees are recorded as offsetting 
            receipts, that is, as reductions in direct spending. CBO 
            estimates that, on net, enacting H.R. 7437 would increase 
            direct spending by $3 million over the 2024-2034 period.
            Costs incurred by the Federal Reserve reduce remittances to 
            the Treasury, which are recorded in the budget as revenues. CBO 
            estimates that H.R. 7437 would decrease revenues by $1 million 
            over the 2024-2034 period.</p>
            <p>If federal financial regulators increase annual fees to 
            offset the costs of implementing the bill, H.R. 7437 would 
            increase the costs of an existing private-sector mandate on 
            entities required to pay those fees. CBO estimates that the 
            incremental cost of the mandate would be small and would fall 
            well below the annual threshold established in the Unfunded 
            Mandates Reform Act (UMRA) for private-sector mandates ($200 
            million in 2024, adjusted annually for inflation).
            The bill contains no intergovernmental mandates as defined 
            in UMRA.</p>
            <p>The CBO staff contacts for this estimate are David Hughes 
            (for federal costs) and Rachel Austin (for mandates). The 
            estimate was reviewed by H. Samuel Papenfuss, Deputy Director 
            of Budget Analysis.</p>
            <p class="smallCaps">Phillip L. Swagel,</p>
            <p class="italic">Director, Congressional Budget Office.</p></cboCostEstimate>
        </estimatedCosts>
<segment><heading>NEW BUDGET AUTHORITY, ENTITLEMENT AUTHORITY, AND TAX EXPENDITURES</heading>
<p>Pursuant to clause 3(c)(2) of rule XIII of the Rules of the 
House of Representatives, the Committee adopts as its own the 
estimate of new budget authority, entitlement authority, or tax 
expenditures or revenues contained in the cost estimate 
prepared by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office 
pursuant to section 402 of the Congressional Budget Act of 
1973.</p></segment>
<segment><heading>FEDERAL MANDATES STATEMENT</heading>
<p>Pursuant to section 423 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform 
Act, the Committee adopts as its own the estimate of the 
Federal mandates prepared by the Director of the Congressional 
Budget Office.</p></segment>
<segment><heading>ADVISORY COMMITTEE STATEMENT</heading>
<p>No advisory committees within the meaning of section 5(b) 
of the Federal Advisory Committee Act were created by this 
legislation.</p></segment>
<segment><heading>APPLICABILITY TO LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</heading>
<p>The Committee finds that the legislation does not relate to 
the terms and conditions of employment or access to public 
services or accommodations within the meaning of section 
102(b)(3) of the Congressional Accountability Act.</p></segment>
<segment><heading>EARMARK IDENTIFICATION</heading>
<p>With respect to clause 9 of rule XXI of the Rules of the 
House of Representatives, the Committee has carefully reviewed 
the provisions of the bill and states that the provisions of 
the bill do not contain any congressional earmarks, limited tax 
benefits, or limited tariff benefits within the meaning of the 
rule.</p></segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>DUPLICATION OF FEDERAL PROGRAMS</heading>
            <p>Pursuant to clause 3(c)(5) of rule XIII of the Rules of the 
House of Representatives, the Committee states that no 
provision of the bill establishes or reauthorizes a program of 
the Federal Government known to be duplicative of another 
Federal program, including any program that was included in a 
report to Congress pursuant to section 21 of the Public Law 
111-139 or the most recent Catalog of Federal Domestic 
Assistance.</p></segment>
<segment><heading>SECTION-BY-SECTION ANALYSIS OF THE LEGISLATION</heading>
<subheading class="italic">Section 1. Short title</subheading>
<p>This Act may be cited as the “Fostering the Use of Technology to Uphold Regulatory Effectiveness in Supervision Act”.</p>
    <subheading class="italic">Section 2. Findings</subheading>
<p>This Section highlights that agencies must leverage new 
technologies to enhance their capacity for effective 
supervision and oversight. The findings also emphasize the 
risks and vulnerabilities associated with reliance on outdated 
technology. Further, this Section emphasizes that agencies must 
leverage new technologies to fulfill other important mandates 
to protect consumers and combat money laundering, the financing 
of terrorism, and other illicit finance activities.</p>
    <subheading class="italic">Section 3. Technological vulnerabilities and procurement practices assessment</subheading>
<p>This Section requires the Federal Reserve, FDIC, OCC, CFPB 
and the NCUA to conduct internal assessments of their 
technological vulnerabilities and procurement practices. The 
assessments within each agency must be completed within 180 
days. A report must be submitted to the Committee on Financial 
Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on 
Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs no later than 180 days 
after the assessments and every 5 years thereafter. This report 
must include a general overview of their hardware and software; 
a description of their procurement practices; a general 
overview of their technology workforce; a description of the 
processes they use to obtain information; a description of how 
they share information with other agencies; and a description 
of any existing plans to implement future upgrades to their 
supervisory technologies.</p></segment>
    </reportMain>
    <endMarker>○</endMarker>
</legislativeReport>
