<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="legislativeReport.css"?>
<legislativeReport  xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.1.1.xsd" xml:lang="en">
    <!-- This is sample content for the purposes of illustrating the elements used in USLM for legislative reports. This file should not be used
            for any other purposes as it is incomplete and may not be accurate. -->
    <!-- https://www.govinfo.gov/app/details/CRPT-118hrpt9/CRPT-118hrpt9 -->
    <reportMeta>
        <dc:title>H. Rept. 118-9: Parents Bill of Rights Act</dc:title><!-- report number + report title, separated by ':' -->
        <dc:date>2023-03-14</dc:date>
        <dc:type>House Legislative Report</dc:type>
        <citableAs>H. Rept. 118-9</citableAs>
        <citableAs>House Report 118-9</citableAs>
        <citableAs>CRPT-118hrpt9</citableAs>
        <currentChamber>House</currentChamber>
        <congress>118</congress>
        <session>1</session>
        <committee>Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee><!-- The only committee in the meta is the lead committee -->
        <genre>legislative</genre>
        <cboCostEstimateLine>Y</cboCostEstimateLine>
        <accompanies>118hr5</accompanies>
        <jacketId>39-006</jacketId>
    </reportMeta>
    <reportPreface> 
        <layout class="reportHeader">
            <row><column class="topLeft"><congress>118th Congress</congress></column><column rowspan="2" class="leftBracket">}</column>
                <column rowspan="2" class="middle"><currentChamber>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</currentChamber></column>
                <column rowspan="2" class="rightBracket">{</column><column class="topRight smallCaps"><dc:type>Report</dc:type></column></row>
            <row><column class="bottomLeft italic"><session>1st Session</session></column><column class="bottomRight"><docNumber>118–9</docNumber></column></row>
        </layout>
        
        <reportTitle>PARENTS BILL OF RIGHTS ACT</reportTitle>
        <action><date date="2023-03-14"><inline class="smallCaps">March 14, 2023</inline>.—</date><actionDescription>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the 
                State of the Union and ordered to be printed</actionDescription></action>
        <action><actionDescription><sponsor bioGuideId="YYY">Ms. <inline class="smallCaps">Foxx</inline></sponsor>, from the <committee>Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee>, submitted 
                the following
                <longTitle><docTitle>R E P O R T</docTitle>
                    <p class="centered">together with</p>
                    <reportViews>MINORITY VIEWS</reportViews>
                    <accompanies>[To accompany <affected><dc:type>H.R.</dc:type> <docNumber>5</docNumber></affected>]</accompanies>
                    <cboCostEstimateLine value="Y">[Including cost estimate of the Congressional Budget Office]</cboCostEstimateLine></longTitle>
        </actionDescription></action>
        <!-- The <slugLine> is a line added to the <reportPreface> (and other types of preface elements) that will be printed in the page footer. The author does not need to be concerned about the placement of the slugLine in the preface as the composition engine will place the content in the appropriate location on the rendered page. By convention it is the last child of the appropriate preface (in this case the <reportPreface>) element. -->
        <slugLine><jacketId>39-006</jacketId></slugLine>
    </reportPreface>
    
    <reportMain> 
        <recommendation>The Committee on Education and the Workforce, to whom was referred the bill (H.R. 5) to ensure the rights of parents are 
            honored and protected in the Nation’s public schools, having considered the same, reports favorably thereon with an 
            amendment and recommends that the bill as amended do pass.</recommendation>
        <legislativeSegment role="amendment"><p>The amendment is as follows:</p>
            <amendmentInstruction><content>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the 
                    following:
                    <amendmentContent><section><num>SECTION 1. </num><heading>SHORT TITLE.</heading>
                            <content> This Act may be cited as the “<shortTitle>Parents Bill of Rights Act</shortTitle>”.</content></section>
                        <title><num>TITLE I—</num><heading>AMENDMENTS TO THE ELEMENTARY AND SECONDARY EDUCATION ACT OF 
                                1965</heading>
                            <section><num>SEC. 101. </num><heading>STATE PLAN ASSURANCES.</heading>
                                <chapeau>Section 1111(g)(2) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 
                                    1965 (20 U.S.C. 6311(g)(2)) is amended—</chapeau>
                                <subsection><num>(1) </num><content>in subparagraph (M), by striking “<quotedText>and</quotedText>” at the end;</content></subsection>
                                <subsection><num>(2) </num><content>in subparagraph (N), by striking the period at the end 
                                        and inserting a semicolon; and</content></subsection>
                                <subsection><num>(3) </num><content>by adding at the end the following:
                                        <quotedContent><subparagraph><num>“(O) </num><chapeau>the State will ensure that each local educational agency in the State—</chapeau>
                                                <clause><num>“(i) </num><chapeau>in a case in which the curriculum for an elementary or secondary school grade level 
                                                        is freely and publicly available on the internet—</chapeau></clause></subparagraph></quotedContent></content></subsection>
                            </section></title></amendmentContent>
            </content></amendmentInstruction>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
        </legislativeSegment>
        
        <segment role="billPurpose">
            <heading>PURPOSE</heading>
            <p>The issue of parents’ rights in education has become a major
                topic since the Covid–19 pandemic revealed the unaccountable influence
                that teachers’ unions and special interest groups hold over
                public K–12 education. School closures allowed many parents, for the first time, to see exactly what their kids were being taught.
                They learned that divisive and inappropriate topics like Critical
                Race Theory (CRT) and progressive gender ideology have infiltrated
                public schools. H.R. 5, the <i>Parents Bill of Rights Act</i> takes important
                steps to clarify that parents have a right to know what is happening
                in their child’s school and maintain the right to make decisions
                about their child’s education. H.R. 5 will put practices in
                place that facilitate meaningful dialog between a family and their
                child’s school, and lead to more input throughout the learning process.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>COMMITTEE ACTION</heading>
            <heading>116TH CONGRESS</heading>
            <subheading class="italic">Second Session—Hearings</subheading>
            <p>On June 15, 2020, the Committee on Education and the 
                Workforce held a virtual hearing on “Budget Cuts and Lost 
                Learning: Assessing the Impact of Covid-19 on Public 
                Education.” The hearing was the first in a series examining 
                the impact of the Covid-19 pandemic on K-12 education. The 
                purpose of the hearing was to evaluate the state of education 
                funding and examine the learning losses students are projected 
                to experience. Testifying before the Committee were Mr. Mark 
                Johnson, State Superintendent, North Carolina Department of 
                Public Instruction, Raleigh, NC; Dr. Michael Leachman, Vice 
                President for State Fiscal Policy, Center on Budget and Policy 
                Priorities, Washington, D.C.; Mr. Eric Gordon, CEO, Cleveland 
                Metropolitan School District, Cleveland, OH; and Ms. Becky 
                Pringle, Vice President, National Education Association, 
                Washington, D.C.</p>
            <p>On July 21, 2020, the Committee’s Subcommittee on Early 
                Childhood, Elementary and Secondary Education (ECESE) held a 
                virtual hearing on “Underfunded &amp; Unprepared: Examining How to 
                Overcome Obstacles to Safely Reopen Public Schools.” The 
                purpose of the hearing was to discuss the barriers to reopening 
                schools and how to overcome them. Testifying before the 
                subcommittee were Mrs. Penny Schwinn, Commissioner, Tennessee 
                Department of Education, Nashville, TN; Ms. Leslie Boggs, 
                President, National Parent Teachers Association, Alexandria, 
                VA; Dr. Michael Hinojosa, Superintendent, Dallas Independent 
                School District, Dallas, TX; and Dr. Sean O’Leary, Pediatric 
                Infectious Disease Specialist, Children’s Hospital Colorado, 
                Co-Chair of the Immunization Committee, Colorado Chapter of the 
                American Academy of Pediatrics, Aurora, CO.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Legislative Action</subheading>
            <p>On April 30, 2019, the Committee held a legislative hearing 
                on school integration and civil rights enforcement. A review of 
                Committee archives suggests this is the first hearing focused 
                on school segregation since the 101st Congress, nearly 30 years 
                ago. The hearing, titled “Brown v. Board of Education at 65: A 
                Promise Unfulfilled,” was used to inform the development of 
                H.R. 2639. On May 9, 2019, Rep. Marcia Fudge (D-OH) introduced 
                H.R. 2639, the Strength in Diversity Act of 2019, with Chairman 
                Bobby Scott (D-VA) and Rep. Gregorio Sablan (D-MP), Chair of 
                the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary 
                Education, as original co-sponsors. On May 16, 2019, the 
                Committee considered H.R. 2639 in a legislative session and 
                ordered it reported favorably, as amended, to the House of 
                Representative by a vote of 26-20. The Committee considered and 
                adopted the following amendments to H.R. 2639:</p>
            <list><listItem><num>1. </num><listContent>Rep. Fudge offered an Amendment in the Nature of a 
                        Substitute (ANS) that made numerous changes to H.R. 
                        2639. The ANS improved provisions under section 5 of 
                        the bill to ensure outreach to parents and students is 
                        produced in commonly understandable language. It also 
                        ensured consultation with students and families in the 
                        district or region targeted for diversity improvement 
                        efforts. Under section 6, the ANS expanded planning 
                        grant activities to include the development of a robust 
                        family, student, and community engagement plan. It also 
                        explicitly stated that funds can be used to support 
                        school districts under a court-ordered school 
                        desegregation plan. The ANS expanded implementation 
                        grants activities to include the development of 
                        innovative and equitable school assignment plans and 
                        other innovative activities to increase racial and 
                        socioeconomic diversity. Under section 7, the ANS added 
                        reducing school discipline rates as a measure of a 
                        school integration plan’s success. Under section 8, the 
                        ANS expanded the annual reporting requirement to 
                        include a description of the entity’s efforts to 
                        increase inclusivity in schools. Finally, the ANS added 
                        a new section to specify that GEPA section 426 does not 
                        apply to funds authorized by the bill.</listContent></listItem></list>
            <p>The Committee further considered the following amendments 
                to the Amendment in the Nature of a Substitute to H.R. 2639:</p>
            <list><listItem><num>2. </num><listContent>Rep. Rick Allen (R-GA) offered an amendment to the 
                        ANS that proposed to strike the authorization of the 
                        new federal grant program created in H.R. 2639 to 
                        support voluntary community-driven efforts to increase 
                        diversity in schools. The amendment instead amended 
                        section 4106 of the Elementary and Secondary Education 
                        Act of 1965 to allow school districts to use funds 
                        authorized by such act to develop or implement 
                        strategies to improve diversity and reduce or eliminate 
                        racial or socioeconomic isolation in schools. The 
                        amendment also permitted LEAs to use funds received 
                        under section 4106 to cover fees associated with 
                        accelerated learning examinations given to low-income 
                        students. Lastly, the amendment exempted funds used 
                        pursuant to the authorized uses from the requirements 
                        of GEPA section 426. Because the amendment proposed to 
                        amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 
                        1965, a law not amended by the underlying bill, the 
                        amendment expanded the scope of the bill and was ruled 
                        out of order by the Chairman.</listContent></listItem></list>
            <p>The Committee again worked with the Committee on 
                Appropriations on longstanding anti-integration riders during 
                the Fiscal Year 2021 (FY21) appropriations process. As a 
                result, H.R. 7617, the Defense, Commerce, Justice, Science, 
                Energy and Water Development, Financial Services and General 
                Government, Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, 
                Transportation, Housing, and Urban Development Appropriations 
                Act, 2021 included a provision striking GEPA section 426 from 
                law entirely. H.R. 7617 passed the House July 31, 2020 by a 
                vote of 217-197.</p>
            <p>On May 2, 2019, Rep. Kim Schrier (D-WA) introduced H.R. 
                2480, the Stronger Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act, 
                with Reps. James Comer (R-KY), Lori Trahan (D-MA), Dusty 
                Johnson (R-SD), Suzanne Bonamici (D-OR), Elise Stefanik (R-NY), 
                Chairman Bobby Scott (D-VA), and Ranking Member Virginia Foxx 
                (R-NC) as original co-sponsors. On May 8, 2019, the Committee 
                considered H.R. 2480 in a legislative session and reported it 
                favorably, as amended, to the House of Representative by a 
                voice vote. The Committee considered and adopted the following 
                amendments to H.R. 2480:</p>
            <list><listItem><num>1. </num><listContent>
                        Rep. Bonamici offered an Amendment in the Nature 
                            of a Substitute (ANS) that made several improvements to 
                            H.R. 2480. The ANS narrowed the condition of receipt of 
                            funds in Section 103(d) to grants received through 
                            Section 106. In Section 106(a)(5)(A), housing agencies 
                            were added to the list of service providers 
                            participating in state and local networks supporting 
                            child and family well-being to establish connections 
                            between the child welfare system and agencies that 
                            support families in finding and securing stable 
                            housing.
                        <p>The ANS made two important changes to support 
                            prevention efforts in tribal communities. The amendment 
                            added Indian tribes and tribal organizations to the 
                            list of entities that receive equitable distribution of 
                            assistance in Section 107 and required the Government 
                            Accountability Office (GAO) to examine and make 
                            recommendations about issues relating to child abuse 
                            and neglect in Indian tribal communities.</p>
                        <p>Several changes were made in Section 110 through the 
                            ANS to clarify the intent of and strengthen the 
                            electronic data exchange system. First, language was 
                            added to ensure that standards and policies governing 
                            the electronic interstate data exchange adhere to 
                            federal law in addition to state law. The ANS also 
                            clarified that the exchange can only be used for 
                            purposes of child safety and is not to be used for any 
                            other purpose. To this end, the ANS included a 
                            prohibition on the Secretary from accessing or storing 
                            data exchanged on the system. The ANS also required 
                            that each state provide the Secretary an assurance that 
                            its child abuse and neglect registry provides 
                            procedural due process for individuals placed on such a 
                            registry. Finally, the ANS modified the appropriations 
                            reservation for Section 110 such that out of annual 
                            funds appropriated in Title I, $2 million per year for 
                            fiscal years 2020 and 2021 and $1 million per year for 
                            fiscal years 2022 through 2025 are reserved for the 
                            development and implementation of the electronic data 
                            exchange system.</p>
                        <p>The ANS also included a change in Title II to raise 
                            the administrative cap on funds received in excess of 
                            fiscal year 2019 state allocations from four percent to 
                            ten percent to ensure lead entities are able to 
                            effectively monitor and provide oversight of prevention 
                            services. The ANS was adopted via voice vote.</p>
            </listContent></listItem></list>
            <p>During the legislative session the Committee adopted 
                several amendments to the ANS:</p>
            <list><listItem><num>1. </num><listContent>Rep. Lucy McBath (D-GA) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Stefanik (R-NY), an amendment to the ANS 
                        allowing the Secretary to fund a national hotline for 
                        child abuse and neglect. The amendment was adopted via 
                        voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>2. </num><listContent>Rep. Russ Fulcher (R-ID) offered an amendment to 
                        the amendment in the nature of the substitute requiring 
                        the working group established in Section 110 to 
                        generate best practices that ensure due process for 
                        individuals included in state child abuse and neglect 
                        registries. The amendment was adopted via voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>3. </num><listContent>Rep. David Trone (D-MD) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Ron Wright (R-TX), an amendment to the ANS 
                        allowing states to carry out programs or strategies 
                        that promote the recruitment, support, or retention of 
                        the child welfare workforce. The amendment was adopted 
                        via voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>4. </num><listContent>Rep. Lloyd Smucker (R-PA) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Lauren Underwood (D-PA), an amendment to the 
                        ANS ensuring the Secretary includes parent substance 
                        use disorder as a factor in the study examining 
                        adoption outcomes. The amendment was adopted via voice 
                        vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>5. </num><listContent>Rep. Van Taylor (R-TX) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Joe Morelle (D-NY), an amendment to the ANS 
                        requiring the Secretary to conduct a study of 
                        exemptions to state laws pertaining to the minimum age 
                        of marriage and examine how such exemptions affect 
                        child safety. The amendment was adopted via voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>6. </num><listContent>Rep. Susan Wild (D-PA) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Glenn “GT” Thompson (R-PA), an amendment to 
                        the ANS requiring the Secretary to conduct a study of 
                        mandatory reporter state laws and examine differences 
                        in rates of referrals related to such state laws. The 
                        amendment was adopted via voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>7. </num><listContent>Rep. Steve Watkins (R-KS) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Susie Lee (D-NV), an amendment to the ANS 
                        ensuring that no child protective services protocols or 
                        systems authorize the separation of a child from their 
                        family due solely to poverty. The amendment was adopted 
                        via voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>8. </num><listContent>Rep. Josh Harder (D-CA) offered, in coordination 
                        with Rep. Dan Meuser (R-PA), an amendment to the ANS 
                        allowing states to carry out activities that reduce 
                        child abuse and neglect due to the substance use 
                        disorder of a parent. The amendment was adopted via 
                        voice vote.</listContent></listItem>
            </list>
               <p>The Committee further considered the following amendment 
                    H.R. 2480, as amended:</p>
            <list>
                <listItem><num>9. </num><listContent>Rep. Pramila Jayapal (D-WA) offered, in 
                        coordination with Rep. Brett Guthrie (R-KY), an 
                        amendment to the ANS ensuring that infants whose 
                        prenatal drug exposure is the result of maternal intake 
                        of drugs as prescribed by a physician are not reported 
                        to child protective services. The amendment was 
                        withdrawn with a commitment to work with Committee 
                        leadership to improve this language for inclusion in 
                        the bill.</listContent></listItem>
            </list>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <heading>117TH CONGRESS</heading>
            <subheading class="italic">First Session—Hearings</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Second Session—Hearings</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Legislative Action</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <heading>118TH CONGRESS</heading>
            <subheading class="italic">First Session—Hearings</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Second Session—Hearings</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Legislative Action</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
        </segment>
        
        <segment role="">
            <heading>COMMITTEE VIEWS</heading>
            <heading>INTRODUCTION</heading>
            <p>Parental rights are non-negotiable. Parents have a God-
                given right to make decisions for their children, to raise 
                children according to the values they hold, and to know how 
                their children are being instructed in school. Americans should 
                never be forced to relinquish these parental rights to the 
                government—whether that involves curriculum decisions or 
                personal medical choices.</p>
            <p>These rights belong to all serving in parental roles. H.R. 
                5 amends the <i>Elementary and Secondary Education Act</i> (ESEA), the 
                <i>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act</i> (FERPA), and the 
                <i>Protection of Pupil Rights Amendment</i> (PPRA), all of which 
                define “parent” broadly to include legal guardians and others 
                standing in <i>loco parentis</i>. Unfortunately, these fundamental 
                parental rights are increasingly under assault. The issue of 
                parents’ rights in education has become a major topic since the 
                COVID-19 pandemic. School closures allowed many parents, for 
                the first time, to see exactly what their kids were being 
                taught. Many parents discovered that divisive and inappropriate 
                leftist ideology had infiltrated their local public school.</p>
            <p>Rather than listening to parents’ concerns about what was 
                being taught, the left has instead tried to silence them. 
                Powerful teachers unions, school boards, Democrat politicians, 
                and the Biden Justice Department have all voiced opposition to 
                the rights of parents to have a say in their child’s education. 
                Former Democrat House Budget Committee Chairman John Yarmuth 
                argued in an Education and Labor Committee markup that children 
                need to be protected from their parents.<ref idref="fn-1"><sup>1</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-1"><num><sup>1 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CwduW_zw18U">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CwduW_zw18U</ref>.</footnote> Virginia Democrat 
                gubernatorial candidate Terry McAuliffe argued during a debate 
                that parents should not tell schools what to teach.<ref idref="fn-2"><sup>2</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-2"><num><sup>2 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/mcauliffe-says-he-doesnt-believe-parents-should-control-what-schools-teach">https://www.foxnews.com/politics/mcauliffe-says-he-doesnt-believe-parents-should-control-what-schools-teach</ref>.</footnote> And 
                Department of Education (ED) Secretary Miguel Cardona refused 
                to accept that parents should be the primary stakeholder in 
                their children’s education.<ref idref="fn-3"><sup>3</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-3"><num><sup>3 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2021/10/01/biden_education_sec_cardona_parents_shouldnt_be_primary_stakeholder_in_their_kids_education.html">https://www.realclearpolitics.com/video/2021/10/01/biden_education_sec_cardona_parents_shouldnt_be_primary_stakeholder_in_their_kids_education.html</ref>.</footnote></p>
            <p>H.R. 5 takes important steps to restore parents’ rights by 
                strengthening provisions in ESEA, FERPA, and the PPRA. 
                Committee Republicans want parents to be involved in the 
                decision- making process when it comes to their child’s 
                education. Parents deserve transparency and accountability. The 
                <i>Parents Bill of Rights Act</i> (PBORA) reaffirms schools’ duties to 
                parents by securing the following five key rights:</p>
            <list><listItem><num>1. </num><listContent>The right to know what their children are being 
                        taught.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>2. </num><listContent>The right to be heard by educators and 
                        policymakers.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>3. </num><listContent>The right to see school budgeting and spending.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>4. </num><listContent>The right to protect their child’s privacy.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>5. </num><listContent>The right to keep their children safe.</listContent></listItem>
            </list>
            <subheading class="italic">Parents have the right to know what is being taught</subheading>
            <p>In 2021, Rhode Island mother-of-two Nicole Solas talked to 
                an elementary school principal in South Kingstown, RI, about 
                what was being taught in schools. She quickly became concerned 
                that leftist ideology was being taught and demanded to know 
                more. She asked the principal, the school board, the 
                superintendent, the director of curriculum, and the legal 
                department at the Rhode Island Department of Education to let 
                her view the curriculum.<ref idref="fn-4"><sup>4</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-4"><num><sup>4 </sup></num><ref href="https://legalinsurrection.com/2021/06/im-a-mom-seeking-records-of-critical-race-and-gender-curriculum-now-the-school-committee-may-sue-to-stop-me/">https://legalinsurrection.com/2021/06/im-a-mom-seeking-records-of-critical-race-and-gender-curriculum-now-the-school-committee-may-sue-to-stop-me/</ref>.</footnote></p>
            <p>After persistent stonewalling, the school district directed 
                her to file a request under state law governing public access 
                of records on the school district website to obtain the 
                curriculum. Solas filed numerous requests, leading the school 
                board to publicly consider suing her.<ref idref="fn-5"><sup>5</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-5"><num><sup>5 </sup></num><ref href="https://turnto10.com/news/local/south-kingstown-school-committee-wont-sue-woman-over-public-records-requests">https://turnto10.com/news/local/south-kingstown-school-committee-wont-sue-woman-over-public-records-requests</ref>.</footnote> In August 2021, the 
                local National Education Association affiliate did file a 
                lawsuit against her.<ref idref="fn-6"><sup>6</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-6"><num><sup>6 </sup></num><ref href="https://turnto10.com/news/local/teachers-union-sues-south-kingstown-school-committee-parent-over-public-records-release">https://turnto10.com/news/local/teachers-union-sues-south-kingstown-school-committee-parent-over-public-records-release</ref>.</footnote></p>
            <p>This kind of treatment is outrageous. Simply because she 
                wanted to know what her child was being taught, Solas was 
                subjected to endless stonewalling, public humiliation, and an 
                interminable and costly legal battle. No parent should have to 
                go through that just to know what their child is learning in 
                school.</p>
            <p>To these ends, schools and school districts must be 
                transparent about every aspect of education. To honor the 
                transparency that all parents deserve, H.R. 5 requires states 
                to ensure that school districts post curriculum information for 
                each grade level on a publicly accessible website or, for any 
                districts that do not operate a website, that such districts 
                must widely disseminate the information to the public. Schools 
                will also be required to allow parents the opportunity to 
                review the curriculum. Additionally, schools will be required 
                to annually release a list of books and reading materials that 
                are available in the school library, so parents are aware and 
                able to review the literature available to their child. 
                Finally, the bill requires states to provide the public a copy 
                of any revisions made to the state’s academic content and 
                achievement standards.</p>
            <p>The Committee is aware of the important role teachers play 
                in school system. These transparency responsibilities will not 
                increase teacher burden. The responsibility to post or widely 
                distribute curriculum information is a school district 
                responsibility. The Committee expects that school district 
                staff will fulfill this obligation.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Parents have the right to be heard</subheading>
            <p>In the past two years, parents have turned out en masse to 
                school board meetings to protest and express their opinions on 
                local education policies. They have much to be frustrated 
                about. For one, parents are rightly concerned about how leftist 
                ideologies have infiltrated school classrooms. Nicole Solas’s 
                story, above, is a prime example of how school administrators 
                can stonewall even the most basic attempts to uncover what 
                children are being taught. That is cause for grave concern.</p>
            <p>Second, children have borne the brunt of excessively 
                cautious and politicized COVID-19 mitigation strategies. School 
                closures and the pandemic experience plunged students into 
                feelings of isolation, depression, and anxiety.<ref idref="fn-7"><sup>7</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-7"><num><sup>7 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/hsph-in-the-news/covid-youth-mental-health-crisis/">https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/hsph-in-the-news/covid-youth-mental-health-crisis/</ref>.</footnote> The CDC’s 
                2021 Adolescent Behaviors and Experiences Survey noted that 37 
                percent of high school students experienced poor mental health 
                during the pandemic, with 44 percent of all students reporting 
                feeling persistently sad or hopeless.<ref idref="fn-8"><sup>8</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-8"><num><sup>8 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.cdc.gov/healthyyouth/data/abes.htm">https://www.cdc.gov/healthyyouth/data/abes.htm</ref>, <ref href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2022/p0331-youth-mental-health-covid-19.html">https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2022/p0331-youth-mental-health-covid-19.html</ref>.</footnote> A study conducted by 
                the American Civil Liberties Union asked students to grade 
                their mental wellness before and after schools closed on a 
                scale of one to 10, with 10 indicating peak mental health.<ref idref="fn-9"><sup>9</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-9"><num><sup>9 </sup></num>Student anxiety, depression increasing during school closures, survey finds | EdSource.</footnote> 
                Before the pandemic, 65 percent of students gave themselves a 
                seven or higher. After the onset of the pandemic, that 
                percentage dropped to less than 40 percent. Moreover, the 
                number of students who rated their mental health a three or 
                lower more than tripled after the pandemic began, from 7.2 
                percent to 23 percent.<ref idref="fn-10"><sup>10</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-10"><num><sup>10 </sup></num>Ibid.</footnote></p>
            <p>Although students have been learning in person most of the 
                last two school years, the learning loss suffered during school 
                closures cannot be overstated. Study after study confirms the 
                sad yet unsurprising reality: school closures crippled K-12 
                students’ learning. ED released National Assessment of 
                Educational Progress (NAEP) data<ref idref="fn-11"><sup>11</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-11"><num><sup>11 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/highlights/ltt/2022/">https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/highlights/ltt/2022/</ref>.</footnote> last fall showing that 
                reading and math scores for nine-year-olds declined sharply 
                over the course of the pandemic. Average scores in 2022 
                declined five points in reading and seven points in math 
                compared to 2020. This is the largest average decline in 
                reading since 1990 and the first ever decline in math. A July 
                2021 analysis conducted by McKinsey &amp; Company found that 
                students may earn $49,000 to $61,000 less over their lifetime 
                because of the pandemic.<ref idref="fn-12"><sup>12</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-12"><num><sup>12 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/public-and-social-sector/our-insights/covid-19-and-education-the-lingering-effects-of-unfinished-learning">https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/public-and-social-sector/our-insights/covid-19-and-education-the-lingering-effects-of-unfinished-learning</ref>.</footnote></p>
            <p>What is worse is that COVID-19 mitigation policies were 
                often influenced less by the imperatives of public health 
                concerns and more by Democrats’ political allies. For instance, 
                the Biden administration allowed the American Federation of 
                Teachers to rewrite key portions of the Centers for Disease 
                Control and Prevention’s school reopening guidance.<ref idref="fn-13"><sup>13</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-13"><num><sup>13 </sup></num><ref href="https://nypost.com/2021/05/01/teachers-union-collaborated-with-cdc-on-school-reopening-emails/">https://nypost.com/2021/05/01/teachers-union-collaborated-with-cdc-on-school-reopening-emails/</ref>.</footnote> 
                Teachers unions also had tremendous control over deciding which 
                school districts would reopen. Research shows large urban 
                school districts with entrenched union power were less likely 
                to reopen in the fall of 2021.<ref idref="fn-14"><sup>14</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-14"><num><sup>14 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/brown-center-chalkboard/2021/03/25/teachers-unions-scapegoats-or-bad-faith-actors-in-covid-19-school-reopening-decisions/">https://www.brookings.edu/blog/brown-center-chalkboard/2021/03/25/teachers-unions-scapegoats-or-bad-faith-actors-in-covid-19-school-reopening-decisions/</ref>.</footnote></p>
            <p>When parents shared their concerns at local school board 
                meetings, the Biden administration reacted not with compassion 
                but by threatening to investigate and prosecute parents. In 
                October 2021, Attorney General Merrick Garland instructed the 
                FBI to be on the lookout for “harassment, intimidation, and 
                threats of violence” against school board members and 
                administrators.<ref idref="fn-15"><sup>15</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-15"><num><sup>15 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.justice.gov/ag/page/file/1438986/download">https://www.justice.gov/ag/page/file/1438986/download</ref>.</footnote> This directive followed on the heels of the 
                National School Boards Association’s plea to the White House 
                that some parents’ protests to school boards could be akin to 
                “domestic terrorism.”<ref idref="fn-16"><sup>16</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-16"><num><sup>16 </sup></num><ref href="https://www.edweek.org/policy-politics/national-school-board-groups-apology-for-domestic-terrorism-letter-may-not-quell-uproar/2021/10">https://www.edweek.org/policy-politics/national-school-board-groups-apology-for-domestic-terrorism-letter-may-not-quell-uproar/2021/10</ref>.</footnote></p>
            <p>Parents should never be prosecuted or labeled “domestic 
                terrorists” simply for sharing their frustrations. School 
                board meetings should be open to any concerned parent who 
                wishes to discuss what is happening in their child’s school. 
                H.R. 5 includes provisions that require each school district 
                receiving Title I funds to provide parents an opportunity to 
                address the school board on issues impacting the education of 
                children in the school district. Additionally, parents should 
                have access to their child’s teachers. Since parents are the 
                primary stakeholders of their child’s education, H.R. 5 
                includes provisions to ensure that all parents are aware of 
                their opportunity to meet in person with each of their child’s 
                teachers at least twice a year.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Parents have the right to see the school budget and spending</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Parents have the right to protect their child’s privacy</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Parents have the right to keep their children safe</subheading>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            <heading>CONCLUSION</heading>
            <p>The Biden administration’s politicization of education must 
                stop. Parents have the right to be part of their child’s 
                education. H.R. 5 takes important steps to restore parents’ 
                rights by strengthening provisions in ESEA, FERPA, and the 
                PPRA. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona recently published 
                an op-ed about the Democrat vision for parent empowerment.<ref>27</ref>
                In his vision, parents should be satisfied when the federal 
                government spends taxpayer dollars on top-down solutions. By 
                contrast, Committee Republicans want an authentic give-and-take 
                between parents and the education system about what students 
                learn, how they are taught, and how they should be protected. 
                Democrats seem to believe parents’ rights means the right to 
                accept whatever the experts hand down from on high. H.R. 5 
                rejects that approach and embraces an active role for parents 
                in the education of their children.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment role="summary">
            <heading>SUMMARY H.R. 5, THE PARENTS BILL OF RIGHTS ACT SECTION BY SECTION SUMMARY</heading>
            <subheading class="italic">Section 1. Short title</subheading>
            <list><listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Names the bill as the “Parents Bill of Rights Act.”</listContent></listItem></list>
            <heading>TITLE I—AMENDMENTS TO THE ELEMENTARY AND SECONDARY EDUCATION ACT</heading>
            <subheading class="italic">Section 101. State plan assurances</subheading>
            <list><listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Amends the Title I state plan to require states to 
                        ensure that each school district in the state posts the 
                        curriculum for each grade level on a publicly accessible 
                        website or, if the district does not operate a website, widely 
                        disseminates the curriculum to the public. To protect 
                        intellectual property, the bill specifies that if the 
                        curriculum is not freely and openly available, school districts 
                        must post descriptions of the curriculum and information on how 
                        parents can review the curriculum.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Amends the Title I state plan to require states to 
                        provide the public a copy of any revisions to the state’s 
                        academic content and achievement standards, while also 
                        clarifying that such a notice does not have to be provided to 
                        the Secretary of Education.</listContent></listItem></list>
            <subheading class="italic">Section 102. Annual local educational agency report card</subheading>
            <list><listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Requires school districts that receive Title I 
                        funds to include, as part of their annual report cards to the 
                        public, the budget (including all revenues and expenditures) 
                        for that school year for the district as a whole and for each 
                        school served by that district.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Requires school districts to present summarized 
                        budget information in addition to the detailed information 
                        required to be reported under the bill.</listContent></listItem></list>
            <subheading class="italic">Section 103. Local educational agency plan assurances</subheading>
            <list><listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Amends the Title I local plan to require each 
                        school district that receives Title I funds to post on a 
                        publicly accessible website or, if the district does not 
                        operate a website, widely disseminate to the public, the school 
                        district’s plan for carrying out the parent engagement required 
                        under section 1116 of the Elementary and Secondary Education 
                        Act and the policies and procedures that result from that 
                        engagement.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Ensures that schools notify parents if their 
                        children are not grade-level proficient in reading at the end 
                        of the third grade.</listContent></listItem>
                <listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Requires school districts to ensure that schools 
                        notify parents of individuals or groups that are invited to 
                        speak at school.</listContent></listItem></list>
            <subheading class="italic">Section 104. Parents Right-to-Know</subheading>
            <list><listItem><num>• </num><listContent>Amends the Title I “Parents Right-To-Know” 
                provisions to require each school district that receives Title 
                I funds to ensure that each school served by the district:</listContent>
                    <list><listItem><num>○ </num><listContent>annually posts a summary notice of the right of 
                                parents to information about their children’s education 
                                contained in the Elementary and Secondary Education 
                                Act, including at least:</listContent>
                            <list><listItem><num>&#x25fe; </num><listContent>the right to review the curriculum of the 
                                        child’s school at no cost to parents;</listContent></listItem>
                                <listItem><num>&#x25fe; </num><listContent>the right to make copies of curriculum, in 
                                        addition to inspecting them;</listContent></listItem>
                                <listItem><num>&#x25fe; </num><listContent>the right to know if the state alters the 
                                        state’s academic standards;</listContent></listItem>
                            </list></listItem></list>
            </listItem></list>
            <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
        </segment>
        <segment role="explanation">
            <heading>EXPLANATION OF AMENDMENTS</heading>
            <p>The amendments, including the amendment in the nature of a 
                substitute, are explained in the body of this report.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment role="legislativeBranchApplication">
            <heading>APPLICATION OF LAW TO THE LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</heading>
            <p>Section 102(b)(3) of Public Law 104-1 requires a 
                description of the application of this bill to the legislative 
                branch. H.R. 5. takes important steps to clarify that parents 
                have a right to know what is happening in their child’s school 
                and maintain the right to make decisions about their child’s 
                education, including by putting practices in place that 
                facilitate meaningful dialog between a family and their child’s 
                school, and lead to more input throughout the learning process.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment role="unfundedMandate">
            <heading>UNFUNDED MANDATE STATEMENT</heading>
            <p>Section 423 of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment 
                Control Act (as amended by Section 101(a)(2) of the Unfunded 
                Mandates Reform Act, P.L. 104-4) requires a statement of 
                whether the provisions of the reported bill include unfunded 
                mandates. This issue is addressed in the CBO letter.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment role="earmark">
            <heading>EARMARK STATEMENT</heading>
            <p>H.R. 5 does not contain any congressional earmarks, limited 
                tax benefits, or limited tariff benefits as defined in clause 9 
                of House rule XXI.</p>
        </segment>
        <votesInCommittee>
            <heading>ROLL CALL VOTES</heading>
            <p>Clause 3(b) of rule XIII of the Rules of the House of 
                Representatives requires the Committee Report to include for 
                each record vote on a motion to report the measure or matter 
                and on any amendments offered to the measure or matter the 
                total number of votes for and against and the names of the 
                Members voting for and against.</p>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 2 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 2 scanned image"/></figure>   
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 3 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 3 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 4 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 4 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 5 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 5 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 6 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 6 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 7 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 7 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 8 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 8 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 9 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 9 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 10 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 10 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 11 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 11 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 12 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 12 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 13 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 13 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 14 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 14 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 15 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 15 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 16 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 16 scanned image"/></figure>
            <figure><figCaption>roll call vote 17 scanned image</figCaption><img alt="roll call vote 17 scanned image"/></figure>
        </votesInCommittee>
        <segment>
            <heading>STATEMENT OF GENERAL PERFORMANCE GOALS AND OBJECTIVES</heading>
            <p>In accordance with clause (3)(c) of House rule XIII, the 
                goal of H.R. 5 is to protect parents’ rights in educational 
                decisions about their children.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>DUPLICATION OF FEDERAL PROGRAMS</heading>
            <p>No provision of H.R. 5 establishes or reauthorizes a 
                program of the Federal Government known to be duplicative of 
                another Federal program, a program that was included in any 
                report from the Government Accountability Office to Congress 
                pursuant to section 21 of Public Law 111-139, or a program 
                related to a program identified in the most recent Catalog of 
                Federal Domestic Assistance.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>DISCLOSURE OF DIRECTED RULE MAKINGS</heading>
            <p>The committee estimates enacting H.R. 5 does not 
                specifically direct the completion of any specific rule makings 
                within the meaning of 5 U.S.C. 551.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>STATEMENT OF OVERSIGHT FINDINGS AND RECOMMENDATIONS
                OF THE COMMITTEE</heading>
            <p>In compliance with clause 3(c)(1) of rule XIII and clause 
                2(b)(1) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives, 
                the committee’s oversight findings and recommendations are 
                reflected in the body of this report.</p>
        </segment>
        <segment>
            <heading>REQUIRED COMMITTEE HEARING AND RELATED HEARINGS</heading>
            <p> In compliance with clause 3(c)(6) of rule XIII the 
                following hearing held during the 118th Congress was used to 
                develop or consider H.R. 5: “American Education in Crisis.”</p>
            <p>The following related hearings were held: “Budget Cuts and 
                Lost Learning: Assessing the Impact of Covid-19 on Public 
                Education.”, “Underfunded &amp; Unprepared: Examining How to 
                Overcome Obstacles to Safely Reopen Public Schools.”, “Brown 
                v. Board of Education at 65: A Promise Unfulfilled,”, 
                “Building Back Better: Investing in Improving Schools, 
                Creating Jobs, and Strengthening Families and our Economy.”, 
                “Addressing the Impact of COVID-19 on Students with 
                Disabilities.”, “Back to School: Highlighting Best Practices 
                for Safely Reopening School.”, “Examining the Implementation 
                of COVID-19 Education Funds.”, “Serving All Students: 
                Promoting a Healthier, More Supportive School Environment.”, 
                “Examining the Policies and Priorities of the U.S. Department 
                of Education.”, “Back to School: Meeting Students’ Academic, 
                Social and Emotional Needs.”</p>
        </segment>
        <estimatedCosts>
            <heading>NEW BUDGET AUTHORITY AND CBO COST ESTIMATE</heading>
            <p>With respect to the requirements of clause 3(c)(2) of rule 
                XIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives and section 
                308(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 and with respect 
                to requirements of clause 3(c)(3) of rule XIII of the Rules of 
                the House of Representatives and section 402 of the 
                Congressional Budget Act of 1974, the committee has received 
                the following estimate for H.R. 5 from the Director of the 
                Congressional Budget Office:</p>
            <cboCostEstimate><figure><figCaption>scanned image of CBO Cost Estimate</figCaption><img src="scanned image of CBO cost estimate" alt="scanned image of CBO cost estimate"/></figure>
            <p>H.R. 5 would amend the Elementary and Secondary Education
            Act (ESEA) and the General Education Provisions Act (GEPA) to
            require public schools to allow parents to review certain materials
            and to be informed of, and grant consent for, certain activities. In
            addition, the bill would establish requirements on local education
            agencies (LEAs) as a condition of receiving federal funds.</p>
            <p>Spending subject to appropriation: The bill would amend ESEA
            to require LEAs that receive funding under title I to ensure that
            schools either make certain information publicly available on a
            website or communicate that information to parents. That information
            would include curricula, budgets, lists of parents’ rights, library
            and course materials, and parent engagement plans.</p>
           <p> In addition, H.R. 5 would amend GEPA to require schools that
            participate in programs administered by the Department of Education
            seek parental consent for specified activities—such as the
            use of technology in the classroom, attendance for guest speakers
            in the classroom, or mental health treatment. The bill also would
            restrict the use of student information for commercial and financial
            gain and require LEAs to provide comment periods to solicit feedback
            from parents on course materials, books available to students,
            and professional development materials. Finally, the Secretary of
            Education would be required to report annually to the Congress
            about investigations and enforcement actions by LEAs and state
            education agencies as well as enforcement action taken by the Secretary.</p>
            <p>Enacting H.R. 5 could result in a decrease in estimated authorizations
            for programs at the Department of Education. This would
            come about if schools choose to forgo federal funding by not complying
            with the requirements in the bill. CBO has no basis to estimate
            whether or how many LEAs would do so. CBO estimates that,
            on average, schools receive $275,000 each year in federal funds
            from programs under ESEA title I.</p>
            <p>Direct spending: Title IV of the bill would establish as a condition
            of federal assistance that schools get parental consent before
            staff change a child’s gender marker, pronouns, or preferred name
            on any school form or allow a child to change which bathroom or
            locker room they use. CBO expects that the requirement would
            apply broadly to all federal funds that schools receive, including
            funding that is authorized by laws other than ESEA or GEPA.</p>
            <p>Enacting the parental consent requirement could result in a reduction
            in direct spending through a similar mechanism as spending
            subject to appropriations, but CBO has no basis to predict
            whether, or how many, schools would not comply with the requirement
            in title IV. As a result, CBO cannot estimate the savings related
            to schools not complying with that requirement.</p>
            <p>CBO expects that schools that fail to get such parental consent
            would not be allowed to participate in the child nutrition programs.
            Under the National School Lunch Program (NSLP), the School
            Breakfast Program (SBP), the Child and Adult Care Food Program,
            the Summer Food Service Program, and the Special Milk Program,
            the government provides commodities and cash payments to reimburse
            participating schools and institutions for at least part of the
            cost of each meal served. In 2024, CBO estimates that the average
            school that participates in the NSLP and SBP will receive about
            $121,800 in 2024 under those programs.</p>
            <p>Mandates: Under the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act (UMRA),
            duties required of nonfederal entities do not impose mandates if
            those duties are a condition of federal assistance. H.R. 5 would require
            state and local educational agencies, including schools, to perform
            a series of new duties primarily related to the publication of
            school materials and parental notification, consent, and review. Because
            the duties in H.R. 5 are either explicitly conditioned on accepting
            federal assistance or amend existing laws that apply to recipients
            of federal assistance, the bill would not impose mandates
            under UMRA.</p>
            <p>The CBO staff contact for this estimate is Garrett Quenneville.
            The estimate was reviewed by H. Samuel Papenfuss, Deputy Director
            of Budget Analysis.</p></cboCostEstimate>
            <heading>COMMITTEE COST ESTIMATE</heading>
            <p>Clause 3(d)(1) of rule XIII of the Rules of the House of 
                Representatives requires an estimate and a comparison of the 
                costs that would be incurred in carrying out H.R. 5. However, 
                clause 3(d)(2)(B) of that rule provides that this requirement 
                does not apply when, as with the present report, the committee 
                has included in its report a timely submitted cost estimate of 
                the bill prepared by the Director of the Congressional Budget 
                Office under section 402 of the Congressional Budget Act.</p>
        </estimatedCosts>
        <changesInExistingLaw>
            <heading>CHANGES IN EXISTING LAW MADE BY THE BILL, AS REPORTED</heading>
            <p>With respect to the requirement of clause 3(e) of rule XIII 
                of the Rules of the House of Representatives, changes in 
                existing law made by the bill, as reported, this section was 
                not made available to the Committee in time for the filing of 
                this report. The Chair of the Committee shall have this printed 
                upon its receipt by the Committee.</p>
        </changesInExistingLaw>
        <supplementalViews role="minority">
            <heading>MINORITY VIEWS</heading>
            <segment role="minorityViewIntroduction">
                <heading class="normal">INTRODUCTION</heading>
                <p>The Majority claims that H.R. 5, the <i>Parents Bill of Rights Act</i>,
                    seeks to “put in place concrete legal protections that will ensure
                    parents always have a seat at the table when it comes to their
                    child’s education.”<ref idref="fn-17"><sup>1</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-17"><num><sup>1 </sup></num>Press Release, Rep. Julia Letlow, Letlow Introduces Parents Bill of Rights (Mar. 1, 2023), https://letlow.house.gov/media/press-releases/letlow-reintroduces-parents-bill-rights.</footnote> However, the bill is largely duplicative of current
                    law, lacks clarity in how its provisions will actually address
                    students well-being, and stands as an example of the type federal
                    overreach Congressional Republicans have long claimed would
                    harm children, teachers and schools.</p>
            </segment>
            <segment role="minorityViewSummary">
                <heading class="normal">SUMMARY OF CONCERNS</heading>
            <heading class="italic">H.R. 5 is Duplicative of Current Law</heading>
                <p>The provisions in H.R. 5 are largely duplicative of current 
                    law and create unnecessary and burdensome requirements on state 
                    education agencies (SEAs), local education agencies (LEAs), and 
                    schools. The bill would require these entities to divert 
                    essential resources and personnel away from serving students 
                    and providing them with the supports they need. Recognizing 
                    this is not an exhaustive list, the following are examples of 
                    duplicative provisions contained in H.R. 5.</p>
                <p>Under the <i>Protection of Pupils Rights Amendment</i> (PPRA), 
                    parents already have the right to access instructional 
                    materials used by their child’s school.<ref idref="fn-18"><sup>2</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-18"><num><sup>2 </sup></num>20 U.S.C. 1232h(c)(1).</footnote> Title I of 
                    <i>Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</i> (Title I) also 
                    currently requires that districts conduct outreach to parents 
                    and family members, and implement programs, activities, and 
                    procedures to involve parents and families in their child’s 
                    education.<ref idref="fn-19"><sup>3</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-19"><num><sup>3 </sup></num>20 U.S.C. 6318(a)(1), (b), (d); 20 U.S.C. 6311(d); 20 U.S.C. 6314(b).</footnote> Under the law, each district that receives Title 
                    I funds must have a written parent and family engagement policy 
                    in place that, in part, provides parents with a description and 
                    explanation of the curriculum and assessments used in their 
                    child’s school.<ref idref="fn-20"><sup>4</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-20"><num><sup>4 </sup></num>20 U.S.C. 6318(a)(1); 20 U.S.C. 6318(b), (d).</footnote> Districts and schools must distribute this 
                    policy to parents and family members and hold at least one 
                    annual meeting with families to explain the policy and their 
                    right to be involved.<ref idref="fn-21"><sup>5</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-21"><num><sup>5 </sup></num>20 U.S.C. 6318.</footnote> Many of the additional requirements 
                    placed on SEAs and LEAs would unduly burden Title I schools, 
                    which serve higher portions of students from low-income 
                    backgrounds and students of color. For example, if H.R. 5 
                    became law, funds spent compiling and disseminating required 
                    lists of books and reading materials to families could 
                    otherwise be spent on direct educational services for 
                    disadvantaged students or efforts to close achievement gaps, as 
                    the <i>Elementary and Secondary Education Act</i> (ESEA) mandates.</p>
                <p>[Content is elided in this sample]</p>
            </segment>
            <segment>
                <heading class="normal">DEMOCRATIC AMENDMENTS OFFERED DURING THE MARKUP OF H.R. 5</heading>
                <p>[Content is elided in this sample.]</p>
            </segment>
            <segment role="minorityViewConclusion">
                <heading class="normal">CONCLUSION</heading> 
                <p>House Democrats believe parental engagement is central to 
                    student success. As the American Psychological Association 
                    highlighted, “research shows a strong relationship between 
                    parent engagement and educational outcomes, including school 
                    attendance and higher grades and classroom test scores.” <ref idref="fn-22"><sup>15</sup></ref><footnote id="fn-22"><num><sup>15 </sup></num>What is Parental Engagement, Am Psych. Ass’n, (last visited Mar. 11, 2023), https://www.apa.org/pi/lgbt/programs.safe-supportive/parental-engagement.</footnote> 
                    However, H.R. 5 does not help further promote parental 
                    engagement. Instead, it is a bill largely duplicative of 
                    requirements already in federal and state law; where it expands 
                    upon existing requirements it unduly burdens schools and 
                    families, opens the door for censorship in school curricula and 
                    school libraries and contributes to the de-professionalization 
                    of educators and librarians. The bill does nothing to address 
                    the real challenges facing students, parents, and educators. 
                    Issues like declining math and science scores, achievement 
                    gaps, mental health services, and a lack community centers and 
                    wrap-around services for youth were sidelined to focus on a 
                    political agenda focused not on education but scapegoating some 
                    of our most vulnerable students.</p>
                <p>Simply put, H.R. 5 and PBOR efforts are educational gag 
                    orders across the nation designed to prevent students from 
                    learning and prevent teachers from teaching. These efforts seek 
                    to score political points and scare parents into thinking that 
                    schools do not have their best interests at heart. The 
                    overwhelming majority of parents in this country know this is 
                    not true. Instead, Committee Democrats will continue to 
                    advocate for the support that schools and families actually 
                    need to improve parent-teacher partnerships and support student 
                    well-being and academic achievement. For the reasons stated 
                    above, Committee Democrats unanimously opposed H.R. 5 when the 
                    Committee on Education and the Workforce considered it on March 
                    8, 2023. For the sake of the students of this country, we urge 
                    the House of Representatives to do the same.</p>
            </segment>
            <signatures class="smallCaps">
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="1">Bobby Scott, <inline class="italic normal">Ranking Member.</inline></legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Raúl Grijalva.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Joe Courtney.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Gregorio Sablan.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Frederica Wilson.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Suzanna Bonamici.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Mark Takano.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Alma Adams.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Mark Desaulnier.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Donald Norcross.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Pramila Jayapal.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Lucy McBath.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Jahana Hayes.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Haley Stevens.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Teresa Leger Fernandez.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Frank Mrvan.</legislator></signature>
                <signature><legislator bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="" rank="">Jamaal Bowman.</legislator></signature>
            </signatures>
        </supplementalViews>

    </reportMain>
</legislativeReport>
