<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="legislativeReport.css"?>
<legislativeReport  xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" 
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.1.1.xsd" xml:lang="en">
    <!-- This is sample content for the purposes of illustrating the elements used in USLM for legislative reports. This file should not be used
            for any other purposes as it is incomplete and may not be accurate. -->
    <reportMeta>
        <dc:title>H. Rept. 108-150: KEEPING CHILDREN AND FAMILIES SAFE ACT OF 2003</dc:title>
        <dc:date>2003-06-12</dc:date>
        <dc:type>Conference Report</dc:type>
        <docNumber>150</docNumber>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <citableAs>H. Rept. 108-150</citableAs>
        <citableAs>House Report 108-150</citableAs>
        <citableAs>CRPT-108hrpt150</citableAs>
        <committee>Conference Committee</committee>
        <currentChamber>House</currentChamber>
        <genre>legislative</genre>
        <genre>conference</genre>
        <accompanies>108s342</accompanies> 
        <relatedDocument id="senateVersion" href="/us/bill/108/s/342@es">108s342es</relatedDocument>
        <relatedDocument id="houseVersion" href="/us/bill/108/s/342@eah">108s342eah</relatedDocument>
    </reportMeta>
    <reportPreface> 
        <layout class="reportHeader">
            <row><column class="topLeft"><congress>108th Congress</congress></column><column rowspan="2" class="leftBracket">}</column>
                <column rowspan="2" class="middle"><currentChamber>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</currentChamber></column>
                <column rowspan="2" class="rightBracket">{</column><column class="topRight smallCaps"><dc:type>Report</dc:type></column></row>
            <row><column class="bottomLeft italic"><session>1st Session</session></column><column class="bottomRight"><docNumber>108-150</docNumber></column></row>
        </layout>
        <reportTitle class="centered">KEEPING CHILDREN AND FAMILIES SAFE ACT OF 2003</reportTitle>
        <action><date date="2003-06-12" class="smallCaps">June 12, 2003.—</date><actionDescription class="inline">Ordered to be printed</actionDescription></action>
        <action><actionDescription><sponsor bioGuideId="YYY">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Boehner</inline></sponsor>, from the committee of conference, submitted the following 
                <longTitle><docTitle>CONFERENCE REPORT</docTitle>
                    <accompanies>[To accompany <affected><dc:type>S.</dc:type> <docNumber>342</docNumber></affected>]</accompanies></longTitle>
        </actionDescription></action>
    </reportPreface>
    <reportMain> 
        <recommendation>
            <p>The committee of conference on the disagreeing votes of 
                the two Houses on the amendment of the House to the bill (S. 
                342), to amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to 
                make improvements to and reauthorize programs under that Act, 
                and for other purposes, having met, after full and free 
                conference, have agreed to recommend and do recommend to their 
                respective Houses as follows:</p>
            <p>That the Senate recede from its disagreement to the 
                amendment of the House and agree to the same with an amendment as follows:</p>
            <legislativeSegment role="amendment">
                <amendmentInstruction><content><p class="block">In lieu of the matter proposed to be inserted by the 
                        House amendment, insert the following:</p>
                <amendmentContent changed="added">
                    <section><num>(a) </num><heading>SHORT TITLE.</heading>
                        <content>This Act may be cited as the ‘‘<shortTitle>Keeping Children and Families Safe Act of 2003</shortTitle>’’.</content></section>
                    <section><num>(b) </num><heading>TABLE OF CONTENTS.</heading>
                        <content>
                            <p>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</p>
                            <toc>
                            <referenceItem><designator>Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</designator></referenceItem>
                            <referenceItem class="centered"><designator class="centered">TITLE I—CHILD ABUSE PREVENTION AND TREATMENT ACT</designator></referenceItem>
                            <referenceItem><designator>Sec. 101. Findings.</designator></referenceItem>
                            <referenceItem><designator class="normal">[Content is elided in this sample.]</designator></referenceItem>
                            </toc>
                        </content>
                    </section>
                    <title><num>TITLE I—</num><heading>CHILD ABUSE PREVENTION AND TREATMENT ACT</heading>
                        <section><num>SEC. 101. </num><heading>FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau>Section 2 of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (42 U.S.C. 5101 note) is amended—</chapeau>
                            <subsection><num>(1) </num><content>in paragraph (1), by striking ‘‘close to 1,000,000" and inserting ‘‘approximately 900,000";</content></subsection>
                        <elided class="centered normal">[Content is elided in this sample.]</elided></section>
                    </title>    
                </amendmentContent></content></amendmentInstruction>
            </legislativeSegment>
            <p>And the House agrees to the same.</p>
            <p>From the Committee on Education and the 
                Workforce, for consideration of the Senate bill 
                and the House amendment, and modifications 
                committed to conference:</p>
            <signaturesBlock>    
                <signatures role="House" class="centered">
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">John Boehner,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Pete Hoekstra,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Jon Porter,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">James Greenwood,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Charlie Norwood,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Phil Gingrey,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Max Burns,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">George Miller,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Rubén Hinojosa,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Susan A. Davis,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Tim Ryan,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Danny K. Davis,</legislator></signature>
                    <role>Managers on the Part of the House.</role>
                </signatures>
                <signatures role="Senate" class="centered">
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Judd Gregg,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Lamar Alexander,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Mike Dewine,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Edward M. Kennedy,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Chris Dodd,</legislator></signature>
                    <role>Managers on the Part of the Senate.</role>
                </signatures>
            </signaturesBlock>
        </recommendation>   
        <jointExplanatoryStatement>
            <heading class="centered">JOINT EXPLANATORY STATEMENT OF THE COMMITTEE OF CONFERENCE</heading>
            <p>The managers on the part of the House and the Senate at the conference on
                the disagreeing votes of the two Houses on the amendment of the House to the bill
                (<ref idref="houseVersion">S. 342</ref>), to amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to make improvements
                to and reauthorize programs under that Act, and for other purposes, submit the
                following joint statement to the House and the Senate in explanation of the effect
                of the action agreed upon by the managers and recommended in the accompanying conference report: </p>
            <subheading class="centered"> THE KEEPING CHILDREN AND FAMILIES SAFE ACT OF 2003— EXPLANATION OF THE COMMITTEE OF CONFERENCE</subheading>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement to S. 342, the Keeping Children 
                and Families Safe Act of 2003, builds upon reforms made during 
                the last reauthorization of CAPTA and FVPSA to improve program 
                implementation and make improvements to current law to ensure 
                that states have the necessary resources and flexibility to 
                properly address issues of child abuse and neglect and family 
                violence. It makes changes that serve to assist states in 
                improving their child protective services systems and enhance 
                the federal government's role in providing support for the 
                child protective services system infrastructure. The conference 
                agreement also makes changes to better serve victims of 
                domestic violence and their dependents.</p>
            <p role="chamberDifferences">The Senate bill and House amendment were very similar 
                with only a few major differences. This conference report 
                reflects the agreements on these major differences.</p>
            <subheading class="centered">CAPTA</subheading>
            <subheading class="italic">Comprehensive Adolescent Victim/Victimizer Program</subheading>
            <p role="senatePosition"> The Senate bill, but not the House amendment, includes a 
                new demonstration program that establishes a network of 
                trainers who will work with schools to implement school-based 
                adolescent victim/victimizer programs that are comprehensive, 
                meet state guidelines for health education, and reduce child 
                sexual abuse by focusing on prevention for both adolescent 
                victims and victimizers.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement does not include this provision.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Safety Training for Caseworkers</subheading>
            <p role="senatePosition">The Senate bill, but not the House amendment, includes 
                language to permit ‘‘personal safety training for caseworkers’’ 
                as part of the training for which states may use their CAPTA 
                dollars. Personal safety training will help child protective 
                services personnel be prepared when faced with a variety of 
                complex situations and emotions as they confront families with 
                allegations of child abuse and neglect.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement includes this provision with no modifications.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Infants Born Addicted to Substances</subheading>
            <p role="chamberDifferences">The House amendment and the Senate bill include 
                provisions to address the needs of infants born and identified 
                as being affected by illegal substance abuse or withdrawal 
                symptoms. The House amendment requires procedures for infants 
                born with fetal alcohol effects, fetal alcohol syndrome, 
                neonatal intoxication or withdrawal syndrome, or neonatal 
                physical or neurological harm resulting from prenatal drug 
                exposure. The Senate bill requires procedures for infants born 
                and identified as being affected by illegal substance abuse or 
                withdrawal symptoms resulting form prenatal drug exposure. The 
                House amendment, but not the Senate, requires the notification 
                of child protectiveservices and permits the consideration of 
                providing the mother with additional services, and providing the infant 
                with referral to IDEA, Part C services for evaluation.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement follows the Senate bill with a 
                modification. The agreement includes the requirement that 
                health care providers involved in the delivery or care of 
                infants born and identified as being affected by illegal 
                substance abuse or withdrawal symptoms notify child protective 
                services of the occurrence of such condition in such infants.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">GAO Study</subheading>
            <p role="senatePosition">The Senate bill, but not the House amendment, includes a 
                study to have GAO review and evaluate training (including 
                cross-training in domestic violence and substance abuse) of 
                child protective services workers including the effects of 
                caseloads, compensation and supervision of staff; the 
                efficiencies and effectiveness of agencies that provide cross-
                training with court personnel; and recommendations to 
                strengthen child protective services effectiveness to improve 
                outcomes for children.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement does not include this provision. 
                The House and Senate conferees agree to write a joint letter to 
                GAO to request the study be conducted.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Children's Justice Act</subheading>
            <p role="housePosition">The House amendment, but not the Senate bill, includes 
                language to allow states to handle cases involving children 
                with disabilities or serious health conditions with their 
                children's justice grant funding. Children's justice grants 
                help states improve their child protection programs in 
                investigation and prosecution of child abuse and neglect cases.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement includes this provision with no 
                modifications.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">IDEA</subheading>
            <p role="housePosition">The House amendment, but not the Senate bill, requires 
                states to have provisions and procedures for referral of a 
                child under the age of 3 who is involved in a substantiated 
                case of child abuse or neglect to the statewide early 
                intervention program funded under Part C, of the Individuals 
                with Disabilities Education Act for an evaluation of services.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement does not include this provision. 
                The conferees agree to provide for a reference to similar 
                provisions for referral of such children in Part C of IDEA.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">State CAPTA Reports</subheading>
            <p role="senatePosition">The Senate bill, but not the House amendment, requires 
                states to report on the manner in which CAPTA dollars, alone or 
                in combination with other funds, were used to address the 
                purposes and achieve the objectives of Kinship Care. Kinship 
                care is a living situation in which a grandparent, other close 
                relative or someone else who is emotionally close to a child 
                takes primary responsibility for the care of that child.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement includes this provision with 
                modifications. The agreement requires states to report on all 
                CAPTA programs, rather than just Kinship Care.</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Respite Care</subheading>
            <p role="housePosition">The House amendment, but not the Senate bill, adds 
                respite care, home visiting and family support services to the 
                list of optional core services that a state may provide as a 
                part of family support services under Community-Based Programs 
                within CAPTA.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement does not include this provision. 
                However, the conferees want to recognize the importance of 
                respite care and other services as positive, cost-effective, 
                community-based child abuse and neglect prevention programs. As 
                evidence shows, respite and crises care programs are effective 
                prevention strategies associated with avoiding more costly and 
                traumatic out-of-home placements, including foster care. By 
                retaining current law for local program criteria, the conferees 
                have not intended to discourage or limit the ability of the 
                lead entity or local program to provide or arrange for respite 
                care.</p>
            <subheading class="centered">FVPSA</subheading>
            <subheading class="italic">Children Who Witness Domestic Violence</subheading>
            <p role="senatePosition">The Senate bill, but not the House amendment, establishes 
                a new program to address the needs of children who witness 
                domestic violence to provide direct services; training for and 
                collaboration among child welfare agencies, domestic violence 
                victim service providers, courts, law enforcement and other 
                entities, and multi-system interventions. This new program is 
                conditioned upon appropriations exceeding $150 million. At such 
                time 50 percent of the excess must be used to fund this 
                program.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement follows the intent of the Senate 
                bill with modifications. The agreement would not create a new 
                program. The agreement adds services for children who witness 
                domestic violence to the list of allowable activities under the 
                state demonstration grants within FVPSA. It requires that once 
                appropriations exceed $130 million for the state demonstration 
                grants, that grants include programs of multi-system 
                interventions, training, and services (either directly or by 
                referral) for children who witness domestic violence. The 
                agreement also requires the national resource center to include 
                children who witness domestic violence as part of their 
                research and training services, and adds children who witness 
                domestic violence to the definition of ‘‘related assistance.’’</p>
            <subheading class="italic">Domestic Violence Hotline/Internet Enchancement</subheading>
            <p role="senatePosition">The Senate bill, but not the House amendment, creates a 
                new five year grant program to establish and operate a highly 
                secure Internet website that links the national domestic 
                violence hotline, U.S. domestic violence shelters, state and 
                local domestic violence agencies, and other domestic violence 
                organizations in order to connect a victim of domestic violence 
                to domestic violence shelters. The website must also 
                containcontinuously updated information concerning the availability of 
                services and space in domestic violence shelters across the U.S. This 
                new program is conditioned upon appropriations for the domestic 
                violence hotline exceeding $3 million. The Senate bill, but not the 
                House amendment, increases the authorization for the domestic violence 
                hotline from $2 million to $4 million. The domestic violence hotline is 
                currently funded at $2.6 million.</p>
            <p role="conferenceAgreement">The conference agreement follows the intent of the Senate 
                bill with modifications. The agreement would not create a new 
                program. The agreement requires that once appropriations for 
                the domestic violence hotline exceed $3 million, grants shall 
                be made for startup and operational costs associated with 
                establishing a highly secure Internet website available to the 
                hotline and to shelters. The website shall serve as a database 
                of information describing the services available to victims of 
                domestic violence, including medical and mental health 
                services, social services, transportation, services for 
                children (including children who witness domestic violence) and 
                other relevant services; domestic violence shelters available; 
                and services provided by participating shelters. The 
                authorization for the domestic violence hotline is $3.5 
                million. As a result of recent significant authorization and 
                appropriation increases occurring since the committee's last 
                consideration of this act, the conferees believe an 
                authorization level of $3.5 million will sustain the services 
                provided as a part of the domestic violence hotline during the 
                current five year authorization without the need for 
                intervening authorizations.</p>
        <p>From the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for consideration of the Senate bill 
            and the House amendment, and modifications committed to conference:</p>
            <signaturesBlock>    
                <signatures role="House" class="centered">
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">John Boehner,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Pete Hoekstra,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Jon Porter,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">James Greenwood,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Charlie Norwood,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Phil Gingrey,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Max Burns,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">George Miller,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Rubén Hinojosa,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Susan A. Davis,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Tim Ryan,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Danny K. Davis,</legislator></signature>
                    <role>Managers on the Part of the House.</role>
                </signatures>
                <signatures role="Senate" class="centered">
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Judd Gregg,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Lamar Alexander,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Mike Dewine,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Edward M. Kennedy,</legislator></signature>
                    <signature><legislator class="centered smallCaps" bioGuideId="" partyAffiliation="" caucusAffiliation="">Chris Dodd,</legislator></signature>
                    <role>Managers on the Part of the Senate.</role>
                </signatures>
            </signaturesBlock>
        </jointExplanatoryStatement>
    </reportMain>
    <endMarker>○</endMarker>
</legislativeReport>

