<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><bill xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:uslm="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm uslm-2.0.11-alpha.xsd" xml:lang="en" id="HADE091B36E194D498A39EC547CD8355B">
<!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.-->
<meta>
<dc:title>116 HR 2157 IH: Making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:type>House Bill</dc:type>
<docNumber>2157</docNumber>
<citableAs>116 HR 2157 IH</citableAs>
<citableAs>116hr2157ih</citableAs>
<citableAs>116 H. R. 2157 IH</citableAs>
<dc:creator>United States House of Representatives</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<docStage>IH</docStage>
<processedBy>GPO XPub Bill to USLM Generator, version 0.2</processedBy>
<processedDate>2022-08-15</processedDate>
<congress>116</congress>
<session>1</session>
<currentChamber>HOUSE</currentChamber>
<publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta>
<preface>
<distributionCode display="yes">I</distributionCode>
<congress value="116">116th CONGRESS</congress>
<session value="1">1st Session</session>
<dc:type>H. R. </dc:type>
<docNumber>2157</docNumber>
<dc:title>Making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<currentChamber value="HOUSE" display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</currentChamber>
<action><date date="2019-04-09">April 9, 2019</date><actionDescription><sponsor bioGuideId="L000480">Mrs.Lowey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee committeeId="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee committeeId="HBU00">the Budget</committee>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</actionDescription></action></preface><main id="HD33CBB9DC6DA4C6086CC7B9C2ED3E7D6" styleType="appropriations"><longTitle><docTitle>A Bill</docTitle><officialTitle>Making supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</officialTitle></longTitle><enactingFormula>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, </enactingFormula><section id="H5C1E6AB8CE77415B9D67C7FC2E3E70E0" role="undesignated-section" class="inline"><content class="inline">That the following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, and out of applicable corporate or other revenues, receipts, and funds, for the several departments, agencies, corporations, and other organizational units of Government for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes, namely:</content></section>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI" id="HAF4848F782A54DB285FF678C221D33A3" styleType="appropriations"><num value="I">TITLE I</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</heading><appropriations level="major" id="HAE65AEDAE483469DB073BE9793FF97C7"><heading>AGRICULTURAL PROGRAMS</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H29D8440CCE154F0E8837831E48A6BA83"><heading>Processing, Research and Marketing</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H56DAB79418EA4603973C16894654B64C"><heading>Office of the Secretary</heading><content>For an additional amount for the “Office of the Secretary”, $3,005,442,000, which shall remain available until December 31, 2020, for necessary expenses related to losses of crops (including milk, on-farm stored commodities, and harvested adulterated wine grapes), trees, bushes, and vines, as a consequence of Hurricanes Michael and Florence, other hurricanes, floods, tornadoes, typhoons, volcanic activity, snowstorms, and wildfires occurring in calendar years 2018 and 2019 under such terms and conditions as determined by the Secretary: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That the Secretary may provide assistance for such losses in the form of block grants to eligible States and territories and such assistance may include compensation to producers, as determined by the Secretary, for past or future crop insurance premiums, forest restoration, and poultry and livestock losses: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That of the amounts provided under this heading, tree assistance payments may be made under section 1501(e) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s9081/e">7 U.S.C. 9081(e)</ref>) to eligible orchardists or nursery tree growers (as defined in such section) of pecan trees with a tree mortality rate that exceeds 7.5 percent (adjusted for normal mortality) and is less than 15 percent (adjusted for normal mortality), to be available until expended, for losses incurred during the period beginning January 1, 2018, and ending December 31, 2018: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That in the case of producers impacted by volcanic activity that resulted in the loss of crop land, or access to crop land, the Secretary shall consider all measures available, as appropriate, to bring replacement land into production: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the total amount of payments received under this heading and applicable policies of crop insurance under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1501/etseq">7 U.S.C. 1501 et seq.</ref>) or the Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program (NAP) under section 196 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7333">7 U.S.C. 7333</ref>) shall not exceed 90 percent of the loss as determined by the Secretary: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the total amount of payments received under this heading for producers who did not obtain a policy or plan of insurance for an insurable commodity for the applicable crop year under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1501/etseq">7 U.S.C. 1501 et seq.</ref>) for the crop incurring the losses or did not file the required paperwork and pay the service fee by the applicable State filing deadline for a noninsurable commodity for the applicable crop year under NAP for the crop incurring the losses shall not exceed 70 percent of the loss as determined by the Secretary: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That producers receiving payments under this heading, as determined by the Secretary, shall be required to purchase crop insurance where crop insurance is available for the next two available crop years, excluding tree insurance policies, and producers receiving payments under this heading shall be required to purchase coverage under NAP where crop insurance is not available in the next two available crop years, as determined by the Secretary: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, not later than 120 days after the end of fiscal year 2019, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress specifying the type, amount, and method of such assistance by State and territory: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HE3DA75E1F96C4B55A81B2A16ABCA5FF4"><heading>Farm Service Agency</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H8B36FFA772DE4C36A9E06FAE22681F81"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">emergency forest restoration program</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for the “Emergency Forest Restoration Program”, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael and Florence and wildfires occurring in calendar year 2018, and other natural disasters, $480,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HB3D793646F1E4DE9A58C3E8DFCF6A67D"><heading>Natural Resources Conservation Service</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HB96132D53B684814A14D314AA17CFFAC"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">watershed and flood prevention operations</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Watershed and Flood Prevention Operations”, for necessary expenses for the Emergency Watershed Protection Program related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael and Florence and wildfires occurring in calendar year 2018, and other natural disasters, $125,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HA42DC9F6555049C883A217B9B3A3376A"><heading>Rural Development</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HAEF0E2A6968748B293C75EC2B118D12A"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">rural community facilities program account</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for the cost of grants for rural community facilities programs as authorized by section 306 and described in section 381E(d)(1) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael and Florence and wildfires occurring in calendar year 2018, and other natural disasters, $150,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That sections 381E–H and 381N of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act are not applicable to the funds made available under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H3C5C8DE862594BAEBD7D060055B79AE2"><heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s101" id="H17CCD9DE54564336A015CC8632923B0D"><num value="101"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 101. </inline></num><content class="inline">In addition to other amounts made available by section 309 of division A of the Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/72">Public Law 115–72</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/131/1229">131 Stat. 1229</ref>), there is hereby appropriated $600,000,000 for the Secretary of Agriculture to provide a grant to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for disaster nutrition assistance in response to Presidentially declared major disasters and emergencies: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That the funds made available to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico under this section shall remain available for obligation by the Commonwealth until September 30, 2020, and shall be in addition to funds otherwise made available: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s102" id="H6FB82DE790214B59B748FD5CEA9527EE"><num value="102"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 102. </inline></num><content class="inline">In addition to amounts otherwise made available, out of the funds made available under section 18 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, $25,200,000 shall be available for the Secretary to provide a grant to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands for disaster nutrition assistance in response to the Presidentially declared major disasters and emergencies: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That funds made available to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands under this section shall remain available for obligation by the Commonwealth until September 30, 2020: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s103" id="H48D7D7C42BE7460583292A18EFAA42B0"><num value="103"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 103. </inline></num><content class="inline">For purposes of administering title I of subdivision 1 of division B of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>), losses to agricultural producers resulting from hurricanes shall also include losses of peach and blueberry crops in calendar year 2017 due to extreme cold: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That the amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That amounts repurposed under this heading that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104" id="H7B26994E34FB4DCEAFE519297DE524CD"><num value="104"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 104. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104/a" id="HDE179E688510474982F55B39CED30DE8" class="inline"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104/a/1" id="HDB23262DE9C446BBAC969673DB755DD1" class="inline"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a person or legal entity is not eligible to receive a payment under the Market Facilitation Program established pursuant to the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s714/etseq">15 U.S.C. 714 et seq.</ref>) if the average adjusted gross income of such person or legal entity is greater than $900,000.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104/a/2" id="HDAF317CCC6FE4CDF97C4C8F2E515875A" class="indent0"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a person or legal entity if at least 75 percent of the adjusted gross income of such person or legal entity is derived from farming, ranching, or forestry related activities.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104/b" id="H6D4CE9328600448D8718B371A0FD9952" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><content>A person or legal entity may not receive a payment under the Market Facilitation Program described in subsection (a)(1), directly or indirectly, of more than $125,000.</content></subsection>
<subsection role="definitions" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104/c" id="HED9D5206D658475FA9F693DDB842006B" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><content>In this section, the term “<term>average adjusted gross income</term>” has the meaning given the term defined in section 760.1502 of title 7 Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect July 18, 2018).</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s104/d" id="H5EA375364B5748928A24FC060EB0981E" class="indent0"><num value="d">(d) </num><content>The amount provided by this section is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s105" id="H77AD977C44A047D2A73E79AF2EEE0387"><num value="105"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 105. </inline></num><content class="inline">There is hereby appropriated $5,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, for the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct an independent study, including a survey of participants, to compare the impact of the additional benefits provided by <ref href="/us/pl/115/72/s309">section 309 of Public Law 115–72</ref> to the food insecurity, health status, and well-being of low-income residents in Puerto Rico without such additional benefits: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s106" id="H0EFCFD8CB0A0447C8D792FF969577984"><num value="106"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 106. </inline></num><content class="inline">In addition to amounts otherwise made available, out of the funds made available under section 18 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, $5,000,000 shall be available for the Secretary to provide a grant to American Samoa for disaster nutrition assistance in response to the Presidentially declared major disasters and emergencies: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That funds made available to the territory under this section shall remain available for obligation by the territory until September 30, 2020: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tI/s107" id="HC9804A7A02034C68B05114917AA0DDF1"><num value="107"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 107. </inline></num><content class="inline">For an additional amount for the “Emergency Conservation Program”, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael and Florence and of wildfires occurring in calendar year 2018, and other natural disasters, $500,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tII" id="HD7AFA254401E44239179F32D552D753D" styleType="appropriations"><num value="II">TITLE II</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HEC3219ABAFC449CAAB0E9A6787EEEAD5"><heading>Economic Development Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HC7DC74666E72462183DAE74524CC5224"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">economic development assistance programs</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H629BA734B0704A75B95667738778E262"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfers of funds)</inline></heading><content>Pursuant to section 703 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3233">42 U.S.C. 3233</ref>), for an additional amount for “Economic Development Assistance Programs” for necessary expenses related to flood mitigation, disaster relief, long-term recovery, and restoration of infrastructure in areas that received a major disaster designation as a result of Hurricanes Florence, Michael, and Lane, Typhoons Yutu and Mangkhut, and of wildfires, volcanic eruptions, earthquakes, and other natural disasters occurring in calendar year 2018, and tornadoes and floods occurring in calendar year 2019 under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>), $600,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That within the amount appropriated, up to 2 percent of funds may be transferred to the “Salaries and Expenses” account for administration and oversight activities: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That within the amount appropriated, $1,000,000 shall be transferred to the “Office of Inspector General” account for carrying out investigations and audits related to the funding provided under this heading.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HA151EC357BE04A81B7C0B587A12D2CF3"><heading>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HB9F41A60062D49BDBFD741AC7AEEF3E3"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">operations, research, and facilities</inline></heading><chapeau>For an additional amount for “Operations, Research, and Facilities” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Yutu, and of wildfires, $120,570,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph id="H0FC93724DFFC4D9C9378A6532D571C75" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>$3,000,000 for repair and replacement of observing assets, real property, and equipment;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6025406167AB4D3AB3FD90C8ED2C79A4" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>$11,000,000 for marine debris assessment and removal;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6420F06BDDD64FF0B7F41B5DFA35C8EF" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>$31,570,000 for mapping, charting, and geodesy services;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5DC7D13AEBDC4108AA497A5DA9E79022" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>$25,000,000 to improve: (a) hurricane intensity forecasting, including through deployment of unmanned ocean observing platforms and enhanced data assimilation; (b) flood prediction, forecasting, and mitigation capabilities; and (c) wildfire prediction, detection, and forecasting; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79A49BA5AAE8440CAF15BCEB44E64C94" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content>$50,000,000 for Title IX Fund grants as authorized under <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dO/s906/c">section 906(c) of division O of Public Law 114–113</ref>:</content></paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0"> <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall submit a spending plan to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for funding provided under subsection (4) of this heading within 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></continuation></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HEBAE17920FE94F3188713D5AE1FD8FCB"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">procurement, acquisition and construction</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Procurement, Acquisition and Construction”, $25,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2021, for improvements to operational and research weather supercomputing infrastructure and satellite ground services used for hurricane intensity and track prediction; flood prediction, forecasting, and mitigation; and wildfire prediction, detection, and forecasting: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall submit a spending plan to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate within 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H93586ED945D943C18E9886851DF64C45"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">fishery disaster assistance</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Fishery Disaster Assistance” for necessary expenses associated with the mitigation of fishery disasters, $150,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That funds shall be used for mitigating the effects of commercial fishery failures and fishery resource disasters declared by the Secretary of Commerce, including those declared by the Secretary to be a direct result of Hurricanes Florence and Michael and Typhoons Yutu and Mangkhut: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H326155527CF54E7392A5D1424C2699BF"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HCFA2697DEA064A318CAB11E7CB6BE43C"><heading>United States Marshals Service</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H5C75A7997D9E498F88D96F109A45AD2C"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">salaries and expenses</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Salaries and Expenses” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael and Typhoon Yutu, $1,336,000: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H313024DF4C7A461780F739E5FA500A06"><heading>Federal Prison System</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H4820C0060E5D4483970BD443D9F04FBD"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">buildings and facilities</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Buildings and Facilities” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael and Typhoon Yutu, $28,400,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H41D615E2E1EF47EA8B77C0269534CE1E"><heading>RELATED AGENCIES</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H9D680B6ACF16473D863B4FF7F51957C5"><heading>Legal Services Corporation</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H17184B3F5937483C983AA46B4C1FCF71"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">payment to the legal services corporation</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Payment to the Legal Services Corporation” to carry out the purposes of the Legal Services Corporation Act by providing for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence, Michael, and Lane, Typhoons Yutu and Mangkhut, calendar year 2018 wildfires, volcanic eruptions, and earthquakes, and calendar year 2019 tornadoes and floods, $15,000,000: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That none of the funds appropriated in this Act to the Legal Services Corporation shall be expended for any purpose prohibited or limited by, or contrary to any of the provisions of, sections 501, 502, 503, 504, 505, and 506 of <ref href="/us/pl/105/119">Public Law 105–119</ref>, and all funds appropriated in this Act to the Legal Services Corporation shall be subject to the same terms and conditions set forth in such sections, except that all references in sections 502 and 503 to 1997 and 1998 shall be deemed to refer instead to 2018 and 2019, respectively, and except that sections 501 and 503 of <ref href="/us/pl/104/134">Public Law 104–134</ref> (referenced by <ref href="/us/pl/105/119">Public Law 105–119</ref>) shall not apply to the amount made available under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, for the purposes of this Act, the Legal Services Corporation shall be considered an agency of the United States Government.</proviso></content></appropriations></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tIII" id="H848D435AC2034ABB93E81E4E372E5753" styleType="appropriations"><num value="III">TITLE III</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H1A90B027769A4FFCB92A17D62EA41231"><heading>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps”, $200,000,000, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael and Florence: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s284">section 284 of title 10, United States Code</ref>, or any other provision of law, funds made available under this heading may only be used for the purposes specifically described under this heading.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HF4914D51A7984BF19C275A7678A083EE"><heading>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Operation and Maintenance, Air Force”, $400,000,000, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael and Florence: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s284">section 284 of title 10, United States Code</ref>, or any other provision of law, funds made available under this heading may only be used for the purposes specifically described under this heading.</proviso></content></appropriations></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tIV" id="H6E314629B7E840F193C027A2B318ACFD" styleType="appropriations"><num value="IV">TITLE IV</num><heading>CORPS OF ENGINEERS—CIVIL</heading><appropriations level="major" id="H052B75297FDA4B558A17F7CBBE7CCD14"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HD720B0D3E3E8446A9EB667E57CE736A0"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">investigations</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Investigations” for necessary expenses related to the completion, or initiation and completion, of flood and storm damage reduction, including shore protection, studies which are currently authorized or which are authorized after the date of enactment of this Act, to reduce risk from future floods and hurricanes, at full Federal expense, $35,000,000, to remain available until expended, in States and insular areas that were impacted by Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, and Tropical Storm Gita: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide a monthly report directly to the Committees on Appropriations of the House and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds, including new studies selected to be initiated using funds provided under this heading, beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HC8FF3C639B6B40318FD2E295AD115CB8"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">construction</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Construction” for necessary expenses, $740,000,000, to remain available until expended, to construct flood and storm damage reduction, including shore protection, projects which are currently authorized or which are authorized after the date of enactment of this Act, and flood and storm damage reduction, including shore protection, projects which have signed Chief’s Reports as of the date of enactment of this Act or which are studied using funds provided under the heading “<headingText>Investigations</headingText>” if the Secretary determines such projects to be technically feasible, economically justified, and environmentally acceptable, in States and insular areas that were impacted by Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, and Tropical Storm Gita: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That projects receiving funds provided under the first proviso in “Corps of Engineers–Civil—Department of the Army—Construction” in <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref> shall not be eligible for funding provided under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That for projects receiving funding under this heading, the provisions of section 902 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 shall not apply to these funds: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the completion of ongoing construction projects receiving funds provided under this heading shall be at full Federal expense with respect to such funds: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That using funds provided under this heading, the non-Federal cash contribution for projects other than ongoing construction projects shall be financed in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/99/662/s103/k">section 103(k) of Public Law 99–662</ref> over a period of 30 years from the date of completion of the project or separable element: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That of this amount, $45,000,000 shall be used to initiate, at full Federal expense, construction of authorized Corps of Engineers ecosystem restoration projects that have incidental flood risk management benefits in areas impacted by Hurricanes Irma and Maria: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That up to $25,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading shall be used for continuing authorities projects to reduce the risk of flooding and storm damage: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That any projects using funds appropriated under this heading shall be initiated only after non-Federal interests have entered into binding agreements with the Secretary requiring, where applicable, the non-Federal interests to pay 100 percent of the operation, maintenance, repair, replacement, and rehabilitation costs of the project and to hold and save the United States free from damages due to the construction or operation and maintenance of the project, except for damages due to the fault or negligence of the United States or its contractors: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide a monthly report directly to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds, beginning not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H52744080A4D94CDA93D3B8E1B9E6F5FF"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">mississippi river and tributaries</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Mississippi River and Tributaries” for necessary expenses to address emergency situations at Corps of Engineers projects and rehabilitate and repair damages to Corps of Engineers projects, caused by natural disasters, including disasters in 2019, $575,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide a monthly report directly to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds, beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H1A82BE1DA83F46CA8CCDE056D0995372"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">operation and maintenance</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Operation and Maintenance” for necessary expenses to dredge Federal navigation projects in response to, and repair damages to Corps of Engineers Federal projects caused by, natural disasters, including disasters in 2019, $908,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which such sums as are necessary to cover the Federal share of eligible operation and maintenance costs for coastal harbors and channels, and for inland harbors shall be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide a monthly report directly to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds, beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HB44CBCFE20F146D081D2BF3D76C7C24F"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">flood control and coastal emergencies</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies”, as authorized by section 5 of the Act of August 18, 1941 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</ref>), for necessary expenses to prepare for flood, hurricane and other natural disasters and support emergency operations, repairs, and other activities in response to such disasters, including disasters in 2019, as authorized by law, $510,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide a monthly report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds, beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="HB4B93331FB2C44A0AE49D78E2BBF1CB2"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HF2CBF087ED4847AB80016A2AF91A53CE"><heading>Central Utah Project</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H9BA991EE36894F6580E562C11E396378"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">central utah project completion account</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Central Utah Project Completion Account”, $350,000, to be deposited into the Utah Reclamation Mitigation and Conservation Account for use by the Utah Reclamation Mitigation and Conservation Commission, to remain available until expended, for expenses necessary in carrying out fire remediation activities related to wildfires in 2018: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H60E81A1D80994BC5A478A0F466FCC4D3"><heading>Bureau of Reclamation</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HAC56CFA924284CDD93D986274C210728"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">water and related resources</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Water and Related Resources”, $17,000,000, to remain available until expended, for fire remediation and suppression emergency assistance related to wildfires in 2017 and 2018: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H65270466DF704646A2CDC93DD2A7F8B2"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H8DA4C06178EA44A9A7012D9505367381"><heading>ENERGY PROGRAMS</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H69033C77063545CFA2275FAC2BA4F220"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">electricity delivery</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Electricity Delivery”, $15,500,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and Super Typhoon Yutu, including technical assistance related to electric grids: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Assistant Secretary of Electricity Delivery shall provide a monthly report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds, beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</proviso></content></appropriations></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV" id="HB914A32F758449FB8907726D1FB4360A" styleType="appropriations"><num value="V">TITLE V</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY</heading><appropriations level="major" id="H56EF8058650C4AD383B52DB6F16BFCAB"><heading>SECURITY, ENFORCEMENT, AND INVESTIGATIONS</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H328E9104DBDF490B81381427DF081312"><heading>Coast Guard</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HBD47564C7F0E4CB58D7E51B037919644"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">operations and support</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Operations and Support” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael, Florence, and Lane, Tropical Storm Gordon, and Typhoon Mangkhut, $48,977,000; of which $46,977,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2020, and of which $2,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2023, for environmental compliance and restoration: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H1C07D8FFD9DA4B1297C7D4FB1FEFAB3B"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">procurement, construction, and improvements</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Procurement, Construction, and Improvements” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Michael, Florence, and Lane, Tropical Storm Gordon, and Typhoon Mangkhut, $476,755,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="HA2787C858E8446F7B4F14AB4B69DA7B7"><heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s501" id="HE0E5D3C83EC24867AF0A9D108C76B2C8"><num value="501"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 501. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s501/a" id="HFED0F5DAC0A248E18584CDBD4A76CC48" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Federal share of assistance provided for DR–4336–PR, DR–4339–PR, DR–4340–USVI and DR–4335–USVI under sections 403, 406, and 407 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b</ref> and 5173) shall be 100 percent of the eligible costs under such sections.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s501/b" id="H0031996AAB814EDEB47302BA0F59479C" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>The Federal share provided by subsection (a) shall apply to disaster assistance applied for before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s502" id="H04C2B08A5C9046BAAF7B3370D60EB7D1"><num value="502"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 502. </inline></num><chapeau class="inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide assistance, pursuant to section 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>), for critical services as defined in section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for the duration of the recovery for incidents DR–4404, DR–4396, and DR–4398 to—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s502/1" id="H29DFF2DE742E47C19717168C16BC0487" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>replace or restore the function of a facility or system to industry standards without regard to the pre-disaster condition of the facility or system; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s502/2" id="H8437E4EB525F48498449A18A58A37792" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>replace or restore components of the facility or system not damaged by the disaster where necessary to fully effectuate the replacement or restoration of disaster-damaged components to restore the function of the facility or system to industry standards.</content></paragraph></section>
<section role="instruction" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s503" id="HB9EAE83974E4474AA2F5B47ACE0DAC6C"><num value="503"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 503. </inline></num><content class="inline"><ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s20601">Section 20601 of Public Law 115–123</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/132/85">132 Stat. 85</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>may</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>shall</quotedText>”. <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That the amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That amounts repurposed under this heading that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504" id="HBC6A67A7FFE44F7AA624D32F8AEE4F48" role="subsequent-section"><num value="504"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 504. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/a" id="HC56E9E62C6A348BB9DB699D38AB6CE2E" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall make a contribution under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</ref>) for each eligible rural medical facility that was damaged or destroyed by a major disaster during calendar year 2015, regardless of whether the operations of such medical facility were subsequently carried out in a temporary replacement facility. Such contribution shall be sufficient to provide for a full permanent replacement of each such medical facility to the resiliency standards described in subsection (b).</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/b" id="HC55990555B55408992F5E6F88BAC3F18" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Resiliency Standards</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A permanent replacement facility provided for under this section shall meet—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/b/1" id="HE97D1833348E471883323FEE13A45DC9" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>the definition of resilient developed pursuant to section 406(e) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172/e">42 U.S.C. 5172(e)</ref>); and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/b/2" id="HDD46E795B2854B728786686ACC42E5BA" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>any relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/c" id="H39EA017BC65D44ED99D5749190911842" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Temporary Replacement Facility</inline>.—</heading><content>In any case in which the President, acting through the Federal Emergency Management Agency, has provided funding to lease or purchase a temporary replacement facility to house the operations of an eligible rural medical facility for which a permanent replacement facility is required under this section, the President shall continue such funding until a permanent replacement facility is operational, including for any period of time for which funding has not otherwise been provided.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/d" id="H66CD29FE71CA4D69AEFCB6BEE3B63067" class="indent0"><num value="d">(d) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Hospital Successor Entity</inline>.—</heading><content>A transfer in ownership of an eligible rural medical facility or of a permanent replacement facility, or the execution of a transaction by the owner of an eligible rural medical facility resulting in different ownership of a permanent replacement facility, shall not affect the requirement in subsection (a) to provide for a full replacement of the facility for which funds are provided under this section, provided that such funds are provided to an entity otherwise eligible for assistance under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</ref>).</content></subsection>
<subsection role="definitions" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/e" id="HF62420FF906D425F8234EADCBA630A2F" class="indent0"><num value="e">(e) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Definition of Eligible Rural Medical Facility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term “<term>eligible rural medical facility</term>” means a private nonprofit hospital facility—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/e/1" id="H2A50CEB829A0458A862E3A2E9AB14051" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>located in a county with a population below 40,000, as determined by the most recent decennial census;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/e/2" id="H04CE15CB94044C49BF259DE768323926" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>that sustained damage during calendar year 2015 that was eligible for financial assistance under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</ref>); and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/e/3" id="H55B9224D647441938EAF0692D801528D" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>that was closed following damage sustained during a major disaster and remains closed as of the date of enactment of this Act.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s504/f" id="HF85B65CC130F44F3B99F979858976A90" class="indent0"><num value="f">(f) </num><content>The amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505" id="HA33838A1A6DB40D2824B61F9C43A1878"><num value="505"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 505. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/a" id="H7791F8E9900B4E29B718D581061A23E2" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall make a contribution under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</ref>) to the applicable State or local government for each eligible hydroelectric facility that was damaged or destroyed by a major disaster during calendar year 2015 to carry out the improvements for which such contribution was provided under this section.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/b" id="HFDF858188B1643EA8E4891E678023B52" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Contribution</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each contribution provided for improvements to an eligible hydroelectric facility under subsection (a) shall be sufficient to—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/b/1" id="HBBA3271C5EEE4189B4EA494DEA92CBB1" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>rebuild canal embankments to meet all applicable guidelines in the Engineering Guidelines for the Evaluation of Hydropower Projects prepared by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/b/2" id="H8B893257A9784AC6B00945EE9A873942" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>restore all other water-control and retaining structures to meet all applicable such Engineering Guidelines; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/b/3" id="HB0A2470DDFE545C198FD1BC920D6716B" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><chapeau>provide for either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/b/3/A" id="H898BE39AD7C84A9199C69F5B633C29A5" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>the restoration of the eligible hydroelectric facility to full operation of its function as a primary water source and hydroelectric power supply; or</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/b/3/B" id="HE3D09E30FC7042DEBB2C38E128389882" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>the establishment of an alternative primary water source and the restoration of the full operation of the hydroelectric power supply function of the eligible hydroelectric facility pursuant to the requirements of subsection (c).</content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/c" id="HD7203EE3CFA746EE87E352CD939C7959" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Alternative Contribution</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A contribution may cover the establishment of an alternative primary water source under subsection (b)(3)(B) only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/c/1" id="H4BBF9F2DF64F4C5AB0550D76D01D0689" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>the water source could provide redundancy to the water supply provided by an eligible hydroelectric facility;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/c/2" id="HD253FBD089A64AC3BB6E9FFCDBD80BAC" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>the water source is approved by any applicable regulatory agencies; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/c/3" id="HAE7510AF0EE9458B99B6E1B82EE10B68" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>the cost of the establishment of such water source and the restoration of the full operation of the hydroelectric power supply function of the eligible hydroelectric facility is less than the cost of restoring the eligible hydroelectric facility to full operation as described under subsection (b)(3)(A).</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/d" id="HD590AA3A0E5D4BA6B58CD01CC888975F" class="indent0"><num value="d">(d) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Resiliency Standards</inline>.—</heading><content>An improvement carried out under this section shall meet the definition of resilient developed pursuant to section 406(e) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172/e">42 U.S.C. 5172(e)</ref>).</content></subsection>
<subsection role="definitions" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/e" id="H12732DE07696485A8BAED32FC61B52F3" class="indent0"><num value="e">(e) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Definition of Eligible Hydroelectric Facility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term “<term>eligible hydroelectric facility</term>” means a hydroelectric facility that—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/e/1" id="H9191E32A2BCF4BF8AD2CC1E30202DF56" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>is part of a system that provides the primary water source for more than 200,000 people;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/e/2" id="HE637C596B0994D009EBEE878D20756B0" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>sustained damage eligible for financial assistance under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</ref>);</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/e/3" id="HEF20F1D3A79044D5BC73CA1142355967" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>is licensed by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under part I of the Federal Power Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s792/etseq">16 U.S.C. 792 et seq.</ref>); and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/e/4" id="HD9A358FBB87640499C6DFE4C7EFF5AA1" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>has been assigned a significant hazard potential classification in accordance with chapter 1 of the Engineering Guidelines for the Evaluation of Hydropower Projects prepared by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tV/s505/f" id="H0BE3E765B17245F1B66E149D4BF2ABFB" class="indent0"><num value="f">(f) </num><content>The amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></subsection></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVI" id="H90FA1FA9160A492AAD23EB9D24A0BE69" styleType="appropriations"><num value="VI">TITLE VI</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HF6DB9FD3DB4A4497B547CEC25A235E93"><heading>United States Fish and Wildlife Service</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H3868ED280E83411A9298C3A727CE4DA0"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">construction</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Construction” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence, Lane, and Michael, and flooding associated with major declared disaster DR–4365, and calendar year 2018 earthquakes, $82,400,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That of this amount $50,000,000 shall be used to restore and rebuild national wildlife refuges and increase the resiliency and capacity of coastal habitat and infrastructure to withstand storms and reduce the amount of damage caused by such storms: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H01E1DB3ECE084735A52A00C81037A468"><heading>National Park Service</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HE0AA3FC06841437FA82E1006FC4384E5"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">historic preservation fund</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for the “Historic Preservation Fund” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, and Typhoon Yutu, $50,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022, including costs to States and territories necessary to complete compliance activities required by <ref href="/us/usc/t54/s306108">section 306108 of title 54, United States Code</ref> (formerly section 106 of the National Historic Preservation Act) and costs needed to administer the program: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That grants shall only be available for areas that have received a major disaster declaration pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>): </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That individual grants shall not be subject to a non-Federal matching requirement: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H31DD44921A3746AD98FE2646B8029889"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">construction</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Construction” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoons Yutu and Mangkhut, and calendar year 2018 wildfires, earthquakes, and volcanic eruptions, $78,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H9FE3E80DF9764EFE98BE14E27ABA3481"><heading>United States Geological Survey</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HAE328B043844403B9F5C2A3B0A59E4EF"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">surveys, investigations, and research</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Surveys, Investigations, and Research” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, and calendar year 2018 wildfires, earthquake damage associated with emergency declaration EM–3410, and in those areas impacted by a major disaster declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>) with respect to calendar year 2018 wildfires or volcanic eruptions, $98,500,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That of this amount, $72,310,000 is for costs related to the repair and replacement of equipment and facilities damaged by disasters in 2018: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Survey shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations that describes the potential options to replace the facility damaged by the 2018 volcano disaster along with cost estimates and a description of how the Survey will provide direct access for monitoring volcanic activity and the potential threat to at-risk communities: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H3D83029C14D44C1AAF878EB262B7CA33"><heading>Departmental Offices</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HAC606B7677E24F6C88D044A58458A868"><heading>Insular Affairs</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H1519359C5F4C45A187E07CE4F5729F0F"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">assistance to territories</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Technical Assistance” for financial management expenses related to the consequences of Typhoon Yutu, $2,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HB1D848A38F7B497F8C2E2ED44AE0AD90"><heading>Office of Inspector General</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H26B56C59B92C407FBEF469C5A6D93249"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">salaries and expenses</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Salaries and Expenses” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of major disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>) in 2018, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H699E9DD28D80471896D1C43E294F9DCF"><heading>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H5F286118F02B4113BA24DEC9B4CCA6E0"><heading>Science and Technology</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Science and Technology” for necessary expenses related to improving preparedness of the water sector, $600,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H1CA32C5993924D2F844BEA273A808DF3"><heading>Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund Program</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Leaking Underground Storage Tank Fund” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, calendar year 2018 earthquakes, and Typhoon Yutu, $1,500,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H4912D62B9AF946679F921B4BD0F91CDD"><heading>State and Tribal Assistance Grants</heading><content>
<p>For additional amounts for “State and Tribal Assistance Grants” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael and calendar year 2018 earthquakes for the hazardous waste financial assistance grants program, $1,500,000, to remain available until expended; for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Typhoon Yutu for the hazardous waste financial assistance grants program and for other solid waste management activities, $56,000,000, to remain available until expended, provided that none of these funds shall be subject to section 3011(b) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act; and for grants under section 106 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended, to address impacts of Hurricane Florence, Hurricane Michael, Typhoon Yutu, and calendar year 2018 wildfires, notwithstanding subsections (b), (e), and (f), of such section: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amounts are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></p>
<p>For an additional amount for “State and Tribal Assistance Grants”, $349,400,000 to remain available until expended, of which $53,300,000 shall be for capitalization grants for the Clean Water State Revolving Funds under title VI of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and of which $296,100,000 shall be for capitalization grants under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That notwithstanding section 604(a) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and section 1452(a)(1)(D) of the Safe Drinking Water Act, funds appropriated herein shall be provided to States or Territories in EPA Regions 4, 9, and 10 in amounts determined by the Administrator for wastewater treatment works and drinking water facilities impacted by Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Yutu, and calendar year 2018 wildfires and earthquakes: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding the requirements of section 603(i) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and section 1452(d) of the Safe Drinking Water Act, for the funds appropriated herein, each State shall use not less than 20 percent but not more than 30 percent of the amount of its capitalization grants to provide additional subsidization to eligible recipients in the form of forgiveness of principal, negative interest loans or grants or any combination of these: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Administrator shall retain $10,400,000 of the funds appropriated herein for grants for drinking water facilities and waste water treatment plants impacted by Typhoon Yutu: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the funds appropriated herein shall be used for eligible projects whose purpose is to reduce flood or fire damage risk and vulnerability or to enhance resiliency to rapid hydrologic change or natural disaster at treatment works as defined by section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act or any eligible facilities under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act, and for other eligible tasks at such treatment works or facilities necessary to further such purposes: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency may retain up to $1,000,000 of the funds appropriated herein for management and oversight: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></p>
<p>In addition, for an additional amount for “State and Tribal Assistance Grants”, $500,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $261,000,000 shall be for capitalization grants for the Clean Water State Revolving Funds under title VI of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and of which $239,000,000 shall be for capitalization grants under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That notwithstanding section 604(a) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and section 1452(a)(1)(D) of the Safe Drinking Water Act, funds appropriated herein shall be provided to States or Territories in EPA Regions 2, 4, and 6 in amounts determined by the Administrator for wastewater and drinking water treatment works and facilities impacted by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, for Region 2, such funds allocated from funds appropriated herein shall not be subject to the matching or cost share requirements of sections 602(b)(2), 602(b)(3) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act nor the matching requirements of section 1452(e) of the Safe Drinking Water Act: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, for Region 2, notwithstanding the requirements of section 603(i) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and section 1452(d) of the Safe Drinking Water Act, each State and Territory shall use the full amount of its capitalization grants allocated from funds appropriated herein to provide additional subsidization to eligible recipients in the form of forgiveness of principal, negative interest loans or grants or any combination of these: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, for Regions 4 and 6, notwithstanding the requirements of section 603(i) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and section 1452(d) of the Safe Drinking Water Act, for the funds allocated, each State shall use not less than 20 percent but not more than 30 percent amount of its capitalization grants allocated from funds appropriated herein to provide additional subsidization to eligible recipients in the form of forgiveness of principal, negative interest loans or grants or any combination of these: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Administrator shall retain $74,600,000 of the funds appropriated herein for grants to any State or territory that has not established a water pollution control revolving fund pursuant to title VI of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act or section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act for drinking water facilities and waste water treatment plants impacted by Hurricanes Irma and Maria: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the funds appropriated herein shall only be used for eligible projects whose purpose is to reduce flood damage risk and vulnerability or to enhance resiliency to rapid hydrologic change or a natural disaster at treatment works as defined by section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act or any eligible facilities under section 1452 of the Safe Drinking Water Act, and for other eligible tasks at such treatment works or facilities necessary to further such purposes: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, for Region 2, notwithstanding section 603(d)(2) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and section 1452(f)(2) of the Safe Drinking Water Act, funds allocated from funds appropriated herein may be used to make loans or to buy, refinance or restructure the debt obligations of eligible recipients only where such debt was incurred on or after September 20, 2017: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency may retain up to $1,000,000 of the funds appropriated herein for management and oversight: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></p></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H81933E07E99F4F89A2B76A56AF4ECA88"><heading>RELATED AGENCIES</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H4D9677D96B0641B3A90E19267D04BF94"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H89FFF5C0E3A64F29AC6E5B97E705AEB3"><heading>Forest Service</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H0BAD0D9BE69A47D594714E66ED533B6C"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">forest and rangeland research</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Forest and Rangeland Research” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, and the calendar year 2018 wildfires, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended for the forest inventory and analysis program: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H66576755332644888A9FE9F4555DAF90"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">state and private forestry</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “State and Private Forestry” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, and the calendar year 2018 wildfires, $12,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H0142F324FDE148B3B39E553BB902BCBB"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">national forest system</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “National Forest System” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, and the calendar year 2018 wildfires, $84,960,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That of this amount $21,000,000 shall be used for hazardous fuels management activities: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H228521943D934A2C9E7B1028798397CC"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">capital improvement and maintenance</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Capital Improvement and Maintenance” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, and the calendar year 2018 wildfires, $36,040,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H25F1931ED98C4F689B3963F70D8D5C5D"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">wildland fire management</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H54A3A12A96784F27A6624153B797BBA8"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfer of funds)</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Wildland Fire Management”, $720,271,000, to remain available through September 30, 2022, for urgent wildland fire suppression operations: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such funds shall be solely available to be transferred to and merged with other appropriations accounts from which funds were previously transferred for wildland fire suppression in fiscal year 2018 to fully repay those amounts: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H7F401738E5C94FE098E58818A0FC5F83"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H3A792C2E75D94645B8CB7C531BB1A54B"><heading>National Institutes of Health</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HA2165DD83E45451D986A8CD390A85213"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">national institute of environmental health sciences</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences” for necessary expenses in carrying out activities set forth in section 311(a) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9660/a">42 U.S.C. 9660(a)</ref>) and section 126(g) of the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 related to the consequences of major disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>) in 2018, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="HE48BE6B474554279B810DAA725DAC662"><heading>GENERAL PROVISION—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVI/s601" id="H81DB09274D1641B7A1CB750668214D03"><num value="601"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 601. </inline></num><content class="inline">Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the agencies receiving funds appropriated by this title shall provide a detailed operating plan of anticipated uses of funds made available in this title by State and Territory, and by program, project, and activity, to the Committees on Appropriations: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That no such funds shall be obligated before the operating plans are provided to the Committees: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such plans shall be updated, including obligations to date, and submitted to the Committees on Appropriations every 60 days until all such funds are expended.</proviso></content></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII" id="H3333F21845CF4A5F853F0EC78F02D6CE" styleType="appropriations"><num value="VII">TITLE VII</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF LABOR</heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H6E2A151FA3E0421BAE1BAC1C8A71E72E"><heading>Employment and Training Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H114FCE8679754504AC96BF840428A1C1"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">training and employment services</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HBB50D6F484B944D497A832C44503948A"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfer of funds)</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Training and Employment Services”, $50,000,000, for the dislocated workers assistance national reserve for necessary expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, wildfires occurring in calendar year 2018, and tornadoes and floods occurring in calendar year 2019, to remain available through September 30, 2020: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of Labor may transfer up to $1,000,000 of such funds to any other Department of Labor account for reconstruction and recovery needs, including worker protection activities: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That these sums may be used to replace grant funds previously obligated to the impacted areas: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That of the amount provided, up to $500,000, to remain available until expended, shall be transferred to “Office of Inspector General” for oversight of activities responding to such consequences: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H8CEFC23B2D3E4668982B86C6BEECC9FB"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H362EEA90DE9C470B9B846EA4556A71A4"><heading>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H730F666C64DF4211BD116A18A54E7E68"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">health surveillance and program support</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Health Surveillance and Program Support”, $30,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, for grants, contracts and cooperative agreements for behavioral health treatment, crisis counseling, and other related helplines, and for other similar programs to provide support to individuals impacted by Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, wildfires occurring in 2018, and tornadoes and floods occurring in calendar year 2019 in those areas for which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref> and 5191): <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HC0A3DDFCFBA645DD8E3D3FCF83B4B9F9"><heading>Administration for Children and Families</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H57636C89AEA041AFABA8C1FAEEEA87F5"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">social services block grant</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Social Services Block Grant”, $250,000,000, which shall remain available through September 30, 2020, for necessary expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, wildfires occurring in 2018, and tornadoes and floods occurring in calendar year 2019 in those areas for which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref> and 5191): <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That notwithstanding section 2002 of the Social Security Act, the distribution of such amount shall be limited to States directly affected by these events: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the time limits in section 2002(c) of the Social Security Act shall not apply to funds appropriated in this paragraph that are used for renovation, repair or construction: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph are in addition to the entitlement grants authorized by section 2002(a)(1) of the Social Security Act and shall not be available for such entitlement grants: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That in addition to other uses permitted by title XX of the Social Security Act, funds appropriated in this paragraph may be used for health services (including mental health services), and for costs of renovating, repairing, and construction of health care facilities (including mental health facilities), child care centers, and other social services facilities: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That of the amount provided, up to $1,000,000, to remain available until expended, shall be transferred to “Office of the Secretary—Office of Inspector General” for oversight of activities responding to such hurricanes, typhoons, wildfires, tornadoes, and floods: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph shall not be available for costs that are reimbursed by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, under a contract for insurance, or by self-insurance: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That up to $3,000,000 may be used to supplement amounts available for the necessary expenses of administering subtitle A of title XX of the Social Security Act: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HB0E6D9AED72243B4B9CEA6721963E2B6"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">children and families services programs</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Children and Families Services Programs”, $60,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2021, for Head Start programs, including making payments under the Head Start Act, for necessary expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, wildfires occurring in 2018, and tornadoes and floods occurring in calendar year 2019 in those areas for which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref> and 5191): <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That none of the funds appropriated in this paragraph shall be included in the calculation of the “base grant” in subsequent fiscal years, as such term is defined in sections 640(a)(7)(A), 641A(h)(1)(B), or 645(d)(3) of the Head Start Act: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph are not subject to the allocation requirements of section 640(a) of the Head Start Act: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph shall not be available for costs that are reimbursed by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, under a contract for insurance, or by self-insurance: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That up to $2,000,000 shall be available for Federal administrative expenses: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H1602AF7C1127482DB916E5F9D5E043CC"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H8A2C4104C41542A491E74AD074BC28DC"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">hurricane education recovery</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HCD1528A58099465D92CE626787F0EF37"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfer of funds)</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Hurricane Education Recovery” for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael, Typhoon Mangkhut, Super Typhoon Yutu, the wildfires, earthquakes, and volcanic eruptions occurring in calendar year 2018, and tornadoes and floods occurring in calendar year 2019 in those areas for which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref> and 5191) (referred to under this heading as a “covered disaster or emergency”), $165,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2019: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such assistance may be provided through any of the programs authorized under this heading in title VIII of subdivision 1 of <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dB">division B of Public Law 115–123</ref> (as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</ref>), as determined by the Secretary of Education, and subject to the terms and conditions that applied to those programs, except that references to dates and school years in <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref> shall be deemed to be the corresponding dates and school years for the covered disaster or emergency: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of Education may determine the amounts to be used for each such program and shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate of these amounts not later than 7 days prior to obligation: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That $2,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading, to remain available until expended, shall be transferred to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Education for oversight of activities supported with funds appropriated under this heading, and up to $1,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading shall be for program administration: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H59033146D9394F429F4A639036406DCC"><heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701" id="HA286E56F41204AAAAB89A5E7C6C72BFB"><num value="701"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 701. </inline></num><subsection role="instruction" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a" id="HBD4027DAAE3F49B08DEA7FEE27167113" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><chapeau>Section 1108(g)(5) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1308/g/5">42 U.S.C. 1308(g)(5)</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction>—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/1" id="H2368F8A3F46A479CA94ADF0B2CDBAB77" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>in subparagraph (A), by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and (E)</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>(E), and (F)</quotedText>”;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/2" id="H1865B3DACDED45A08D9A6E5BAEE655E1" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>in subparagraph (C), in the matter preceding clause (i), by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and (E)</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and (F)</quotedText>”;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/3" id="H87BC5A30B4634AD5874590575F34B9DD" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="redesignate">redesignating</amendingAction> subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F);</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/4" id="H350B6C52BC344791AAAE1678D18961D7" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> after subparagraph (D), the following:<quotedContent id="H685A8E04C65E4A00868DFA74BA477BBC" styleType="OLC">
<subparagraph id="HCA5254CE81F04ABAAEBA3E60A0B6070D" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E) </num><content>Subject to subparagraph (F), for the period beginning January 1, 2019, and ending September 30, 2019, the amount of the increase otherwise provided under subparagraph (A) for the Northern Mariana Islands shall be further increased by $36,000,000.”; and</content></subparagraph></quotedContent></content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/5" id="H5F3B99F8473943C9950B331B6346ABF2" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><chapeau>in subparagraph (F) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/5/A" id="H640567DC78B341E2A15DE9B65E2D05C8" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>title XIX, during</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> <quotedContent>“title XIX—
<clause id="HECF07E32AAF14B01A414B151B40608EB" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i) </num><content>during”;</content></clause></quotedContent></content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/5/B" id="H85DEFEAFC32D48CA964EDCF1D9B978A6" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and (D)</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>, (D), and (E)</quotedText>”;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/5/C" id="HBB0BBBC5B85E43629D57797EFD367F03" class="indent2"><num value="C">(C) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and the Virgin Islands</quotedText>” each place it appears and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands</quotedText>”;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/5/D" id="H670FA80461B44426BC460A4A8CCF7EC8" class="indent2"><num value="D">(D) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> the period at the end and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>; and</quotedText>”; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/a/5/E" id="H7638B71796A9429D8E54C17270466AFF" class="indent2"><num value="E">(E) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="add">adding</amendingAction> at the end the following:<quotedContent id="H2F2C7BF26986420684C94D4977484079" styleType="OLC">
<clause id="HC88C98150CFC47B8911E9C5ABE9BCFC8" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii) </num><content>for the period beginning January 1, 2019, and ending September 30, 2019, with respect to payments to Guam and American Samoa from the additional funds provided under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall increase the Federal medical assistance percentage or other rate that would otherwise apply to such payments to 100 percent.”.</content></clause></quotedContent></content></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s701/b" id="HBB54719E141F4FCDBC0B8FA13B7F852E" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><content>The amounts provided by the amendments made by subsection (a) are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s702" id="HC338635DFBB54B2F8018F6C8211727BE"><num value="702"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 702. </inline></num><content class="inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education shall provide a detailed spend plan of anticipated uses of funds made available in this title, including estimated personnel and administrative costs, to the Committees on Appropriations: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such plans shall be updated and submitted to the Committees on Appropriations every 60 days until all funds are expended or expire.</proviso></content></section>
<section role="instruction" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703" id="H03C468C1A2724D6E867934398094245C"><num value="703"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 703. </inline></num><chapeau class="inline">The second proviso under the heading “<headingText>Hurricane Education Recovery</headingText>” under the heading “<headingText>Department of Education</headingText>” under title VIII of subdivision 1 of division B of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/132/95">132 Stat. 95</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction>—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703/1" id="H5B4CCA0D079648FE9EA75A8BDF7B4762" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><chapeau>in paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703/1/A" id="H95A1468CE54145E384A3B76FF69FB977" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>in subparagraph (I), by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and</quotedText>” after the semicolon; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703/1/B" id="H1EC8D94FB0F240F79C571BB6779DDCBD" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="add">adding</amendingAction> at the end the following:<quotedContent id="HA1A45371B7774423BFB1019D7782E60F" styleType="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H058A2D2706734652B99CE26D7002AE63" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K) </num><content>assistance provided to an eligible entity under this heading, including assistance provided to an eligible entity before the date of enactment of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2019, may be used by the eligible entity for a purpose described in section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster and Relief Emergency Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</ref>), notwithstanding <ref href="/us/pl/109/148/dB/tIV/s102/e/3">section 102(e)(3) of title IV of division B of Public Law 109–148</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/119/2794">119 Stat. 2794</ref>), if the eligible entity will receive funds for that purpose under such section 406; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5D7F987A7AC94A31B16DF8A9111D3DE1" class="indent2"><num value="L">“(L) </num><content>any duplicative Federal assistance provided under this heading to an eligible entity may be retained by the entity and used for other activities to restart school operations in accordance with this paragraph;”;</content></subparagraph></quotedContent></content></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703/2" id="HB443157AD1BA4B21B2C6413C98658624" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>in paragraph (9), by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>and</quotedText>” after the semicolon;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703/3" id="HCFEF1314C5F6459ABFC3314F1FDB538E" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="redesignate">redesignating</amendingAction> paragraph (10) as paragraph (11); and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVII/s703/4" id="HCB29816D2A154DF69D29CF34BEC0D865" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>by <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> after paragraph (9) the following:<quotedContent id="H7671D3C7462F43F3B6D0239D68469EF3" styleType="OLC">
<paragraph id="H1C904E75D40745CEAB452909334A8D6F" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10) </num><content>amounts available under paragraph (4) that exceed the amount required to meet the need for such funds as determined by the Secretary as of December 31, 2018, shall be available to carry out paragraph (3); and”:</content></paragraph></quotedContent></content></paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0"> <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That amounts repurposed pursuant to this section that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></continuation></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tVIII" id="H035FB810048047C79F10BAE08ACFC21E" styleType="appropriations"><num value="VIII">TITLE VIII</num><heading>LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H03A3EAF97AF443C8817F4E77B85A42D2"><heading>Government Accountability Office</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HD7AADBF005A742C3B9D5A588A8DAA2E9"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">salaries and expenses</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Salaries and Expenses”, $10,000,000, to remain available until expended, for audits and investigations related to Hurricanes Florence, Lane, and Michael, Typhoons Yutu and Mangkhut, the calendar year 2018 wildfires, earthquakes, and volcano eruptions, and other disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>): <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Government Accountability Office shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a spend plan specifying funding estimates for audits and investigations of any such declared disasters occurring in 2018 and identifying funding estimates or carryover balances, if any, that may be available for audits and investigations of any other such declared disasters: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tIX" id="H6FF395862F8840C69636EA356661937D" styleType="appropriations"><num value="IX">TITLE IX</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HDB2BF6BF7E3D47FD8805439E0C5943A7"><heading>Military Construction, Navy and Marine Corps</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Military Construction, Navy and Marine Corps”, $115,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023, for planning and design related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael on Navy and Marine Corps installations: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That none of the funds shall be available for obligation until the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate receive a master plan for the installations and a form 1391 for each specific project: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, not later than 60 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Navy, or his designee, shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2808">section 2808 of title 10, United States Code</ref>, or any other provision of law, funds made available under this heading may only be used for the purposes specifically described under this heading.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H4B84EF79C163446FB2BFDAF61A9C2C7B"><heading>Military Construction, Air Force</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Military Construction, Air Force”, $700,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023, for planning and design, and construction expenses related to the consequences of Hurricane Michael: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That none of the funds shall be available for obligation until the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate receive a basing plan and future mission requirements for installations significantly damaged by Hurricane Michael: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, not later than 60 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Air Force, or his designee, shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2808">section 2808 of title 10, United States Code</ref>, or any other provision of law, funds made available under this heading may only be used for the purposes specifically described under this heading.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HB38830F01BDA4F47B7C024B7C8A82F2B"><heading>Military Construction, Army National Guard</heading><content>For an additional amount for “Military Construction, Army National Guard”, $42,400,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That none of the funds shall be available for obligation until the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate receive form 1391 for each specific request: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, not later than 60 days after enactment of this Act, the Director of the Army National Guard, or his designee, shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such funds may be obligated or expended for planning and design and military construction projects not otherwise authorized by law: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2808">section 2808 of title 10, United States Code</ref>, or any other provision of law, funds made available under this heading may only be used for the purposes specifically described under this heading.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H6D6B5E5EA2E74FA98221C832230CD216"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS </heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HAF87969863FA4FAF8999E09885A7EB82"><heading>Veterans Health Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H4DE69E1B4E514BEEA1921FC2FD03DD61"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">medical facilities</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H0662D63DE02B4D5380A739D56E863C77"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfer of funds)</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HB6353157D0B744B29836F73F14AFA75F"><content>For an additional amount for “Medical Facilities”, $3,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael and Typhoons Mangkhut and Yutu: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, upon determination that such action is necessary to address needs as a result of the consequences of Hurricanes Florence and Michael and Typhoons Mangkhut and Yutu, may transfer such funds to any discretionary account of the Department of Veterans Affairs: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That before a transfer may take place, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit notice thereof to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That none of these funds shall be available for obligation until the Secretary of Veterans Affairs submits to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tX" id="H61EA32B1777B47F6AD074DA8108A3A8D" styleType="appropriations"><num value="X">TITLE X</num><heading>DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION </heading><appropriations level="intermediate" id="HC4B2F40661C4418F833153E441CF4804"><heading>Federal Transit Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H46EA9819205141DB9C0EF8510D3E0D48"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">public transportation emergency relief program</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for the “Public Transportation Emergency Relief Program” as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s5324">section 5324 of title 49, United States Code</ref>, $10,542,000 to remain available until expended, for transit systems affected by major declared disasters occurring in calendar year 2018: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That not more than three-quarters of 1 percent of the funds for public transportation emergency relief shall be available for administrative expenses and ongoing program management oversight as authorized under sections 5334 and 5338(f)(2) of such title and shall be in addition to any other appropriations for such purpose: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H62D60C6E00B74E08AA5E1DC1F9DBB2EB"><heading>Federal Aviation Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H74886DBA58704DD8A1BAAB5C2B743E35"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">operations</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H1BB16C607213424290486D80096939EC"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(airport and airway trust fund)</inline></heading><content>Of the amounts made available for “Federal Aviation Administration—Operations” in division B of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>), up to $18,000,000 shall also be available for necessary expenses related to the consequences of major declared disasters occurring in calendar year 2018: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That amounts repurposed under this heading that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H2362852A80A94309A98174215E243A06"><heading>Federal Highway Administration</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H4F3E419D090F4FBEBEE5EBDDF35906F0"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">emergency relief program</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for the Emergency Relief Program as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t23/s125">section 125 of title 23, United States Code</ref>, $1,650,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="HB9E27794B7D14C5388057F15D9FD32E8"><heading>DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="intermediate" id="H3A50C7318AA84E72A62BE2A723A97078"><heading>Community Planning and Development</heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="H01FDED8F952045ED8EE883DC55AFEA63"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">community development fund</inline></heading></appropriations><appropriations level="small" id="HE2E46860CFD84CE5816B3CDBA2C35B47"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfers of funds)</inline></heading><content>For an additional amount for “Community Development Fund”, $2,210,000,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses for activities authorized under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</ref>) related to disaster relief, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation in the most impacted and distressed areas resulting from a major disaster that occurred in 2018 or 2019 (except as otherwise provided under this heading) pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>): <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That funds shall be awarded directly to the State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974) at the discretion of the Secretary: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That of the amounts made available under this heading $150,000,000 shall be allocated to meet unmet needs for restoration of infrastructure for grantees that received allocations for disasters that occurred in 2017 (excluding grantees that received allocations related to disasters specified in section 501(a) of title V of this Act) under this heading of <ref href="/us/pl/115/56/dB">division B of Public Law 115–56</ref> and title XI of subdivision 1 of <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dB">division B of Public Law 115–123</ref>: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That of the amounts provided in the previous proviso, the Secretary’s determination of unmet needs for restoration of infrastructure shall not take into account mitigation-specific allocations: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That any funds made available under this heading and under the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref> that remain available, after the funds under such headings have been allocated for necessary expenses for activities authorized under such headings, shall be allocated to grantees receiving awards for disasters that occurred in 2018 or 2019, for mitigation activities in the most impacted and distressed areas resulting from a major disaster that occurred in 2018 or 2019: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That allocations under the previous proviso shall be made in the same proportion that the amount of funds each grantee received or will receive under this heading for unmet needs related to disasters that occurred in 2018 or 2019 and the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dI">division I of Public Law 115–254</ref> bears to the amount of all funds provided to all grantees that received allocations for disasters that occurred in 2018 or 2019: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That of the amounts made available under the text preceding the first proviso under this heading and under the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref>, the Secretary shall allocate to all such grantees an aggregate amount not less than 33 percent of the sum of such amounts of funds within 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act based on the best available data, and shall allocate no less than 100 percent of such funds by no later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall not prohibit the use of funds made available under this heading and the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref> for non-Federal share as authorized by section 105(a)(9) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5305/a/9">42 U.S.C. 5305(a)(9)</ref>): </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, grantees may establish grant programs to assist small businesses for working capital purposes to aid in recovery: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That as a condition of making any grant, the Secretary shall certify in advance that such grantee has in place proficient financial controls and procurement processes and has established adequate procedures to prevent any duplication of benefits as defined by section 312 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5155">42 U.S.C. 5155</ref>), to ensure timely expenditure of funds, to maintain comprehensive websites regarding all disaster recovery activities assisted with these funds, and to detect and prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That with respect to any such duplication of benefits, the Secretary shall act in accordance with <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1210">section 1210 of Public Law 115–254</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/132/3442">132 Stat. 3442</ref>) and section 312 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5155">42 U.S.C. 5155</ref>): </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall require grantees to maintain on a public website information containing common reporting criteria established by the Department that permits individuals and entities awaiting assistance and the general public to see how all grant funds are used, including copies of all relevant procurement documents, grantee administrative contracts and details of ongoing procurement processes, as determined by the Secretary: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That prior to the obligation of funds a grantee shall submit a plan to the Secretary for approval detailing the proposed use of all funds, including criteria for eligibility and how the use of these funds will address long-term recovery and restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation in the most impacted and distressed areas: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such funds may not be used for activities reimbursed by, or for which funds have been made available by, the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the Army Corps of Engineers, in excess of the authorized amount of the project or its components: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That funds allocated under this heading shall not be considered relevant to the non-disaster formula allocations made pursuant to section 106 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5306">42 U.S.C. 5306</ref>): </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That a State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe may use up to 5 percent of its allocation for administrative costs: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the first proviso under this heading in the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dI">division I of Public Law 115–254</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>State or unit of general local government</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</ref>))</quotedText>”: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the sixth proviso under this heading in the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dI">division I of Public Law 115–254</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> “<quotedText>State or subdivision thereof</quotedText>” and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> “<quotedText>State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</ref>))</quotedText>”: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That in administering the funds under this heading, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may waive, or specify alternative requirements for, any provision of any statute or regulation that the Secretary administers in connection with the obligation by the Secretary or the use by the recipient of these funds (except for requirements related to fair housing, nondiscrimination, labor standards, and the environment), if the Secretary finds that good cause exists for the waiver or alternative requirement and such waiver or alternative requirement would not be inconsistent with the overall purpose of title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, notwithstanding the preceding proviso, recipients of funds provided under this heading that use such funds to supplement Federal assistance provided under section 402, 403, 404, 406, 407, 408(c)(4), or 502 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</ref>) may adopt, without review or public comment, any environmental review, approval, or permit performed by a Federal agency, and such adoption shall satisfy the responsibilities of the recipient with respect to such environmental review, approval or permit: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That, notwithstanding section 104(g)(2) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5304/g/2">42 U.S.C. 5304(g)(2)</ref>), the Secretary may, upon receipt of a request for release of funds and certification, immediately approve the release of funds for an activity or project assisted under this heading if the recipient has adopted an environmental review, approval or permit under the preceding proviso or the activity or project is categorically excluded from review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321/etseq">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</ref>): </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the Secretary shall publish via notice in the Federal Register any waiver, or alternative requirement, to any statute or regulation that the Secretary administers pursuant to title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 no later than 5 days before the effective date of such waiver or alternative requirement: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, up to $5,000,000 shall be made available for capacity building and technical assistance, including assistance on contracting and procurement processes, to support States, units of general local government, or Indian tribes (and their subrecipients) that receive allocations pursuant to this heading, received disaster recovery allocations under the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref>, or may receive similar allocations for disaster recovery in future appropriations Acts: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That of the amounts made available under this heading and under the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref>, up to $2,500,000 shall be transferred, in aggregate, to “<quotedText>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Program Office Salaries and Expenses—Community Planning and Development</quotedText>” for necessary costs, including information technology costs, of administering and overseeing the obligation and expenditure of amounts under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That the amount specified in the preceding proviso shall be combined with funds appropriated under the same heading and for the same purpose in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref> and the aggregate of such amounts shall be available for any of the same such purposes specified under this heading or the same heading in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref> without limitation: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That amounts repurposed under this heading that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations><appropriations level="major" id="H69AECDCF3904425C979D2B9022B46B7B"><heading>GENERAL PROVISION—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tX/s1001" id="HB425C73A574E48E0AF3800C7CB835C6A"><num value="1001"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1001. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tX/s1001/a" id="HF19456FCC0AD4D0E80A62815F2488D2A" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><content>Amounts previously made available for activities authorized under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</ref>) related to disaster relief, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation in the most impacted and distressed areas resulting from a major disaster, including funds provided under <ref href="/us/pl/114/223/dC/s145">section 145 of division C of Public Law 114–223</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/114/223/dC/s192">section 192 of division C of Public Law 114–223</ref> (as added by <ref href="/us/pl/114/254/dA/s101/3">section 101(3) of division A of Public Law 114–254</ref>), <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dK/s421">section 421 of division K of Public Law 115–31</ref>, and any mitigation funding provided under the heading “<headingText>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Community Development Fund</headingText>” of <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>, that were allocated in response to Hurricane Matthew, may be used interchangeably and without limitation for the same activities in the most impacted and distressed areas related to Hurricane Florence. In addition, any funds provided under the heading “<headingText>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Community Development Fund</headingText>” in this Act or in <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dI">division I of Public Law 115–254</ref> that are allocated in response to Hurricane Florence may be used interchangeably and without limitation for the same activities in the most impacted and distressed areas related to Hurricane Matthew. Until HUD publishes the Federal Register Notice implementing this provision, grantees may submit for HUD approval revised plans for the use of funds related to Hurricane Matthew that expand the eligible beneficiaries of existing programs contained in such previously approved plans to include those impacted by Hurricane Florence. Approval of any such revised plans shall include the execution of revised grant terms and conditions as necessary. Once the implementing Notice is published, any additional action plan revisions shall follow the requirements contained therein.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tX/s1001/b" id="HC91A7F0C7DEE429CAC2CDE3EC0DD236C" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><content>Amounts made available for administrative costs for activities authorized under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301/etseq">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</ref>) related to disaster relief, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation in the most impacted and distressed areas under this Act or any future Act, and amounts previously provided under <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dL/s420">section 420 of division L of Public Law 114–113</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/114/223/dC/s145">section 145 of division C of Public Law 114–223</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/114/223/dC/s192">section 192 of division C of Public Law 114–223</ref> (as added by <ref href="/us/pl/114/254/dA/s101/3">section 101(3) of division A of Public Law 114–254</ref>), <ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dK/s421">section 421 of division K of Public Law 115–31</ref>, and under the heading “<headingText>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Community Development Fund</headingText>” of <ref href="/us/pl/115/56/dB">division B of Public Law 115–56</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Public Law 115–254</ref>, shall be available for eligible administrative costs of the grantee related to any disaster relief funding identified in this subsection without regard to the particular disaster appropriation from which such funds originated.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tX/s1001/c" id="HA80B2018B6834616898F9CCCB8A8B506" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><content>The additional uses pursuant to this section for amounts that were previously designated by the Congress, respectively, as an emergency requirement or as being for disaster relief pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></subsection></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI" id="H7155020B68874871A360639727B3CC6E" styleType="appropriations"><num value="XI">TITLE XI</num><heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS ACT</heading>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1101" id="HC93BF6FFDB634038A9C16760C59E5293"><num value="1101"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1101. </inline></num><content class="inline">Each amount appropriated or made available by this Act is in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1102" id="H148BED5494BC4DC8B84FD15362810F7E"><num value="1102"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1102. </inline></num><content class="inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1103" id="H8B3A265314444E18938E5569F1A6CBB4"><num value="1103"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1103. </inline></num><content class="inline">Unless otherwise provided for by this Act, the additional amounts appropriated by this division to appropriations accounts shall be available under the authorities and conditions applicable to such appropriations accounts for fiscal year 2019.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1104" id="H22D244F3E2E644078D6FE8068F2D0965"><num value="1104"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1104. </inline></num><content class="inline">Each amount designated in this Act by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 shall be available (or rescinded or transferred, if applicable) only if the President subsequently so designates all such amounts and transmits such designations to the Congress.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1105" id="H9DBEE9CC53874BFBA5C276207A6DB3F1"><num value="1105"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1105. </inline></num><content class="inline">Any amount appropriated by this Act designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 and subsequently so designated by the President, and transferred pursuant to transfer authorities provided by this division shall retain such designation.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1106" id="HC73CFDC4C6CC4D3FB0892E0A52AE7DC6"><num value="1106"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 1106. </inline></num><chapeau class="inline">Of all amounts made available for mitigation activities under the heading “<headingText>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Development Fund</headingText>” in <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the allocations to all eligible grantees, and the necessary administrative requirements applicable to such allocations within 90 days after enactment of this Act:</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1106/1" id="H7DACDE4BB8B64CB082B97E586972D07E" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>For any plans or amendments addressing the use of any funds provided under <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref> and received by the Secretary prior to December 22, 2018, the Secretary shall review pending amendments within 15 days of enactment of this Act and pending plans within 30 days of enactment of this Act.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/2157/tXI/s1106/2" id="HAC607AD45C5948F7A77457A46E16FE27" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>After the date of this Act, the Secretary may not apply the statutory waiver or alternative requirement authority provided by <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref> to extend or otherwise alter existing statutory and regulatory provisions governing the timeline for review of required grantee plans.</content></paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0"> <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That the amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: </proviso><proviso><i> Provided further</i>, That amounts repurposed under this heading that were previously designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></continuation></section>
<section id="H5C98098A2B3B4B71BEFED5AEB7E1D950" role="undesignated-section"><content>This Act may be cited as the “<shortTitle role="act">Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2019</shortTitle>”.</content></section></title></main><endMarker>○</endMarker></bill>