<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><bill xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:uslm="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm uslm-2.1.0.xsd" xml:lang="en" id="H60E28E426731497D9784D6D60D589617"><!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.--> <meta>
<dc:title>116 HR 3401 RDS: Making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:type>House Bill</dc:type>
<docNumber>3401</docNumber>
<citableAs>116 HR 3401 RDS</citableAs>
<citableAs>116hr3401rds</citableAs>
<citableAs>116 H. R. 3401 RDS</citableAs>
<docStage>Received in Senate</docStage>
<currentChamber>SENATE</currentChamber>
<dc:creator>United States Senate</dc:creator>
<processedBy>GPO XPub Bill to USLM Generator, version 0.5 + manual changes</processedBy>
<processedDate>2024-09-09</processedDate>
<dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<congress>116</congress>
<session>1</session>
<publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta>
<preface>
<slugLine> HR 3401 RDS</slugLine>
<distributionCode display="yes">II</distributionCode>
<congress value="116">116th CONGRESS</congress>
<session value="1">1st Session</session>
<dc:type>H. R. </dc:type>
<docNumber>3401</docNumber>
<currentChamber value="SENATE">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</currentChamber>
<action><date date="2019-06-26"><inline class="smallCaps">June </inline>26, 2019</date><actionDescription>Received</actionDescription></action></preface>
<main id="H7C94772371C74E3AB2F71A3D220C21A5" styleType="appropriations" changed="notChanged"><longTitle><docTitle>AN ACT</docTitle><officialTitle>Making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</officialTitle></longTitle><enactingFormula><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, </i></enactingFormula><section id="H80BE1EF742114BCEB5C367BFF4BF7989" class="inline"><content class="inline"> That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated,<br verticalSpace="nextPage"/> for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes, namely:</content></section>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tI" id="H76E45FA5B9D84FEC96E25270BBE7501A"><num value="I">TITLE I</num><heading class="block">DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</heading>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="HC9CA97D365204DEBAF3FB5C684DC2FAB"><heading>General Administration</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="HAEA6C473013F4E6C824AB43846EAE64A"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">executive office for immigration review</inline></heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="H8BABBF2AD2274E4BA3427A738E8AD71B"><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Executive Office for Immigration Review”, $17,000,000 to be used only for services and activities provided by the Legal Access Programs, of which not less than $2,000,000 shall be for the continued operation of the Immigration Court Helpdesk Program: <proviso><i> Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="H8A4EA83E1D18431FB2C4EDBC1AF10DEC"><heading>United States Marshals Service</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="HAB369960CAD24F4BA367C0580D2CB901"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">federal prisoner detention</inline></heading><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Federal Prisoner Detention”, $155,000,000 to be used only for the necessary expenses related to United States prisoners in the custody of the United States Marshals Service as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s4013">section 4013 of title 18, United States Code</ref>: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII" id="HF23C89ABBF054D1DBBCF72CCB26B3ABF"><num value="II">TITLE II</num><heading class="block">DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY</heading>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="H2B67CD92886B4C59A2EA5346F46F3FFB"><heading>Security, Enforcement, and Border Protection</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="H6284D1BC079E4E10BE5FFCACC4ED9225"><heading>U.S. Customs and Border Protection</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="HE23CA0DA6B4749F99907D7BB74BD79A4"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">operations and support</inline></heading><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Operations and Support” for necessary expenses to respond to the significant rise in aliens at the southwest border and related activities, $1,217,931,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020; of which $702,500,000 is for migrant processing facilities; of which $92,000,000 is for consumables; of which $19,950,000 is for medical assets and high risk support; of which $8,000,000 is for Federal Protective Service support; of which $35,000,000 is for transportation; of which $90,636,000 is for temporary duty and overtime costs; of which $19,845,000 is for reimbursements for temporary duty and overtime costs; and of which $50,000,000 is for mission support data systems and analysis: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="HB5DEF249E9BD4FA4B8E629FA3AAA1F9F"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">procurement, construction, and improvements</inline></heading><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Procurement, Construction, and Improvements” for migrant processing facilities, $85,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="H5D712C5CF82D4BE4879CFB25E29303BE"><heading>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="H306CE699350F4BA5A6D95CC3809D49AE"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">operations and support</inline></heading><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Operations and Support” for necessary expenses to respond to the significant rise in aliens at the southwest border and related activities, $128,238,000; of which $35,943,000 is for transportation of unaccompanied alien children; of which $11,981,000 is for detainee transportation for medical needs, court proceedings, or relocation to and from U.S. Customs and Border Protection custody; of which $5,114,000 is for reimbursements for overtime and temporary duty costs; of which $20,000,000 is for alternatives to detention; of which $45,000,000 is for detainee medical care; and of which $10,200,000 is for the Office of Professional Responsibility for background investigations and facility inspections: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="H392ABC0574DC4601A6504C55EF51E1CA"><heading>Federal Emergency Management Agency</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="HAA04BD786B44491CA5875F4014DFEDD4"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">federal assistance</inline></heading><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Federal Assistance”, $60,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, for the emergency food and shelter program under Title III of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11331/etseq">42 U.S.C. 11331 et seq.</ref>) for the purposes of providing assistance to aliens released from the custody of the Department of Homeland Security: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That notwithstanding Sections 315 and 316(b) of such Act, funds made available under this section shall be disbursed by the Emergency Food and Shelter Program National Board not later than 30 days after the date on which such funds becomes available: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the Emergency Food and Shelter Program National Board shall distribute such funds only to jurisdictions or local recipient organizations serving communities that have experienced a significant influx of such aliens: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That such funds may be used to reimburse such jurisdictions or local recipient organizations for costs incurred in providing services to such aliens on or after January 1, 2019: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations>
<appropriations level="major" id="H1F07668CA8AD42FEAD0CBCDCB8194F41"><heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s201" id="HDD62B298B41B42129EBF337177A51379"><num value="201"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 201. </inline></num><content class="inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds made available under each heading in this title shall only be used for the purposes specifically described under that heading.</content></section>
<section role="instruction" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s202" id="H371F62E4D78B465EBB24B0306B8945A0"><num value="202"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 202. </inline></num><content class="inline">Division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2019 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="add">adding</amendingAction> after section 540 the following:
<quotedContent id="H31DBCAC86E8A4F01B67B51DBF7995380" styleType="appropriations">
<section id="HC4321931C5994E149E968FE79E95D4DA"><num value="541"><inline class="smallCaps">“Sec. 541. </inline></num><subsection id="HAE80953F8BB341BAA4F9B2434C637DE1" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><chapeau>Section 831 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s391">6 U.S.C. 391</ref>) shall be applied—</chapeau>
<paragraph id="H88D1CBB558F8455B9AC04837B635564F" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1) </num><content>in subsection (a), by substituting ‘September 30, 2019,’ for ‘September 30, 2017,’; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD414E10D74924C6BAB29CCDD3A3C9199" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2) </num><content>in subsection (c)(1), by substituting ‘September 30, 2019,’ for ‘September 30, 2017’.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF95F36B57FBD4A4BAC59DCDBDCF67317" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b) </num><content>The Secretary of Homeland Security, under the authority of section 831 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s391/a">6 U.S.C. 391(a)</ref>), may carry out prototype projects under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2371b">section 2371b of title 10, United States Code</ref>, and the Secretary shall perform the functions of the Secretary of Defense as prescribed.</content></subsection>
<subsection id="HA963BBA744B74C8D9B396B9EB607B2E3" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c) </num><content>The Secretary of Homeland Security under section 831 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s391/d">6 U.S.C. 391(d)</ref>) may use the definition of nontraditional government contractor as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2371b/e">section 2371b(e) of title 10, United States Code</ref>.”</content></subsection></section></quotedContent><inline role="after-quoted-block">.</inline></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203" id="HC30771E2290248BB86CC5475FCA1707C"><num value="203"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 203. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/a" id="H92E4F2CF04184688A8DF6783E8912EAD" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><chapeau>The Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security shall establish policies and distribute written personnel guidance, as appropriate, not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act on the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/a/1" id="HFBAD03B3A3B241089F8D1D911FE443EB" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>Providing private meeting space and video teleconferencing access for individuals returned to Mexico under the Migrant Protection Protocols to consult with legal counsel, including prior to initial immigration court hearings.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/a/2" id="H150F3B34B78E4045ADA290ADAA637259" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>Efforts, in consultation with the Department of State, to address the housing, transportation, and security needs of such individuals.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/a/3" id="H9825D03BF3E14AAA93B167DAAC45A72A" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>Efforts, in consultation with the Department of Justice, to ensure that such individuals are briefed, in their primary spoken language to the greatest extent possible, on their legal rights and obligations prior to being returned to Mexico.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/a/4" id="H5BF34D4708EB4E549C4391F943DCAADA" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>Efforts, in consultation with the Department of Justice, to prioritize the immigration proceedings of such individuals.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/a/5" id="H39DDE99F18B94CFCA0C801C879A372F1" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content>The establishment of written policies defining categories of vulnerable individuals who should not be so returned.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection role="definitions" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/b" id="H13FBEEBE8CB64D27834A3A8DF9D36B3D" class="indent-1"><num value="b">(b) </num><content>For purposes of this section, the term “<term>Migrant Protection Protocols</term>” means the actions taken by the Secretary to implement the memorandum dated January 25, 2019 entitled “Policy Guidance for the Implementation of the Migrant Protection Protocols”.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s203/c" id="H3E4A601E58B44015AB15FC0DBEE28A0A" class="indent-1"><num value="c">(c) </num><content>The amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s204" id="HCB5926EF0ADE4C3083C71DD0E8463EB1"><num value="204"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 204. </inline></num><content class="inline">None of the funds provided in this Act under “U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Operations and Support” for facilities shall be available until U.S. Customs and Border Protection establishes policies (via directive, procedures, guidance, and/or memorandum) and training programs to ensure that such facilities adhere to the National Standards on Transport, Escort, Detention, and Search, published in October of 2015: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall provide a detailed report to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the House Judiciary Committee regarding the establishment and implementation of such policies and training programs.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s205" id="H0397A1E392E3413DB1068FED47F85A61"><num value="205"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 205. </inline></num><content class="inline">No later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide a report on the number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection Officers assigned to Northern Border land ports of entry and temporarily assigned to the ongoing humanitarian crisis: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That the report shall outline what resources and conditions would allow a return to northern border staffing levels that are no less than the number committed in the June 12, 2018 Department of Homeland Security Northern Border Strategy: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the report shall include the number of officers temporarily assigned to the southwest border in response to the ongoing humanitarian crisis, the number of days the officers will be away from their northern border assignment, the northern border ports from which officers are being assigned to the southwest border, and efforts being made to limit the impact on operations at each northern border land port of entry where officers have been temporarily assigned to the southwest border.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s206" id="H978E635F179D4B31A53624AC2DDF581B"><num value="206"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 206. </inline></num><content class="inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act or division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2019 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</ref>) for the Department of Homeland Security may be used to relocate to the National Targeting Center the vetting of Trusted Traveler Program applications and operations currently carried out at existing locations unless specifically authorized by a statute enacted after the date of enactment of this Act.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207" id="H0B0D11AA137D42C7B9C3C2DAF33AE236"><num value="207"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 207. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a" id="H4668E4B33D854B17847B2F402CABF389" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><chapeau>Of the additional amount provided under “U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Operations and Support”, $200,000,000 is for a multi-agency, integrated, migrant processing center pilot program for family units and unaccompanied alien children, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/1" id="H9D4B640D33CC4631AAEA65896D97D059" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>Ongoing assessment and treatment efforts for physical or mental health conditions, including development of a support plan and services for each member of a vulnerable population.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/2" id="H4EA62907ECE94434B3A9D4273A09711F" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>Assessments of child protection and welfare needs.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/3" id="H713451A9FEB140689BC0D992F2298223" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>Food, shelter, hygiene services and supplies, clothing, and activities appropriate for the non-penal, civil detention of families.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/4" id="HE22E0FAED1544508873734CDD434EDF8" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>Personnel with appropriate training on caring for families and vulnerable populations in a civil detention environment.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/5" id="H5625E84B6A4840E8B9A9FDFA41B236CE" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content>Free telephonic communication access, including support for contacting family members.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/6" id="HC3BE9609293D48018B4FD24C7615472C" class="indent1"><num value="6">(6) </num><content>Direct access to legal orientation, legal representation, and case management in private areas of the center.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/7" id="HE60886F8C6D747289B8709257A519240" class="indent1"><num value="7">(7) </num><content>Credible fear and reasonable fear interviews conducted by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services asylum officers in private areas of the center.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/8" id="HC19599BB5D044A079D4AC06F8D0ADCD4" class="indent1"><num value="8">(8) </num><content>Granting of asylum directly by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for manifestly well-founded or clearly meritorious cases.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/9" id="H445024C65AFE4A858968C4C8BB10B321" class="indent1"><num value="9">(9) </num><chapeau>For family units not found removable prior to departure from the center—</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/9/A" id="HB7EF23027C5C42CEA633D191C49A6252" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>release on own recognizance or placement in alternatives to detention with case management; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/9/B" id="H9674A37042174942B1764577736E025D" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>coordinated transport to a respite shelter or city of final destination.</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/10" id="HDDABF34AAB7141AE9850CDCE7197870F" class="indent1"><num value="10">(10) </num><content>For family units found removable prior to departure from the center, safe return planning support by an immigration case manager, including a consular visit to assist with reintegration.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/a/11" id="H1F6D70F89B0C4481A2EBA1355407384C" class="indent1"><num value="11">(11) </num><content>On-site operational support by non-governmental organizations for the identification and protection of vulnerable populations.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/b" id="H6586DFBAA30C442A906A4C20906D25A1" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><chapeau>The Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives within 24 hours of any—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/b/1" id="HEF380F4209B6407D94C84EEE4B928B5C" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>unaccompanied child placed in the pilot program whose time in Department of Homeland Security custody exceeds 72 hours; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/b/2" id="H71F72B046DAC4389AF641A394BB3E420" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>family unit placed in the pilot program whose time in such custody exceed exceeds 9 days.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s207/c" id="HFBC3C4B9C4C349EBAAD0226EDBEFE034" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><content>Prior to the obligation of the amount identified in subsection (a), but not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a plan for the implementation of the pilot program to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives which shall include a definition of vulnerable populations.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s208" id="H3C8D200F360D41499B686706D36EB5D4"><num value="208"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 208. </inline></num><chapeau class="inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish final plans, standards, and protocols to protect the health and safety of individuals in the custody of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s208/1" id="H16B99BD8DD504296961E3A5A5C85EFBF" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>standards and response protocols for medical assessments and medical emergencies;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s208/2" id="HAA41DC8CC81D4890A4D5FE600DE4D98F" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>requirements for ensuring the provision of water, appropriate nutrition, hygiene, and sanitation needs;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s208/3" id="H954C845E63FC42AB83B86C46C76B9957" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>standards for temporary holding facilities that adhere to best practices for the care of children, which shall be in compliance with the relevant recommendations in the Policy Statement of the American Academy of Pediatrics entitled, “Detention of Immigrant Children”;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s208/4" id="H7EEF2E4E83DC43EA9B09D771F20EA2F5" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>protocols for responding to surges of migrants crossing the southern border or arriving at land ports of entry; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s208/5" id="H66BAD01B6DEA42B6B75E8597F5459CD5" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content>required training for all Federal and contract personnel who interact with migrants on the care and treatment of individuals in civil detention.</content></paragraph></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tII/s209" id="H3A2ED6B992E5423D94710D0D317209FD"><num value="209"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 209. </inline></num><content class="inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the House of Representatives and the Senate a plan for ensuring access to appropriate translation services for all individuals encountered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, including an estimate of related resource requirements and the feasibility and potential benefit of these components jointly procuring such services.</content></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII" id="HE8824208DA224740A430AB46851D79C6"><num value="III">TITLE III</num><heading class="block">DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</heading>
<appropriations level="intermediate" id="HFD06F6DC0516434CAB327467DA540BB6"><heading>Administration for Children and Families</heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="H86A68D71B4E942C8888E9CEFE8B040D6"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">refugee and entrant assistance</inline></heading></appropriations>
<appropriations level="small" id="HDD87B1738AA14282BAB94B611E4949A3"><heading><inline class="smallCaps">(including transfer of funds)</inline></heading><content class="block">For an additional amount for “Refugee and Entrant Assistance” $2,881,552,000, to be merged with and available for the same period as funds appropriated in <ref href="/us/pl/115/245/dB">division B of Public Law 115–245</ref> and made available through fiscal year 2021 under this heading, and to be made available for any purpose funded under such heading in such law: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That if any part of the reprogramming described in the notification submitted by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the “Secretary”) to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate on May 16, 2019, has been executed as of the date of the enactment of this Act, such amounts provided by this Act as are necessary shall be used to reverse such reprogramming: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That of the amounts provided under this heading, the amount allocated by the Secretary for costs of leases of property that include facilities to be used as hard-sided dormitories for which the Secretary intends to seek State licensure for the care of unaccompanied alien children, and that are executed under authorities transferred to the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement (ORR) under section 462 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, shall remain available until expended: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That ORR shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate within 72 hours of conducting a formal assessment of a facility for possible lease or acquisition and within 7 days of any lease or acquisition of real property: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That not less than $866,000,000 of the amounts provided under this heading shall be used for the provision of care in licensed shelters and for expanding the supply of shelters for which State licensure will be sought, of which not less than $27,000,000 shall be available for the purposes of <amendingAction type="add">adding</amendingAction> shelter beds in State-licensed facilities in response to funding opportunity HHS–2017–ACF–ORR–ZU–1132, and of which not less than $185,000,000 shall be available for expansion grants to add beds in State-licensed facilities and open new State-licensed facilities, and for contract costs to acquire, activate, and operate facilities that include small- and medium-scale hard-sided facilities for which the Secretary intends to seek State licensure in an effort to phase out the need for shelter beds in unlicensed facilities: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That not less than $100,000,000 of the amounts provided under this heading shall be used for post-release services, child advocates, and legal services: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the amount made available for legal services in the preceding proviso shall be made available for the same purposes for which amounts were provided for such services in fiscal year 2017: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That not less than $8,000,000 of the amounts provided under this heading shall be used for the purposes of hiring additional Federal Field Specialists and for increasing case management and case coordination services, with the goal of more expeditiously placing unaccompanied alien children with sponsors and reducing the length of stay in ORR custody: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That not less than $1,000,000 of amounts provided under this heading shall be used for the purposes of hiring project officers and program monitor staff dedicated to pursuing strategic improvements to the Unaccompanied Alien Children program and for the development of a discharge rate improvement plan which shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate within 120 days of the date of enactment of this Act: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That of the amounts provided under this heading, $5,000,000 shall be transferred to “<quotedText>Office of the Secretary—Office of Inspector General</quotedText>” and shall remain available until expended for oversight of activities supported with funds appropriated under this heading: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That none of the funds made available under this heading may be transferred pursuant to the authority in <ref href="/us/pl/115/245/dB/s205">section 205 of division B of Public Law 115–245</ref>: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</proviso></content></appropriations>
<appropriations level="major" id="H751514FF89274770875485F84B9AF956"><heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS TITLE</heading></appropriations>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s301" id="H099AE84E126641C783CF2E803A995243"><num value="301"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 301. </inline></num><content class="inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (the “Secretary”) shall prioritize use of community-based residential care (including long-term and transitional foster care and small group homes) and shelter care other than large-scale institutional shelter facilities to house unaccompanied alien children in the custody of the Department of Health and Human Services. The Secretary shall prioritize State-licensed, hard-sided dormitories.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s302" id="H4A5940775088409592A15685CD8D27C9"><num value="302"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 302. </inline></num><content class="inline">Funds made available in this Act under the heading “<headingText>Department of Health and Human Services—Administration for Children and Families—Refugee and Entrant Assistance</headingText>” shall remain available for obligation only if the operational directives issued by the Office of Refugee Resettlement between December 1, 2018, and June 15, 2019, to accelerate the identification and approval of sponsors, remain in effect.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s303" id="H8666F158229849E78AFA608A09BCA0FD"><num value="303"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 303. </inline></num><content class="inline">Funds made available in this Act under the heading “<headingText>Department of Health and Human Services—Administration for Children and Families—Refugee and Entrant Assistance</headingText>” shall be subject to the authorities and conditions of section 224 of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2019 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</ref>).</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304" id="H4D77051264D74C0D81ADB3710FBA4B09"><num value="304"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 304. </inline></num><chapeau class="inline">None of the funds made available in this Act under the heading “<headingText>Department of Health and Human Services—Administration for Children and Families—Refugee and Entrant Assistance</headingText>” may be obligated to a grantee or contractor to house unaccompanied alien children (as such term is defined in section 462(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s279/g/2">6 U.S.C. 279(g)(2)</ref>)) in any facility that is not State-licensed for the care of unaccompanied alien children, except in the case that the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the “Secretary”) determines that housing unaccompanied alien children in such a facility is necessary on a temporary basis due to an influx of such children or an emergency: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That—</proviso></chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/1" id="HDC233C0287304CD2B16F7A68B557A39A" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><chapeau>the terms of the grant or contract for the operations of any such facility that remains in operation for more than six consecutive months shall require compliance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/1/A" id="HDE0A406462BD4441942B2CFE8E709DE0" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>the same requirements as licensed placements, as listed in Exhibit 1 of the Flores Settlement Agreement, regardless of the status of the underlying settlement agreement;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/1/B" id="H6EB3962B244B47908E4D35AED209ACC3" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>staffing ratios of 1 on-duty Youth Care Worker for every 8 children or youth during waking hours, 1 on-duty Youth Care Worker for every 16 children or youth during sleeping hours, and clinician ratios to children (including mental health providers) as required in grantee cooperative agreements; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/1/C" id="H2550F388DD18486F8BEEACC68CCDF579" class="indent2"><num value="C">(C) </num><content>access provided to legal services;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/2" id="HFEB4B9E1F7614CF19FA8BEDD2D9D9C98" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>the Secretary may grant a 60-day waiver for a contractor’s or grantee’s non-compliance with paragraph (1) if the Secretary certifies and provides a report to Congress on the contractor’s or grantee’s good-faith efforts and progress towards compliance and the report specifies each requirement referenced in paragraph (1) that is being waived for 60 days;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3" id="H251111FA4F0A4809AD3B69B91AB45864" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><chapeau>the Secretary shall not waive requirements for grantees or contractors to provide or arrange for the following services—</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/A" id="HA2245A66DB2F4018B9AA857DC507642A" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>proper physical care and maintenance, including suitable living accommodations, food, appropriate clothing, and personal grooming items;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/B" id="HB5632635E33843FFA5588DBE0AD40F3D" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>a complete medical examination (including screening for infectious diseases) within 48 hours of admission, unless the minor was recently examined at another facility;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/C" id="HBE137A3585454514862F24DAA526234C" class="indent2"><num value="C">(C) </num><content>appropriate routine medical and dental care;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/D" id="H674474A7BD2F476D97D43EB3E119F3E1" class="indent2"><num value="D">(D) </num><content>at least one individual counseling session per week conducted by trained social work staff with the specific objectives of reviewing a minor’s progress, establishing new short term objectives, and addressing both the developmental and crisis-related needs of each minor;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/E" id="H8703D0C1CF1D46D6A1F8F260EFC95052" class="indent2"><num value="E">(E) </num><content>educational services appropriate to the minor’s level of development, and communication skills in a structured classroom setting, Monday through Friday, which concentrates primarily on the development of basic academic competencies and secondarily on English Language Training;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/F" id="H8D1E76FFDE664B6FA3663582F987ADD5" class="indent2"><num value="F">(F) </num><content>activities according to a leisure time plan which shall include daily outdoor activity, weather permitting, at least one hour per day of large muscle activity and one hour per day of structured leisure time activities (this should not include time spent watching television). Activities should be increased to three hours on days when school is not in session;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/G" id="H4D55ADA604344527919DEFF818BF3652" class="indent2"><num value="G">(G) </num><content>whenever possible, access to religious services of the minor’s choice;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/H" id="H12C1E68BA36A46AC918B3F3DD2EC5AF5" class="indent2"><num value="H">(H) </num><content>visitation and contact with family members (regardless of their immigration status) which is structured to encourage such visitation. The staff shall respect the minor’s privacy while reasonably preventing the unauthorized release of the minor;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/I" id="H4815E409CB2B4F10BF7D84AF47569BD3" class="indent2"><num value="I">(I) </num><content>family reunification services designed to identify relatives in the United States as well as in foreign countries and assistance in obtaining legal guardianship when necessary for the release of the minor; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/3/J" id="H2D635281448E4E8C8759F8BAE8CAF5BE" class="indent2"><num value="J">(J) </num><content>legal services information regarding the availability of free legal assistance, the right to be represented by counsel at no expense to the government, the right to a deportation or exclusion hearing before an immigration judge, the right to apply for political asylum or to request voluntary departure in lieu of deportation;</content></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/4" id="HFA3352AF28D649898A31445C25D2D624" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>if the Secretary determines that a contractor or grantee is not in compliance with any of the requirements set forth in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall not permit such contractor or grantee to continue to provide services beyond a reasonable period, not to exceed 60 days, needed to award a contract or grant to a new service provider, and the incumbent contractor or grantee shall not be eligible to compete for the new contract or grant;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/5" id="H3F98F6CAC41A47668C18A6564D5D698E" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content>not more than three consecutive waivers under paragraph (2) may be granted to a contractor or grantee with respect to a specific facility;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/6" id="H6E9170491D554D44A9BDBD3153F65AC7" class="indent1"><num value="6">(6) </num><content>ORR shall ensure full adherence to the monitoring requirements set forth in section 5.5 of its Policies and Procedures Guide as of June 15, 2019;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/7" id="HFCA54BA48FD94550AE862DA0002916A8" class="indent1"><num value="7">(7) </num><content>for any such unlicensed facility in operation for more than three consecutive months, ORR shall conduct a minimum of one comprehensive monitoring visit during the first three months of operation, with quarterly monitoring visits thereafter; </content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/8" id="H7A04D562F66A49569DF72273C349A2A3" class="indent1"><num value="8">(8) </num><content>not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, ORR shall brief the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate outlining the requirements of ORR for influx facilities; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s304/9" id="HE4BDAE85041343FDB1DA4F301FCC362E" class="indent1"><num value="9">(9) </num><content>the amounts provided by this section are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</content></paragraph></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s305" id="H13BA154795294703803E7AA08551CF11"><num value="305"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 305. </inline></num><content class="inline">In addition to the existing Congressional notification requirements for formal site assessments of potential influx facilities, the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate at least 15 days before operationalizing an unlicensed facility, and shall (1) specify whether the facility is hard-sided or soft-sided, and (2) provide analysis that indicates that, in the absence of the influx facility, the likely outcome is that unaccompanied alien children will remain in the custody of the Department of Homeland Security for longer than 72 hours or that unaccompanied alien children will be otherwise placed in danger. Within 60 days of bringing such a facility online, and monthly thereafter, the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report detailing the total number of children in care at the facility, the average length of stay and average length of care of children at the facility, and, for any child that has been at the facility for more than 60 days, their length of stay and reason for delay in release.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306" id="H5F8C38CAFB554B7B915640827DD97252"><num value="306"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 306. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/a" id="H989A251D400C4EF0B6EFBFDBDC76EEE8" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><content>The Secretary shall ensure that, when feasible, no unaccompanied alien child is at an unlicensed facility if the child is not expected to be placed with a sponsor within 30 days.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/b" id="H9BA0C77192664B6CAD4EBEC2B96633B2" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that no unaccompanied alien child is at an unlicensed facility if the child—</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/b/1" id="HF09C664AAA72457683A130AEA99D8687" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>is under the age of 13;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/b/2" id="HDF1E0248EB824BEBBDC2A35F0F1D9CD9" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>does not speak English or Spanish as his or her preferred language;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/b/3" id="H8628A19310D948A7985C537BE9A84A9F" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>has known special needs, behavioral health issues, or medical issues that would be better served at an alternative facility;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/b/4" id="HACAB8DEF3D3E435FBF8CC578FF4BEA0B" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>is a pregnant or parenting teen; or</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/b/5" id="HA017195364B24C8B8187AE29ABD03B91" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content>would have a diminution of legal services as a result of the transfer to such an unlicensed facility.</content></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s306/c" id="H6B2D4CB919ED48D793ECD5AFB7B7C8C8" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><content>ORR shall notify a child’s attorney of record in advance of any transfer, where applicable.</content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s307" id="H6C74D75340514F5781561A638916F2BC"><num value="307"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 307. </inline></num><content class="inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to prevent a United States Senator or Member of the House of Representatives from entering, for the purpose of conducting oversight, any facility in the United States used for the purpose of maintaining custody of, or otherwise housing, unaccompanied alien children (as defined in section 462(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s279/g/2">6 U.S.C. 279(g)(2)</ref>)): <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this section shall be construed to require such a Senator or Member to provide prior notice of the intent to enter such a facility for such purpose.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s308" id="H5524B4E3F6764BEE97299D0CA3704A9F"><num value="308"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 308. </inline></num><chapeau class="inline">Not later than 14 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and monthly thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and make publicly available online, a report with respect to children who were separated from their parents or legal guardians by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) (regardless of whether or not such separation was pursuant to an option selected by the children, parents, or guardians), subsequently classified as unaccompanied alien children, and transferred to the care and custody of ORR during the previous month. Each report shall contain the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s308/1" id="HF73EEF86C2E042F19CC1306AEE9652F7" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>The number and ages of children so separated subsequent to apprehension at or between ports of entry, to be reported by sector where separation occurred.</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s308/2" id="H031A69734B3A4D10B66415C21580ADC5" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>The documented cause of separation, as reported by DHS when each child was referred.</content></paragraph></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s309" id="HBC6CC82185FB45638845563CFF3422C8"><num value="309"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 309. </inline></num><content class="inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed spend plan of anticipated uses of funds made available in this account, including the following: a list of existing grants and contracts for both permanent and influx facilities, including their costs, capacity, and timelines; costs for expanding capacity through the use of community-based residential care placements (including long-term and transitional foster care and small group homes) through new or modified grants and contracts; current and planned efforts to expand small-scale shelters and available foster care placements, including collaboration with state child welfare providers; influx facilities being assessed for possible use; costs and services to be provided for legal services, child advocates, and post release services; program administration; and the average number of weekly referrals and discharge rate assumed in the spend plan: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such plan shall be updated to reflect changes and expenditures and submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate every 60 days until all funds are expended or expire.</proviso></content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s310" id="H5CAB0B679D1E4942B6D285F6154326EA"><num value="310"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 310. </inline></num><content class="inline">The Office of Refugee Resettlement shall ensure that its grantees are aware of current law regarding the use of information collected as part of the sponsor vetting process.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s311" id="HD6FFA08EBB4244589F8E8CF7C7D7DA09"><num value="311"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 311. </inline></num><content class="inline">The Secretary is directed to report the death of any unaccompanied alien child in Office of Refugee Resettlement (ORR) custody or in the custody of any grantee on behalf of ORR within 24 hours, including relevant details regarding the circumstances of the fatality, to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s312" id="HF8EBFB504C6346DF84710964EEE7203C"><num value="312"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 312. </inline></num><content class="inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds made available in this Act under the heading “<headingText>Department of Health and Human Services—Administration for Children and Families—Refugee and Entrant Assistance</headingText>” shall only be used for the purposes specifically described under that heading.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s313" id="H98B8605D64B54C508139EBD0D29C8E29"><num value="313"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 313. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s313/a" id="HAA859120C8194CA08FFAC8C1AE5BC8E4" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall ensure that no unaccompanied alien child (as defined in section 462(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<ref href="/us/usc/t6/s279/g/2">6 U.S.C. 279(g)(2)</ref>)) spends more than 90 days, in the aggregate, at an unlicensed facility.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s313/b" id="H5B6D8BCA88D04F0F9779EDFF3F7D0FF5" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><content>Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall ensure transfer to a State-licensed facility for any unaccompanied alien child who has been at an unlicensed facility for longer than 90 days.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s313/c" id="HD34E2886341B42028084D6E7BEC9E7B9" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><content>Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to an unaccompanied alien child when the Secretary determines that a potential sponsor had been identified and the unaccompanied alien child is expected to be placed with the sponsor within 30 days.</content></subsection>
<subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIII/s313/d" id="H59FA262B5CCB474399A07FB661135859" class="indent0"><num value="d">(d) </num><content>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), if the Secretary determines there is insufficient space available at State-licensed facilities to transfer an unaccompanied alien child who has been at an unlicensed facility for longer than 90 days, the Secretary shall submit a written justification to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and shall submit a summary every two weeks, disaggregated by influx facility, on the number of unaccompanied alien children at each influx facility longer than 90 days, with a summary of both the status of placement and the transfer efforts for all children who have been in care for longer than 90 days.</content></subsection></section></title>
<title identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV" id="H55C5BCD5A52B43FCB4E3076C0BD39782"><num value="IV">TITLE IV</num><heading class="block">GENERAL PROVISIONS—THIS ACT</heading>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s401" id="HF026E67EE02B44A59152EA5EC26AFCB6"><num value="401"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 401. </inline></num><subsection identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s401/a" id="HCB689F687FF543B39A775B410ECFB2F7" class="inline"><num value="a">(a) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Fiscal Year 2017</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds made available by the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2017 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dJ">division J of Public Law 115–31</ref>) that were initially obligated for assistance for El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras may not be reprogrammed after the date of enactment of this Act for assistance for a country other than for which such funds were initially obligated: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That if the Secretary of State suspends assistance for the central government of El Salvador, Guatemala, or Honduras pursuant to section 7045(a)(5) of such Act, not less than 75 percent of the funds for such central government shall be reprogrammed for assistance through nongovernmental organizations or local government entities in such country: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the balance of such funds shall only be reprogrammed for assistance for countries in the Western Hemisphere.</proviso></content></subsection>
<subsection role="instruction" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s401/b" id="H0A756707090C4260B138F759107FA0FE" class="indent0"><num value="b">(b) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Fiscal Year 2018</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 7045(a) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dK">division K of Public Law 115–141</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> paragraph (4)(D) and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> in lieu of paragraph (1) the following paragraph:
<quotedContent styleType="OLC" id="H260EDE9C39C949619897D92704BD1A0F">
<paragraph id="H7CDFB9D71EFC47D0B7851ECB8D2F99D6" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the requirements of this subsection, of the funds appropriated under titles III and IV of this Act, not less than $615,000,000 shall be made available for assistance for countries in Central America, of which not less than $452,000,000 shall be for assistance for El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to implement the United States Strategy for Engagement in Central America (the Strategy): <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amounts shall be made available notwithstanding any provision of law permitting deviations below such amounts: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That if the Secretary of State cannot make the certifications under paragraph (3), or makes a determination under paragraph (4)(A) or (4)(C) that the central government of El Salvador, Guatemala, or Honduras is not meeting the requirements of this subsection, not less than 75 percent of the funds for such central government shall be reprogrammed for assistance through nongovernmental organizations or local government entities in such country: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the balance of such funds shall only be reprogrammed for assistance for countries in the Western Hemisphere.”</proviso></content></paragraph></quotedContent><inline role="after-quoted-block">.</inline></content></subsection>
<subsection role="instruction" identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s401/c" id="HA2786D39C3CC4921B1ED6B1A7B36422A" class="indent0"><num value="c">(c) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Fiscal Year 2019</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 7045(a) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2019 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/6/dF">division F of Public Law 116–6</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="delete">striking</amendingAction> paragraph (2)(C) and <amendingAction type="insert">inserting</amendingAction> at the end, between paragraph (4)(B) and subsection (b), the following new paragraph:
<quotedContent styleType="appropriations" id="HB7402BFE5DA04E6A98D6734A098B028B">
<paragraph id="HABF7FAE82D8846A5941D80F26A97864F" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5) </num><heading><inline class="smallCaps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the requirements of this subsection, of the funds appropriated under titles III and IV of this Act, not less than $540,850,000 shall be made available for assistance for countries in Central America, of which not less than $452,000,000 shall be made available for assistance for El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to implement the United States Strategy for Engagement in Central America: <proviso><i>Provided</i>, That such amounts shall be made available notwithstanding any provision of law permitting deviations below such amounts: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That if the Secretary of State cannot make the certification under paragraph (1), or makes a determination under paragraph (2) that the central government of El Salvador, Guatemala, or Honduras is not meeting the requirements of this subsection, not less than 75 percent of the funds for such central government shall be reprogrammed for assistance through nongovernmental organizations or local government entities in such country: </proviso><proviso><i>Provided further</i>, That the balance of such funds shall only be reprogrammed for assistance for countries in the Western Hemisphere.”</proviso></content></paragraph></quotedContent><inline role="after-quoted-block">.</inline></content></subsection></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s402" id="HF5ECAED0BF9A4CEB80A95C6E32139BEB"><num value="402"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 402. </inline></num><content class="inline">Each amount appropriated or made available by this Act is in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s403" id="H5B45FC8BFBC44B6CAA54FDAAB2947B70"><num value="403"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 403. </inline></num><content class="inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s404" id="H0BB6985DDA5548CDAFDE8DB1C9B8FB37"><num value="404"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 404. </inline></num><content class="inline">Unless otherwise provided for by this Act, the additional amounts appropriated by this Act to appropriations accounts shall be available under the authorities and conditions applicable to such appropriations accounts for fiscal year 2019.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s405" id="HC178321FD4C74A85AFED6156173AA2FC"><num value="405"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 405. </inline></num><content class="inline">Each amount designated in this Act by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 shall be available (or rescinded or transferred, if applicable) only if the President subsequently so designates all such amounts and transmits such designations to the Congress.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/bill/116/hr/3401/tIV/s406" id="H11B706D13DA84595BDF8179EF9B84947"><num value="406"><inline class="smallCaps">Sec. 406. </inline></num><content class="inline">Any amount appropriated by this Act, designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 and subsequently so designated by the President, and transferred pursuant to transfer authorities provided by this Act shall retain such designation.</content></section><section id="HC2C472E9CC5A4FD7BCA9BE2A8551573F" class="inline"><content class="block inline">This Act may be cited as the “<shortTitle role="act">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Humanitarian Assistance and Security at the Southern Border Act, 2019</shortTitle>”.</content></section></title></main>
<attestation><action><actionDescription>Passed the House of Representatives </actionDescription><date date="2019-06-25" meta="chamber:House">June 25, 2019</date>.</action>
<signatures>
<signature><notation type="attestation">Attest: </notation><name>CHERYL L. JOHNSON,</name><role>Clerk.</role></signature></signatures></attestation></bill>