<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><resolution xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:uslm="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm uslm-2.1.0.xsd" xml:lang="en" id="H9CD00070523A436BB7E2655FC6D1F814"><!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.--> <meta>
<dc:title>116 HRES 1033 IH: Condemning acts by the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region that violate fundamental rights and freedoms of Hong Kong residents as well as acts that undermine Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy.</dc:title>
<dc:type>House Simple Resolution</dc:type>
<docNumber>1033</docNumber>
<citableAs>116 HRES 1033 IH</citableAs>
<citableAs>116hres1033ih</citableAs>
<citableAs>116 H. Res. 1033 IH</citableAs>
<docStage>Introduced in House</docStage>
<currentChamber>HOUSE</currentChamber>
<dc:creator>United States House of Representatives</dc:creator>
<processedBy>GPO XPub Bill to USLM Generator, version 0.5 + manual changes</processedBy>
<processedDate>2024-09-09</processedDate>
<dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<congress>116</congress>
<session>2</session>
<publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta>
<preface>
<slugLine>•HRES 1033 IH</slugLine>
<distributionCode display="yes">IV</distributionCode>
<congress value="116">116th CONGRESS</congress>
<session value="2">2d Session</session>
<dc:type>H. RES. </dc:type>
<docNumber>1033</docNumber>
<dc:title>Condemning acts by the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region that violate fundamental rights and freedoms of Hong Kong residents as well as acts that undermine Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy.</dc:title>
<currentChamber value="HOUSE">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</currentChamber>
<action><date date="2020-06-30"><inline class="smallCaps">June </inline>30, 2020</date><actionDescription><sponsor bioGuideId="E000179">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Engel</inline></sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor bioGuideId="M001157">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">McCaul</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor bioGuideId="M000312">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">McGovern</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor bioGuideId="B001287">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Bera</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor bioGuideId="Y000065">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Yoho</inline></cosponsor>, and <cosponsor bioGuideId="M001203">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Malinowski</inline></cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee committeeId="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee></actionDescription></action></preface>
<main styleType="OLC"><longTitle><docTitle>RESOLUTION</docTitle><officialTitle>Condemning acts by the People’s Republic of China and the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region that violate fundamental rights and freedoms of Hong Kong residents as well as acts that undermine Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy.</officialTitle></longTitle><preamble>
<recital>Whereas the Government of the People’s Republic of China is legally bound to guarantee the civil liberties of the people of Hong Kong through 2047 under the Basic Law and the “Joint Declaration of the Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland and the Government of the People’s Republic of China on the Question of Hong Kong” (hereafter the “Joint Declaration”), in which the People’s Republic of China committed that for 50 years, the “social and economic systems in Hong Kong will remain unchanged, and so will the life-style.”;</recital>
<recital>Whereas Article 39 of the Basic Law of Hong Kong mandates that: “The provisions of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights, and international labour conventions as applied to Hong Kong shall remain in force and shall be implemented through the laws of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.”;</recital>
<recital><p class="inline">Whereas Chapter III of the Basic Law of Hong Kong guarantees Hong Kong residents other specific rights and freedoms, including—</p>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/1" id="id197AD5E13BD844049AEDAFA1575F7429" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content> freedom of speech, of the press, and of publication;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/2" id="id0AF4A98278E049F28CA9C5810BBC5A69" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content> freedom of association, of assembly, of procession, and of demonstration;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/3" id="id54EE5444AA704E5F848E1637F2670E3D" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content> the right and freedom to form and join trade unions and to strike;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/4" id="id8B3E6C05BF3E43BE81C237E9DEBB8EF7" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>freedom from arbitrary or unlawful arrest, detention, or imprisonment; </content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/5" id="id5A631AECC4B44634B3B710C98A69AD6D" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><content> freedom from arbitrary or unlawful search of, or intrusion into, a Hong Kong resident’s home or other premises;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/6" id="id0C71CD8CB99E412099D71265B8BCDB4C" class="indent1"><num value="6">(6) </num><content> freedom and privacy of communication; </content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/7" id="id44CE0D790CD34EB39BE46B560E6652E6" class="indent1"><num value="7">(7) </num><content> freedom of movement within the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region; </content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/8" id="id5D3AC3FACEE3487CB0504DA195C521C6" class="indent1"><num value="8">(8) </num><content> freedom of emigration to other countries and regions;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/9" id="id8518B45E65D343B3A07EA4AAEA2BE97A" class="indent1"><num value="9">(9) </num><content> freedom of conscience; and </content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/10" id="idA97B4F0B962247978B70F5C250AC6549" class="indent1"><num value="10">(10) </num><content> the right to institute legal proceedings in the courts against the acts of the executive authorities and their personnel; </content></paragraph></recital>
<recital>Whereas the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress of the People’s Republic of China has inserted a national security law directly into Annex III of the Basic Law of Hong Kong, and said national security law is purportedly intended to prevent and punish acts of “separating the country, subverting state power, and organizing terroristic activities”;</recital>
<recital>Whereas said action is a flagrant violation of Hong Kong’s autonomy and rule of law in that Article 18 of the Basic Law provides that laws included in Annex III are “confined to those relating to defense and foreign affairs as well as other matters outside the limits of the autonomy of the Region as specified by this Law”;</recital>
<recital>Whereas Article 23 further specifies that “[Hong Kong] shall enact laws on its own to prohibit any act of treason, secession, sedition, subversion against the Central People’s Government”;</recital>
<recital>Whereas through a similar abuse of Annex III of the Basic Law of Hong Kong, the Government of the People’s Republic of China caused the adoption of the National Anthem Law in Hong Kong, which curtails the freedom of speech and carries a maximum sentence of 3 years, mirroring the extent of sentence under the People’s Republic of China Criminal Law;</recital>
<recital>Whereas the Chinese Government’s repeated and heavy-handed actions to undermine the rule of law in Hong Kong and Hong Kong’s high degree of autonomy will only further escalate the ongoing protests, jeopardizing Hong Kong’s future as an open and prosperous international city; and</recital>
<recital>Whereas the imposition of this national security legislation, which undermines the established rights and freedoms of Hong Kong residents provided in the Joint Declaration and the Basic Law, would constitute a violation of commitments made by the People’s Republic of China under international law: Now, therefore, be it</recital><resolvingClause><i>Resolved, </i></resolvingClause></preamble><resolvingClause><i>Resolved, </i></resolvingClause><section id="id44B5506855394D0D89842701B95344EC" class="inline"><chapeau>That the House of Representatives— </chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/1" id="id5916BB170DB3457DA19CE814BA958CBF" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><content>underscores that democratic societies around the world stand in solidarity with the people of Hong Kong, who face grave threats to their inviolable rights and freedoms;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/2" id="id6BA545B878F94D3C9BEE881DE69F0E27" class="indent1"><num value="2">(2) </num><content>condemns the action by the People’s Republic of China’s National People’s Congress to advance national security legislation for Hong Kong through irregular procedures, which would constitute a violation of the letter and spirit of the Basic Law and the Joint Declaration;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/3" id="id30231059CC2F4F0097B1CA0E81388B29" class="indent1"><num value="3">(3) </num><content>asserts that such actions by the People’s Republic of China undermine the credibility of the People’s Republic of China within the international community, including the People’s Republic of China’s credibility in honoring its commitments to international agreements and respecting internationally recognized human rights;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/4" id="idBEE53D03BBCB45BDA933A82606A4EA2A" class="indent1"><num value="4">(4) </num><content>urges the People’s Republic of China and the Hong Kong Government to refrain from implementation of this law or taking any action that abridges or curtails, in whole or in part, the rights of Hong Kong residents as established by the Joint Declaration and Basic Law; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/5" id="idD6560E378465420A8EAF716AB82A8697" class="indent1"><num value="5">(5) </num><chapeau>advises the President, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of the Treasury to coordinate with allies and partners to respond to developments in Hong Kong, including by— </chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/5/A" id="id2911642170E04A55A7DD2C059B33F50B" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>appointing a United Nations Special Envoy for Hong Kong;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/5/B" id="idE7765CAE680A46608A68E6C5CC045E2E" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>expanding the mandate of the United Nations Special Rapporteur to improve monitoring and reporting on People’s Republic of China’s policies in Hong Kong;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/5/C" id="id714F6F001F73469FACFCDE939A912A20" class="indent2"><num value="C">(C) </num><content>providing Hong Kong residents who face well-founded fears of persecution an opportunity to emigrate from, or not be compelled to return to, Hong Kong;</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/5/D" id="idEAF296C7E77B467F9457A505FA021E64" class="indent2"><num value="D">(D) </num><content>introducing other measures to urge the People’s Republic of China to refrain from promulgating national security legislation in Hong Kong which contravenes the Joint Declaration and the Basic Law; and</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/hres/1033/s/5/E" id="idA702C6EBEDB94F5CB12E627B19C74F5F" class="indent2"><num value="E">(E) </num><content>establishing other measures, including economic sanctions, to hold the People’s Republic of China accountable for contravention of international law and human rights norms with respect to Hong Kong.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section></main><endMarker>○</endMarker></resolution>