<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><resolution xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:uslm="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm uslm-2.1.0.xsd" xml:lang="en"><!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.--> <meta>
<dc:title>116 SJRES 36 ENR: Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed transfer to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, the Kingdom of Spain, and the Italian Republic of certain defense articles and services.</dc:title>
<dc:type>Senate Joint Resolution</dc:type>
<docNumber>36</docNumber>
<citableAs>116 SJRES 36 ENR</citableAs>
<citableAs>116sjres36enr</citableAs>
<citableAs>116 S. J. Res. 36 ENR</citableAs>
<docStage>Enrolled Bill</docStage>
<processedBy>GPO XPub Bill to USLM Generator, version 0.5 + manual changes</processedBy>
<processedDate>2024-09-09</processedDate>
<dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<congress>116</congress>
<session>1</session>
<publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta>
<preface>
<dc:type>S. J. Res. </dc:type>
<docNumber>36</docNumber>
<congress value="116">One Hundred Sixteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress>
<session value="1">AT THE FIRST SESSION</session>
<enrolledDateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Thursday, the third day of January, two thousand and nineteen</enrolledDateline></preface>
<main styleType="OLC"><longTitle><docTitle>Joint Resolution</docTitle><officialTitle>Providing for congressional disapproval of the proposed transfer to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, the Kingdom of Spain, and the Italian Republic of certain defense articles and services.</officialTitle></longTitle><resolvingClause><i>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, </i></resolvingClause><section id="S1" class="inline"><chapeau class="inline">That the issuance of a manufacturing license, technical assistance license, or export license with respect to any of the following proposed agreements or transfers to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, the Kingdom of Spain, and the Italian Republic is prohibited:</chapeau>
<paragraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/36/s/1" id="idb6717d6911604398a17dca9e808e96ab" class="indent1"><num value="1">(1) </num><chapeau>The transfer of the following defense articles, including defense services and technical data, described in Executive Communication 1427 (EC–1427) submitted to Congress pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2776">22 U.S.C. 2776</ref>) and published in the Congressional Record on June 3, 2019:</chapeau>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/36/s/1/A" id="id0E6661108CD143CAA64187C9C022B766" class="indent2"><num value="A">(A) </num><content>Coproduction and manufacture in Saudi Arabia of Paveway Pre-Amp Circuit Card Assemblies (CCA), Guidance Electronics Assembly (GEA) CCAs, and Control Actuator System (CAS) CCAs for all Paveway variants.</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/36/s/1/B" id="idF3FD5F2E1FD8409B899CC0177E1A18B5" class="indent2"><num value="B">(B) </num><content>Coproduction and manufacture in Saudi Arabia of Paveway II Guidance Electronics Detector Assemblies (GEDA) and Computer Control Groups (CCG).</content></subparagraph>
<subparagraph identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/36/s/1/C" id="id4092DAE9C1D24D59815A40EC56AA3CB7" class="indent2"><num value="C">(C) </num><content>The transfer of up to 64,603 additional kits, partial kits, and full-up-rounds.</content></subparagraph></paragraph></section></main>
<signatures>
<signature><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives</role>.</signature></signatures>
<signatures>
<signature><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></signature></signatures></resolution>