<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><statuteCompilation xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:gpo="http://www.gpo.gov/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.0.9.xsd" xml:lang="en" style="-uslm-dtd:statute">
    <meta style="-uslm-dtd:compilation-act-form">
        <dc:title>OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH ACT OF 1970</dc:title>
        <citableAs>Public Law 91–596, as amended</citableAs>
        <citableAsShortTitle>OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH ACT OF 1970</citableAsShortTitle>
        <docNumber>596</docNumber>
        <currentThroughPublicLaw>116–92</currentThroughPublicLaw>
        <dc:type>Statute Compilation</dc:type>
        <dc:creator>United States House of Representatives</dc:creator>
        <dc:creator>Office of the Legislative Counsel</dc:creator>
        <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
        <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
        <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
        <processedBy>GPO Statute Compilations USLM converter, version 20210520.1</processedBy>
        <processedDate>2021-05-25</processedDate>
        <containsShortTitle>Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970</containsShortTitle>
        <property role="fileId">1523</property>
        <congress>91</congress>
        <approvedDate>1970-12-29</approvedDate>
    </meta>
    <preface style="-uslm-dtd:compilation-act-form">
        <property style="-uslm-dtd:comp-short-title" role="compShortTitle">OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH ACT OF 1970</property>
        <citationNote style="-uslm-dtd:public-law">[<citableAs>Public Law 91–596</citableAs>, <date date="1970-12-29">December 29, 1970</date>]</citationNote>
        <editionNote style="-uslm-dtd:updated-through-note">[As Amended Through <currentThroughPublicLaw>P.L. 116–92</currentThroughPublicLaw>, Enacted <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>]</editionNote>
        <explanationNote style="-uslm-dtd:explanatory-note"><b>[</b>Currency: This publication is a compilation of the text of Public Law 91-596. It was last amended by the public law listed in the As Amended Through note above and below at the bottom of each page of the pdf version and reflects current law through the date of the enactment of the public law listed at https://www.govinfo.gov/app/collection/comps/<b>]</b></explanationNote>
        <explanationNote style="-uslm-dtd:explanatory-note"><b>[</b>Note: While this publication does  not represent an official version of any Federal statute, substantial efforts have been made to ensure the accuracy of its contents. The official version of Federal law is found in the United States Statutes at Large and in the United States Code. The legal effect to be given to the Statutes at Large and the United States Code is established by statute (1 U.S.C. 112, 204).<b>]</b></explanationNote>
    </preface>
    <main style="-uslm-dtd:legis-body"><longTitle><docTitle style="-uslm-dtd:legis-type">AN ACT</docTitle><officialTitle style="-uslm-dtd:official-title">To assure safe and healthful working conditions for working men and women; by authorizing enforcement of the standards developed under the Act; by assisting and encouraging the States in their efforts to assure safe and healthful working conditions; by providing for research, information, education, and training in the field of occupational safety and health; and for other purposes.</officialTitle></longTitle><enactingFormula style="-uslm-dtd:enacting-clause">
Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,
</enactingFormula><section style="-uslm-dtd:section" styleType="OLC" role="undesignated-level" class="inline"><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">That this Act may be cited as the “<shortTitle style="-uslm-dtd:quote">Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970</shortTitle>”.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651nt">29 U.S.C. 651nt</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 1, 84 Stat. 1590.</sourceCredit></section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">congressional findings and purpose </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="(2)">Sec. (2)<ref style="-uslm-dtd:footnote-ref" idref="IDF9549612DEA54351B3DA03CBB6290F3E" class="footnoteRef">1</ref> </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" styleType="traditional" role="undesignated-level" class="inline"><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Congress finds that personal injuries and illnesses arising out of work situations impose a substantial burden upon, and are a hindrance to, interstate commerce in terms of lost production, wage loss, medical expenses, and disability compensation payments.</content><footnote id="IDF9549612DEA54351B3DA03CBB6290F3E" style="-uslm-dtd:footnote"><sup style="-uslm-dtd:superscript">1</sup><p style="-uslm-dtd:para; margin-left:1em">So in original. Probably should strike “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">(2)</quotedText>” and insert “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">2. (a)</quotedText>”.</p></footnote></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Congress declares it to be its purpose and policy, through the exercise of its powers to regulate commerce among the several States and with foreign nations and to provide for the general welfare, to assure so far as possible every working man and woman in the Nation safe and healthful working conditions and to preserve our human resources—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by encouraging employers and employees in their efforts to reduce the number of occupational safety and health hazards at their places of employment, and to stimulate employers and employees to institute new and to perfect existing programs for providing safe and healthful working conditions;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing that employers and employees have separate but dependent responsibilities and rights with respect to achieving safe and healthful working conditions;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/3" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by authorizing the Secretary of Labor to set mandatory occupational safety and health standards applicable to businesses affecting interstate commerce, and by creating an Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission for carrying out adjudicatory functions under the Act;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/4" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by building upon advances already made through employer and employee initiative for providing safe and healthful working conditions;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/5" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing for research in the field of occupational safety and health, including the psychological factors involved, and by developing innovative methods, techniques, and approaches for dealing with occupational safety and health problems;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/6" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by exploring ways to discover latent diseases, establishing causal connections between diseases and work in environmental conditions, and conducting other research relating to health problems, in recognition of the fact that occupational health standards present problems often different from those involved in occupational safety;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/7" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing medical criteria which will assure insofar as practicable that no employee will suffer diminished health, functional capacity, or life expectancy as a result of his work experience;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/8" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="8">(8) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing for training programs to increase the number and competence of personnel engaged in the field of occupational safety and health;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/9" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="9">(9) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing for the development and promulgation of occupational safety and health standards;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/10" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="10">(10) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing an effective enforcement program which shall include a prohibition against giving advance notice of any inspection and sanctions for any individual violating this prohibition;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/11" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="11">(11) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by encouraging the States to assume the fullest responsibility for the administration and enforcement of their occupational safety and health laws by providing grants to the States to assist in identifying their needs and responsibilities in the area of occupational safety and health, to develop plans in accordance with the provisions of this Act, to improve the administration and enforcement of State occupational safety and health laws, and to conduct experimental and demonstration projects in connection therewith;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/12" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="12">(12) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by providing for appropriate reporting procedures with respect to occupational safety and health which procedures will help achieve the objectives of this Act and accurately describe the nature of the occupational safety and health problem;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s(2)/b/13" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="13">(13) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by encouraging joint labor-management efforts to reduce injuries and disease arising out of employment.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">29 U.S.C. 651</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 2, 84 Stat. 1590.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3" styleType="traditional" role="definitions">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">definitions </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">Sec. 3. </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">For the purposes of this Act—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">Secretary</term>” means the Secretary of Labor.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">Commission</term>” means the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission established under this Act.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/3" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">commerce</term>” means trade, traffic, commerce, transportation, or communication among the several States, or between a State and any place outside thereof, or within the District of Columbia, or a possession of the United States (other than the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands), or between points in the same State but through a point outside thereof.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/4" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">person</term>” means one or more individuals, partnerships, associations, corporations, business trusts, legal representatives, or any organized group of persons.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/5" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">employer</term>” means a person engaged in a business affecting commerce who has employees, but does not include the United States (not including the United States Postal Service) or any State or political subdivision of a State.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/6" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">employee</term>” means an employee of an employer who is employed in a business of his employer which affects commerce.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/7" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">State</term>” includes a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/8" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="8">(8) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">occupational safety and health standard</term>” means a standard which requires conditions, or the adoption or use of one or more practices, means, methods, operations, or processes, reasonably necessary or appropriate to provide safe or healthful employment and places of employment.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/9" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="9">(9) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">national consensus standard</term>” means any occupational safety and health standard or modification thereof which (1) has been adopted and promulgated by a nationally recognized standards-producing organization under procedures whereby it can be determined by the Secretary that persons interested and affected by the scope or provisions of the standard have reached substantial agreement on its adoption, (2) was formulated in a manner which afforded an opportunity for diverse views to be considered and (3) has been designated as such a standard by the Secretary, after consultation with other appropriate Federal agencies.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/10" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="10">(10) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">established Federal standard</term>” means any operative occupational safety and health standard established by any agency of the United States and presently in effect, or contained in any Act of Congress in force on the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/11" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="11">(11) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">Committee</term>” means the National Advisory Committee on Occupational Safety and Health established under this Act.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/12" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="12">(12) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">Director</term>” means the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/13" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="13">(13) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">Institute</term>” means the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health established under this Act.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s3/14" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="14">(14) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The term “<term style="-uslm-dtd:term">Workmen's Compensation Commission</term>” means the National Commission on State Workmen's Compensation Laws established under this Act.</content>
            </paragraph><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s652">29 U.S.C. 652</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 3, 84 Stat. 1591.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">applicability of this act </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">Sec. 4. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">This Act shall apply with respect to employment performed in a workplace in a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, Wake Island, Outer Continental Shelf lands defined in the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, Johnston Island, and the Canal Zone. The Secretary of the Interior shall, by regulation, provide for judicial enforcement of this Act by the courts established for areas in which there are no United States district courts having jurisdiction.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4/b/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Nothing in this Act shall apply to working conditions of employees with respect to which other Federal agencies, and State agencies acting under section 274 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended (42 U.S.C. 2021), exercise statutory authority to prescribe or enforce standards or regulations affecting occupational safety or health.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4/b/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The safety and health standards promulgated under the Act of June 30, 1936, commonly known as the Walsh-Healey Act (41 U.S.C. 35 et seq.), the Service Contract Act of 1965 (41 U.S.C. 351 et seq.), Public Law 91–54, Act ofAugust 9, 1969 (40 U.S.C. 333). Public Law 85–742, Act of August 23, 1958 (33 U.S.C. 941), and the National Foundation on Arts and Humanities Act (20 U.S.C. 951 et seq.) are superseded on the effective date of corresponding standards, promulgated under this Act, which are determined by the Secretary to be more effective. Standards issued under the laws listed in this paragraph and in effect on or after the effective date of this Act shall be deemed to be occupational safety and health standards issued under this Act, as well as under such other Acts.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4/b/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall, within three years after the effective date of this Act, report to the Congress his recommendations for legislation to avoid unnecessary duplication and to achieve coordination between this Act and other Federal laws.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s4/b/4" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede or in any manner affect any workmen's compensation law or to enlarge or diminish or affect in any other manner the common law or statutory rights, duties, or liabilities of employers and employees under any law with respect to injuries, diseases, or death of employees arising out of, or in the course of, employment.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s653">29 U.S.C. 653</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 4, 84 Stat. 1592.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s5" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">duties </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">Sec. 5. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s5/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">Each employer—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s5/a/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">shall furnish to each of his employees employment and a place of employment which are free from recognized hazards that are causing or are likely to cause death or serious physical harm to his employees;</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s5/a/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">shall comply with occupational safety and health standards promulgated under this Act.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s5/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Each employee shall comply with occupational safety and health standards and all rules, regulations, and orders issued pursuant to this Act which are applicable to his own actions and conduct.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s654">29 U.S.C. 654</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 5, 84 Stat. 1593.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">occupational safety and health standards </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">Sec. 6. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Without regard to chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code, or to the other subsections of this section, the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable during the period beginning with the effective date of this Act and ending two years after such date, by rule promulgate as an occupational safety or health standard any national consensus standard, and any established Federal standard, unless he determines that the promulgation of such a standard would not result in improved safety or health for specifically designated employees. In the event of conflict among any such standards, the Secretary shall promulgate the standard which assures the greatest protection of the safety or health of the affected employees.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary may by rule promulgate, modify, or revoke any occupational safety or health standard in the following manner:</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Whenever the Secretary, upon the basis of information submitted to him in writing by an interested person, a representative of any organization of employers or employees, a nationally recognized standards-producing organization, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare,<ref style="-uslm-dtd:footnote-ref" idref="ID57F0D2B450A4424D9000C6A24115B2CA" class="footnoteRef">2</ref> the National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health, or a State or political subdivision, or on the basis of information developed by the Secretary or otherwise available to him, determines that a rule should be promulgated in order to serve the objectives of this Act, the Secretary may request the recommendations of an advisory committee appointed under section 7 of this Act. The Secretary shall provide such an advisory committee with any proposals of his own or of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, together with all pertinent factual information developed by the Secretary or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, or otherwise available, including the results of research, demonstrations, and experiments. An advisory committee shall submit to the Secretary its recommendations regarding the rule to be promulgated within ninety days from the date of its appointment or within such longer or shorter period as may be prescribed by the Secretary, but in no event for a period which is longer than two hundred and seventy days.</content><footnote id="ID57F0D2B450A4424D9000C6A24115B2CA" style="-uslm-dtd:footnote"><sup style="-uslm-dtd:superscript">2</sup><p style="-uslm-dtd:para; margin-left:1em">References in this Act to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare are deemed to refer to the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to section 509(b) of the Department of Education Organization Act (20 U.S.C. 3508(b); 93 Stat. 695).</p></footnote>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall publish a proposed rule promulgating, modifying, or revoking an occupational safety or health standard in the Federal Register and shall afford interested persons a period of thirty days after publication to submit written data or comments. Where an advisory committee is appointed and the Secretary determines that a rule should be issued, he shall publish the proposed rule within sixty days after the submission of the advisory committee's recommendations or the expiration of the period prescribed by the Secretary for such submission.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/3" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">On or before the last day of the period provided for the submission of written data or comments under paragraph (2), any interested person may file with the Secretary written objections to the proposed rule, stating the grounds therefor and requesting a public hearing on such objections. Within thirty days after the last day for filing such objections, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice specifying the occupational safety or health standard to which objections have been filed and a hearing requested, and specifying a time and place for such hearing.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/4" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Within sixty days after the expiration of the period provided for the submission of written data or comments under paragraph (2), or within sixty days after the completion of any hearing held under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall issue a rule promulgating, modifying, or revoking an occupational safety or health standard or make a determination that a rule should not be issued. Such a rule may contain a provision delaying its effective date for such period (not in excess of ninety days) as the Secretary determines may be necessary to insure that affected employers and employees will be informed of the existence of the standard and of its terms and that employers affected are given an opportunity to familiarize themselves and their employees with the existence of the requirements of the standard.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/5" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary, in promulgating standards dealing with toxic materials or harmful physical agents under this subsection, shall set the standard which most adequately assures, to the extent feasible, on the basis of the best available evidence, that no employee will suffer material impairment of health or functional capacity even if such employee has regular exposure to the hazard dealt with by such standard for the period of his working life. Development of standards under this subsection shall be based upon research, demonstrations, experiments, and such other information as may be appropriate. In addition to the attainment of the highest degree of health and safety protection for the employee, other considerations shall be the latest available scientific data in the field, the feasibility of the standards, and experience gained under this and other health and safety laws. Whenever practicable, the standard promulgated shall be expressed in terms of objective criteria and of the performance desired.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/A" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer may apply to the Secretary for a temporary order granting a variance from a standard or any provision thereof promulgated under this section. Such temporary order shall be granted only if the employer files an application which meets the requirements of clause (B) and establishes that (i) he is unable to comply with a standard by its effective date because of unavailability of professional or technical personnel or of materials and equipment needed to come into compliance with the standard or because necessary construction or alteration of facilities cannot be completed by the effective date, (ii) he is taking all available steps to safeguard his employees against the hazards covered by the standard, and (iii) he has an effective program for coming into compliance with the standard as quickly as practicable. Any temporary order issued under this paragraph shall prescribe the practices, means, methods, operations, and processes which the employer must adopt and use while the order is in effect and state in detail his program for coming into compliance with the standard. Such a temporary order may be granted only after notice to employees and an opportunity for a hearing: <i style="-uslm-dtd:italic">Provided</i>, That the Secretary may issue one interim order to be effective until a decision is made on the basis of the hearing. No temporary order may be in effect for longer than the period needed by the employer to achieve compliance with the standard or one year, whichever is shorter, except that such an order may be renewed not more than twice (I) so long as the requirements of this paragraph are met and (II) if an application for renewal is filed at least 90 days prior to the expiration date of the order. No interim renewal of an order may remain in effect for longer than 180 days.</content></subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/B" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">An application for a temporary order under this paragraph (6) shall contain:</chapeau>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/B/i" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="i">(i) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">a specification of the standard or portion thereof from which the employer seeks a variance,</content>
                        </clause>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/B/ii" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="ii">(ii) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">a representation by the employer, supported by representations from qualified persons having firsthand knowledge of the facts represented, that he is unable to comply with the standard or portion thereof and a detailed statement of the reasons thereof,</content>
                        </clause>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/B/iii" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="iii">(iii) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">a statement of the steps he has taken and will take (with specific dates) to protect employees against the hazard covered by the standard,</content>
                        </clause>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/B/iv" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="iv">(iv) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">a statement of when he expects to be able to comply with the standard and what steps he has taken and what steps he will take (with dates specified) to come into compliance with the standard, and</content>
                        </clause>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/B/v" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="v">(v) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">a certification that he has informed his employees of the application by giving a copy thereof to their authorized representative, posting a statement giving a summary of the application and specifying where a copy may be examined at the place or places where notices to employees are normally posted, and by other appropriate means.</content>
                        </clause><continuation style="-uslm-dtd:continuation-text" role="subparagraph">A description of how employees have been informed shall be contained in the certification. The information to employees shall also inform them of their right to petition the Secretary for a hearing.</continuation>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/6/C" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="C">(C) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary is authorized to grant a variance from any standard or portion thereof whenever he determines, or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare certifies, that such variance is necessary to permit an employer to participate in an experiment approved by him or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare designed to demonstrate or validate new and improved techniques to safeguard the health or safety of workers.</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/7" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any standard promulgated under this subsection shall prescribe the use of labels or other appropriate forms of warning as are necessary to insure that employees are apprised of all hazards to which they are exposed, relevant symptoms and appropriate emergency treatment, and proper conditions and precautions of safe use or exposure. Where appropriate, such standard shall also prescribe suitable protective equipment and control or technological procedures to be used in connection with such hazards and shall provide for monitoring or measuring employee exposure at such locations and intervals, and in such manner as may be necessary for the protection of employees. In addition, where appropriate, any such standard shall prescribe the type and frequency of medical examinations or other tests which shall be made available, by the employer or at his cost, to employees exposed to such hazards in order to most effectively determine whether the health of such employees is adversely affected by such exposure. In the event such medical examinations are in the nature of research, as determined by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, such examinations may be furnished at the expense of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare. The results of such examinations or tests shall be furnished only to the Secretary or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, and, at the request of the employee, to his physician. The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, may by rule promulgated pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, make appropriate modifications in the foregoing requirements relating to the use of labels or other forms of warning, monitoring or measuring, and medical examinations, as may be warranted by experience, information, or medical or technological developments acquired subsequent to the promulgation of the relevant standard.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/b/8" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="8">(8) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Whenever a rule promulgated by the Secretary differs substantially from an existing national consensus standard, the Secretary shall, at the same time, publish in the Federal Register a statement of the reasons why the rule as adopted will better effectuate the purposes of this Act than the national consensus stantard.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/c/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall provide, without regard to the requirements of chapter 5, title 5, United States Code, for an emergency temporary standard to take immediate effect upon publication in the Federal Register if he determines (A) that employees are exposed to grave danger from exposure to substances or agents determined to be toxic or physically harmful or from new hazards, and (B) that such emergency standard is necessary to protect employees from such danger.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/c/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Such standard shall be effective until superseded by standard promulgated in accordance with the procedures in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/c/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Upon publication of such standard in the Federal Register the Secretary shall commence a proceeding in accordance with section 6(b) of this Act, and the standard as published shall also serve as a proposed rule for the proceeding. The Secretary shall promulgate a standard under this paragraph no later than six months after publication of the emergency standard as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any affected employer may apply to the Secretary for a rule or order for a variance from a standard promulgated under this section. Affected employees shall be given notice of each such application and an opportunity to participate in a hearing. The Secretary shall issue such rule or order if he determines on the record, after opportunity for an inspection where appropriate and a hearing, that the proponent of the variance has demonstrated by a preponderance of the evidence that the conditions, practices, means, methods, operations, or processes used or proposed to be used by an employer will provide employment and places of employment to his employees which are as safe and healthful as those which would prevail if he complied with the standard. The rule or order so issued shall prescribe the conditions the employer must maintain, and the practices, means, methods, operations, and processes which he must adopt and utilize to the extent they differ from the standard in question. Such a rule or order may be modified or revoked upon application by an employer, employees, or by the Secretary on his own motion, in the manner prescribed for its issuance under this subsection at any time after six months from its issuance.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Whenever the Secretary promulgates any standard, makes any rule, order, or decision, grants any exemption or extention of time, or compromises, mitigates, or settles any penalty assessed under this Act, he shall include a statement of the reasons for such action, which shall be published in the Federal Register.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any person who may be adversely affected by a standard issued under this section may at any time prior to the sixtieth day after such standard is promulgated file a petition challenging the validity of such standard with the United States court of appeals for the circuit wherein such person resides or has his principal place of business, for a judicial review of such standards. A copy of the petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Secretary. The filing of such petition shall not, unless otherwise ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the standard. The determinations of the Secretary shall be conclusive if supported by substantial evidence in the record considered as a whole.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s6/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">In determining the priority for establishing standards under this section, the Secretary shall give due regard to the urgency of the need for mandatory safety and health standards for particular industries, trades, crafts, occupations, businesses, workplaces or work environments. The Secretary shall also give due regard to the recommendations of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare regarding the need for mandatory standards in determining the priority for establishing such standards.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s655">29 U.S.C. 655</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 6. 84 Stat. 1593.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">advisory committees; administration </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">Sec. 7. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/a/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There is hereby established a National Advisory Committee on Occupational Safety and Health consisting of twelve members appointed by the Secretary, four of whom are to be designated by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and composed of representatives of management, labor, occupational safety and occupational health professions, and of the public. The Secretary shall designate one of the public members as Chairman. The members shall be selected upon the basis of their experience and competence in the field of occupational safety and health.</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/a/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Committee shall advise, consult with, and make recommendations to the Secretary and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare on matters relating to the administration of the Act. The Committee shall hold no fewer than two meetings during each calendar year. All meetings of the Committee shall be open to the public and a transcript shall be kept and made available for public inspection.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/a/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The members of the Committee shall be compensated in accordance with the provisions of section 3109 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/a/4" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall furnish to the Committee an executive secretary and such secretarial, clerical, and other services as are deemed necessary to the conduct of its business.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">An advisory committee may be appointed by the Secretary to assist him in his standard-setting functions under section 6 of this Act. Each such committee shall consist of not more than fifteen members and shall include as a member one or more designees of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, and shall include among its members an equal number of persons qualified by experience and affiliation to present the viewpoint of the employers involved, and of persons similarly qualified to present the viewpoint of the workers inolved, as well as one or more representatives of health and safety agencies of the States. An advisory committee may also include such other persons as the Secretary may appoint who are qualified by knowledge and experience to make a useful contribution to the work of such committee, including one or more representatives of professional organizations of technicians or professionals specializing in occupational safety or health, and one or more representatives of nationally recognized standards-producing organizations, but the number of persons so appointed to any such advisory committee shall not exceed the number appointed to such committee as representatives of Federal and State agencies. Persons appointed to advisory committees from private life shall be compensated in the same manner as consultants or experts under section 3109 of title 5, United States Code. The Secretary shall pay to any State which is the employer of a member of such a committee who is a representative of the health or safety agency of that State, reimbursement sufficient to cover the actual cost to the State resulting from such representative's membership on such committee. Any meeting of such committee shall be open to the public and an accurate record shall be kept and made available to the public. No member of such committee (other than representatives of employers and employees) shall have an economic interest in any proposed rule.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">In carrying out his responsibilities under this Act, the Secretary is authorized to—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/c/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">use, with the consent of any Federal agency, the services, facilities, and personnel of such agency, with or without reimbursement, and with the consent of any State or political subdivision thereof, accept and use the services, facilities, and personnel of any agency of such State or subdivision with reimbursement; and</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/c/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">employ experts and consultants or organizations thereof as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, except that contracts for such employment may be renewed annually; compensate individuals so employed at rates not in excess of the rate specified at the time of service for grade GS–18 under section 5332 of title 5, United States Code, including traveltime, and allow them while away from their homes or regular places of business, travel expenses (including per diem in lieu of subsistence) as authorized by section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, for persons in the Government service employed intermittently, while so employed.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s7/d" styleType="traditional">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There is established a Maritime Occupational Safety and Health Advisory Committee, which shall be a continuing body and shall provide advice to the Secretary in formulating maritime industry standards and regarding matters pertaining to the administration of this Act related to the maritime industry. The composition of such advisory committee shall be consistent with the advisory committees established under subsection (b). A member of the advisory committee who is otherwise qualified may continue to serve until a successor is appointed. The Secretary may promulgate or amend regulations as necessary to implement this subsection.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s656">29 U.S.C. 656</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 7, 84 Stat. 1597.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">inspections, investigations, and recordkeeping </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="8">Sec. 8. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">In order to carry out the purposes of this Act, the Secretary, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, is authorized—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/a/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">to enter without delay and at reasonable times any factory, plant, establishment, construction site, or other area, workplace or environment where work is performed by an employee of an employer; and</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/a/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">to inspect and investigate during regular working hours and at other reasonable times, and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, any such place of employment and all pertinent conditions, structures, machines, apparatus, devices, equipment, and materials therein, and to question privately any such employer, owner, operator, agent or employee.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">In making his inspections and investigations under this Act the Secretary may require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence under oath. Witnesses shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are paid witnesses in the courts of the United States. In case of a contumacy, failure, or refusal of any person to obey such an order, any district court of the United States or the United States courts of any territory or possession, within the jurisdiction of which such person is found, or resides or transacts business, upon the application by the Secretary, shall have jurisdiction to issue to such person an order requiring such person to appear to produce evidence if, as, and when so ordered, and to give testimony relating to the matter under investigation or in question, and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by said court as a contempt thereof.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/c/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Each employer shall make, keep and preserve, and make available to the Secretary or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, such records regarding his activities relating to this Act as the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, may prescribe by regulation as necessary or appropriate for the enforcement of this Act or for developing information regarding the causes and prevention of occupational accidents and illnesses. In order to carry out the provisions of this paragraph such regulations may include provisions requiring employers to conduct periodic inspections. The Secretary shall also issue regulations requiring that employers, through posting of notices or other appropriate means, keep their employees informed of their protections and obligations under this Act, including the provisions of applicable standards.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/c/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, shall prescribe regulations requiring employers to maintain accurate records of, and to make periodic reports on, work-related deaths, injuries and illnesses other than minor injuries requiring only first aid treatment and which do not involve medical treatment, loss of consciousness, restriction of work or motion, or transfer to another job.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/c/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, shall issue regulations requiring employers to maintain accurate records of employee exposures to potentially toxic materials or harmful physical agents which are required to be monitored or measured under section 6. Such regulations shall provide employees or their representatives with an opportunity to observe such monitoring or measuring, and to have access to the records thereof. Such regulations shall also make appropriate provision for each employee or former employee to have access to such records as will indicate his own exposure to toxic materials or harmful physical agents. Each employer shall promptly notify any employee who has been or is being exposed to toxic materials or harmful physical agents in concentrations or at levels which exceed those prescribed by an applicable occupational safety and health standard promulgated under section 6, and shall inform any employee who is being thus exposed of the corrective action being taken.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any information obtained by the Secretary, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, or a State agency under this Act shall be obtained with a minimum burden upon employers, especially those operating small businesses. Unnecessary duplication of efforts in obtaining information shall be reduced to the maximum extent feasible.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Subject to regulations issued by the Secretary, a representative of the employer and a representative authorized by his employees shall be given an opportunity to accompany the Secretary or his authorized representative during the physical inspection of any workplace under subsection (a) for the purpose of aiding such inspection. Where there is no authorized employee representative, the Secretary or his authorized representative shall consult with a reasonable number of employees concerning matters of health and safety in the workplace.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/f/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employees or representative of employees who believe that a violation of a safety or health standard exists that threatens physical harm, or that an imminent danger exists, may request an inspection by giving notice to the Secretary or his authorized representative of such violation or danger. Any such notice shall be reduced to writing, shall be set forth with reasonable particularity the grounds for the notice, and shall be signed by the employees or representative of employees, and a copy shall be provided the employer or his agent no later than at the time of inspection, except that, upon the request of the person giving such notice, his name and the names of individual employees referred to therein shall not appear in such copy or on any record published, released, or made available pursuant to subsection (g) of this section. If upon receipt of such notification the Secretary determines there are reasonable grounds to believe that such violation or danger exists, he shall make a special inspection in accordance with the provisions of this section as soon as practicable, to determine if such violation or danger exists. If the Secretary determines there are no reasonable grounds to believe that a violation or danger exists he shall notify the employees or representative of the employees in writing of such determination.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/f/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Prior to or during any inspection of a workplace, any employees or representative of employees employed in such workplace may notify the Secretary or any repesentative of the Secretary responsible for conducting the inspection, in writing, of any violation of this Act which they have reason to believe exists in such workplace. The Secretary shall, by regulation, establish procedures for informal review of any refusal by a representative of the Secretary to issue a citation with respect to any such alleged violation and shall furnish the employees or representative of employees requesting such review a written statement of the reasons for the Secretary's final disposition of the case.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/g/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary and Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare are authorized to compile, analyze, and publish, either in summary or detailed form, all reports or information obtained under this section.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/g/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall each prescribe such rules and regulations as he may deem necessary to carry out their responsibilities under this Act, including rules and regulations dealing with the inspection of an employer's establishment.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s8/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall not use the results of enforcement activities, such as the number of citations issued or penalties assessed, to evaluate employees directly involved in enforcement activities under this Act or to impose quotas or goals with regard to the results of such activities.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s657">29 U.S.C. 657</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 8, 84 Stat. 1598; amended July 16, 1998, P.L. 105–198, sec. 1, 112 Stat. 640.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s9" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">citations </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="9">Sec. 9. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s9/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If, upon inspection or investigation, the Secretary or his authorized representative believes that an employer has violated a requirement of section 5 of this Act, of any standard, rule or order promulgated pursuant to section 6 of this Act, or of any regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, he shall with reasonable promptness issue a citation to the employer. Each citation shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of the Act, standard, rule, regulation, or order alleged to have been violated. In addition, the citation shall fix a reasonable time for the abatement of the violation. The Secretary may prescribe procedures for the issuance of a notice in lieu of a citation with respect to de minimis violations which have no direct or immediate relationship to safety or health.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s9/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Each citation issued under this section, or a copy or copies thereof, shall be prominently posted, as prescribed in regulations issued by the Secretary, at or near each place a violation referred to in the citation occurred.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s9/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">No citation may be issued under this section after the expiration of six months following the occurrence of any violation.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s658">29 U.S.C. 658</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 9, 84 Stat. 1601.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s10" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">procedure for enforcement </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="10">Sec. 10. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s10/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If, after an inspection or investigation, the Secretary issues a citation under section 9(a), he shall, within a reasonable time after the termination of such inspection or investigation, notify the employer by certified mail of the penalty, if any, proposed to be assessed under section 17 and that the employer has fifteen working days within which to notify the Secretary that he wishes to contest the citation or proposed assessment of penalty. If, within fifteen working days from the receipt of the notice issued by the Secretary the employer fails to notify the Secretary that he intends to contest the citation or proposed assessment of penalty, and no notice is filed by any employee or representative of employees under subsection (c) within such time, the citation and the assessment, as proposed, shall be deemed a final order of the Commission and not subject to review by any court or agency.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s10/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If the Secretary has reason to believe that an employer has failed to correct a violation for which a citation has been issued within the period permitted for its correction (which period shall not begin to run until the entry of a final order by the Commission in the case of any review proceedings under this section initiated by the employer in good faith and not solely for delay or avoidance of penalties), the Secretary shall notify the employer by certified mail of such failure and of the penalty proposed to assessed under section 17 by reason of such failure, and that the employer has fifteen working days within which to notify the Secretary that he wishes to contest the Secretary's notification or the proposed assessment of penalty. If, within fifteen working days from the receipt of notification issued by the Secretary, the employer fails to notify the Secretary that he intends to contest the notification or proposed assessment of penalty, the notification and assessment, as proposed, shall be deemed a final order of the Commission and not subject to review by any court or agency.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s10/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If an employer notifies the Secretary that he intends to contest a citation issued under section 9(a) or notification issued under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, or if, within fifteen working days of the issuance of a citation under section 9(a), any employee or representative of employees files a notice with the Secretary alleging that the period of time fixed in the citation for the abatement of the violation is unreasonable, the Secretary shall immediately advise the Commission of such notification, and the Commission shall afford an opportunity for a hearing (in accordance with section 554 of title 5, United States Code, but without regard to subsection (a)(3) of such section). The Commission shall thereafter issue an order, based on findings of fact, affirming, modifying, or vacating the Secretary's citation or proposed penalty, or directing other appropriate relief, and such order shall become final thirty days after its issuance. Upon a showing by an employer of a good faith effort to comply with the abatement requirements of a citation, and that abatement has not been completed because of factors beyond his reasonable control, the Secretary, after an opportunity for a hearing as provided in this subsection, shall issue an order affirming or modifying the abatement requirements in such citation. The rules of procedure prescribed by the Commission shall provide affected employees or representatives of affected employees an opportunity to participate as parties to hearings under this subsection.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s659">29 U.S.C 659</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 10, 84 Stat. 1601.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">judicial review </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="11">Sec. 11. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any person adversely affected, or aggrieved by an order of the Commission issued under subsection (c) of section 10 may obtain a review of such order in any United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the violation is alleged to have occurred or where the employer has its principal office, or in the Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, by filing in such court within sixty days following the issuance of such order a written petition praying that the order be modified or set aside. A copy of such petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Commission and to the other parties, and thereupon the Commission shall file in the court and the record in the proceeding as provided in section 2112 of title 28, United States Code. Upon such filing, the court shall have jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein, and shall have power to grant such temporary relief or restraining order as it deems just and proper, and to make and enter upon the pleadings, testimony, and proceedings set forth in such record a decree affirming, modifying, or setting aside in whole or in part, the order of the Commission and enforcing the same to the extent that such order affirmed or modified. The commencement of proceedings under this subsection shall not, unless ordered by the court, operate as a stay of the order of the Commission. No objection that has not been urged before the Commission shall be considered by the court, unless the failure or neglect to urge such objection shall be excused because of extraordinary circumstances. The findings of the Commission with respect to questions of the fact, if supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive. If any party shall apply to the court for leave to adduce additional evidence and shall show to the satisfaction of the court that such additional evidence is material and that such additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for the failure to adduce such evidence in the hearing before the Commission, the court may order such additional evidence to be taken before the Commission and to be made a part of the record. The Commission may modify its findings as to the facts, or make new finding, by reason of additional evidence so taken and filed, and it shall file such modified or new findings, which findings with respect to questions of fact, is supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive, and its recommendations, if any, for the modification or setting aside of its original order. Upon the filing of the record, with it, the jurisdiction of the court shall be exclusive and its judgment and decree shall be final, except that the same shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States, as provided in section 1254 of title 28, United States Code.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary may also obtain review or enforcement of any final order of the Commission by filing a petition for such relief in the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the alleged violation occurred or in which the employer has its principal office, and the provisions of subsection (a) shall govern such proceedings to the extent applicable. If no petition for review, as provided in subsection (a), is filed within sixty days after service of the Commission's order, the Commission's findings of fact and order shall be conclusive in connection with any petition for enforcement which is filed by the Secretary after the expiration of such sixty-day period. In any such case, as well as in the case of a noncontested citation or notification by the Secretary which has become a final order of the Commission under subsection (a) or (b) of section 10, the clerk of the court, unless otherwise ordered by the court, shall forthwith enter a decree enforcing the order and shall transmit a copy of such decree to the Secretary and the employer named in the petition. In any contempt proceeding brought to enforce a decree of a court of appeals entered pursuant to this subsection or subsection (a), the court of appeals may assess the penalties provided in section 17, in addition to invoking any other available remedies.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11/c/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">No person shall discharge or in any manner discriminate against any employee because such employee has filed any complaint or instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding under or related to this Act or has testified or is about to testify in any such proceeding or because of the exercise by such employee on behalf of himself or others of any right afforded by this Act.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11/c/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employee who believes that he has been discharged or otherwise discriminated against by any person in violation of this subsection may, within thirty days after such violation occurs, file a complaint with the Secretary alleging such discrimination. Upon receipt of such complaint, the Secretary shall cause such investigation to be made as he deems appropriate. If upon such investigation, the Secretary determines that the provisions of this subsection have been violated, he shall bring an action in any appropriate United States district court against such person. In any such action the United States district courts shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown to restrain violations of paragraph (1) of this subsection and order all appropriate relief including rehiring or reinstatement of the employee to his former position with back pay.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s11/c/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Within 90 days of the receipt of a complaint filed under this subsection the Secretary shall notify the complainant of his determination under paragraph 2 of this subsection.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s660">29 U.S.C. 660</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 11, 84 Stat. 1602; amended November 8, 1984, P.L. 98–620, title IV, sec. 402(32), 98 Stat.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">the occupational safety and health review commission </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="12">Sec. 12. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission is hereby established. The Commission shall be composed of three members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among persons who by reason of training, education, or experience are qualified to carry out the functions of the Commission under this Act. The President shall designate one of the members of the Commission to serve as Chairman.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The terms of members of the Commission shall be six years except that (1) the members of the Commission first taking office shall serve, as designated by the President at the time of appointment, one for a term of two years, one for a term of four years, and one for a term of six years, and (2) a vacancy caused by the death, resignation, or removal of a member prior to the expiration of the term for which he was appointed shall be filled only for the remainder of such unexpired term. A member of the Commission may be removed by the President for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c)<ref style="-uslm-dtd:footnote-ref" idref="IDA5C58B57DC6B418F977700BDFDCB4E37" class="footnoteRef">3</ref> </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">
<elided style="-uslm-dtd:omitted-text">* * *</elided>
</content><footnote id="IDA5C58B57DC6B418F977700BDFDCB4E37" style="-uslm-dtd:footnote"><sup style="-uslm-dtd:superscript">3</sup><p style="-uslm-dtd:para; margin-left:1em">Sections 12(c) (1) and (2) of the Act amend sections 5314 and 5315 of title 5 of the United States Code.</p></footnote>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The principal office of the Commission shall be in the District of Columbia. Whenever the Commission deems that the convenience of the public or of the parties may be promoted, or delay or expense may be minimized, it may hold hearings or conduct other proceedings at any other place.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Chairman shall be responsible on behalf of the Commission for the administrative operations of the Commission and shall appoint such administrative law judges and other employees as he deems necessary to assist in the performance of the Commission's functions and to fix their compensation in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates: <i style="-uslm-dtd:italic">Provided, </i>That assignment, removal and compensation of administrative law judges shall be in accordance with sections 3105, 3344, 5362, and 7521 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">For the purpose of carrying out its functions under this Act, two members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum and official action can be taken only on the affirmative vote of at least two members.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Every official act of the Commission shall be entered of record, and its hearings and records shall be open to the public. The Commission is authorized to make such rules as are necessary for the orderly transaction of its proceedings. Unless the Commission has adopted a different rule, its proceedings shall be in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Commission may order testimony to be taken by deposition in any proceedings pending before it at any state of such proceeding. Any person may be compelled to appear and depose, and to produce books, papers, or documents, in the same manner as witnesses may be compelled to appear and testify and produce like documentary evidence before the Commission. Witnesses whose depositions are taken under this subsection, and the persons taking such depositions, shall be entitled to the same fees as are paid for like services in the courts of the United States.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/i" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="i">(i) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">For the purpose of any proceeding before the Commission, the provisions of section 11 of the National Labor Relations Act (29 U.S.C. 161) are hereby made applicable to the jurisdiction and powers of the Commission.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/j" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="j">(j) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">A administrative law judge appointed by the Commission shall hear, and make a determination upon, any proceeding instituted before the Commission and any motion in connection therewith, assigned to such administrative law judge by the Chairman of the Commission, and shall make a report of any such determination which constitutes his final disposition of the proceedings. The report of the administrative law judge shall become the final order of the Commission within thirty days after such report by the administrative law judge, unless within such period any Commission member has directed that such report shall be reviewed by the Commission.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s12/k" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="k">(k) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the administrative law judges shall be subject to the laws governing employees in the classified civil service, except that appointments shall be made without regard to section 5108 of title 5, United States Code. Each administrative law judge shall receive compensation at a rate not less than that prescribed for GS–16 under section 5332 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s661">29 U.S.C. 661</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 12, 84 Stat. 1603–1605; amended March 27, 1978, P.L. 95–251, sec. 2(a)(7), 92 Stat. 183.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s13" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">procedures to counteract imminent dangers </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="13">Sec. 13. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s13/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The United States district courts shall have jurisdiction, upon petition of the Secretary, to restrain any conditions or practices in any place of employment which are such that a danger exists which could reasonably be expected to cause death or serious physical harm immediately or before the imminence of such danger can be eliminated through the enforcement procedures otherwise provided by this Act. Any order issued under this section may require such steps to be taken as may be necessary to avoid, correct, or remove such imminent danger and prohibit the employment or presence of any individual in locations or under conditions where such imminent danger exists, except individuals whose presence is necessary to avoid, correct, or remove such imminent danger or to maintain the capacity of a continuous process operation to resume normal operations without a complete cessation of operations, or where a cessation of operations is necessary, to permit such to be accomplished in a safe and orderly manner.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s13/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Upon the filing of any such petition the district court shall have jurisdiction to grant such injunctive relief or temporary restraining order pending the outcome of an enforcement proceeding pursuant to this Act. The proceeding shall be as provided by Rule 65 of the Federal Rules, Civil Procedure, except that no temporary restraining order issued without notice shall be effective for a period longer than five days.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s13/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Whenever and as soon as an inspector concludes that conditions or practices described in subsection (a) exist in any place of employment, he shall inform the affected employees and employers of the danger and that he is recommending to the Secretary that relief be sought.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s13/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If the Secretary arbitrarily or capriciously fails to seek relief under this section, any employee who may be injured by reason of such failure, or the representative of such employees, might bring an action against the Secretary in the United States district court for the district in which the imminent danger is alleged to exist or the employer has its principal office, or for the District of Columbia, for a writ of mandamus to compel the Secretary to seek such an order and for such further relief as may be appropriate.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s662">29 U.S.C. 662</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 13, 84 Stat. 1605.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s14" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">representation in civil litigation </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="14">Sec. 14. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Except as provided in section 518(a) of title 28, United States Code, relating to litigation before the Supreme Court, the Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary in any civil litigation brought under this Act but all such litigation shall be subject to the direction and control of the Attorney General.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s663">29 U.S.C. 663</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 14, 84 Stat. 1606.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s15" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">confidentiality of trade secrets </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="15">Sec. 15. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">All information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Secretary or his representative in connection with any inspection or proceeding under the Act which contains or which might reveal a trade secret referred to in section 1905 of title 18 of the United States Code shall be considered confidential for the purpose of that section, except that such information may be disclosed to other officers or employees concerned with carrying out this Act or when relevant in any proceeding under this Act. In any such proceeding the Secretary, the Commission, or the court shall issue such orders as may be appropriate to protect the confidentiality of trade secrets.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s654">29 U.S.C. 654</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 15, 84 Stat. 1606.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s16" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">variations, tolerances, and exemptions </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="16">Sec. 16. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary, on the record, after notice and opportunity for a hearing may provide such reasonable limitations and may make such rules and regulations allowing reasonable variations, tolerances, and exemptions to and from any or all provisions of this Act as he may find necessary and proper to avoid serious impairment of the national defense. Such action shall not be in effect for more than six months without notification to affected employees and an opportunity being afforded for a hearing.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s655">29 U.S.C. 655</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 16, 84 Stat. 1606.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">penalties </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="17">Sec. 17. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer who willfully or repeatedly violates the requirements of section 5 of this Act, any standard, rule, or order promulgated pursuant to section 6 of this Act, or regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, may be assessed a civil penalty or not more than $70,000 for each violation, but not less than $5,000 for each willful violation.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer who has received a citation for a serious violation of the requirements of section 5 of this Act, of any standard, rule, or order promulgated pursuant to section 6 of this Act, or of any regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, shall be assessed a civil penalty of up to $7,000 for each such violation.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer who has received a citation for a violation of the requirements of section 5 of this Act, of any standard, rule, or order promulgated pursuant to section 6 of this Act, or of regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, and such violation is specifically determined not to be of a serious nature, may be assessed a civil penalty of up to $7,000 for each violation.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer who fails to correct a violation for which a citation has been issued under section 9(a) within the period permitted for its correction (which period shall not begin to run until the date of the final order of the Commission in the case of any review proceeding under section 10 initiated by the employer in good faith and not solely for delay or avoidance of penalties), may be assessed a civil penalty of not more than $7,000 for each day during which such failure or violation continues.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer who willfully violates any standard, rule, or order promulgated pursuant to section 6 of this Act, or of any regulations prescribed pursuant to this Act, and that violation caused death to any employee, shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine of not more than $10,000 or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or by both; except that if the conviction is for a violation committed after a first conviction of such person, punishment shall be by a fine of not more than $20,000 or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or by both.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any person who gives advance notice of any inspection to be conducted under this Act, without authority from the Secretary or his designees, shall upon conviction, be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or by both.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Whoever knowingly makes any false statement, representation, or certification in any application, record, report, plan, or other document filed or required to be maintained pursuant to this Act shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine of not more than $10,000, or by imprisonment for not more than six months, or by both.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/h/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Section 1114 of title 18, United States Code, is hereby amended by striking out “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">designated by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare to conduct investigations, or inspections under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</quotedText>” and inserting in lieu thereof “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">or of the Department of Labor assigned to perform investigative, inspection, or law enforcement functions</quotedText>”.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/h/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 1111 and 1114 of title 18, United States Code, whoever, in violation of the provisions of section 1114 of such title, kills a person while engaged in or on account of the performance of investigative, inspection, or law enforcement functions added to such section 1114 by paragraph (1) of this subsection, and who would otherwise be subject to the penalty provisions of such section 1111, shall be punished by imprisonment for any term of years or for life.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/i" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="i">(i) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any employer who violates of the posting requirements, as prescribed under the provisions of this Act, shall be assessed a civil penalty of up to $7,000 for each violation.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/j" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="j">(j) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Commission shall have authority to assess all civil penalties provided in this section, giving due consideration to the appropriateness of the penalty with respect to the size of the business of the employer being charged, the gravity of the violation, the good faith of the employer, and the history of previous violations.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/k" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="k">(k) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">For purposes of this section, a serious violation shall be deemed to exist in a place of employment if there is a substantial probability that death or serious physical harm could result from a condition which exists, or from one or more practices, means, methods, operations, or processes which have been adopted or are in use, in such place of employment unless the employer did not, and could not with the exercise of reasonable diligence, know of the presence of the violation.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s17/l" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="l">(l) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Civil penalties owed under this Act shall be paid to the Secretary for deposit into the Treasury of the United States and shall accrue to the United States and may be recovered in a civil action in the name of the United States brought in the United States district court for the district where the violation is alleged to have occurred or where the employer has its principal office.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s666">29 U.S.C. 666</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 17, 84 Stat. 1606, 1607, amended November 5, 1990, P.O. 101–508, sec. 3101, 104 Stat. 1388–29.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">state jurisdiction and state plans </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="18">Sec. 18. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Nothing in this Act shall prevent any State agency or court from asserting jurisdiction under State law over any occupational safety or health issue with respect to which no standard is in effect under section 6.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any State which, at any time, desires to assume responsibility for development and enforcement therein of occupational safety and health standards relating to any occupational safety or health issue with respect to which a Federal standard has been promulgated under section 6 shall submit a State plan for the development of such standards and their enforcement.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall approve the plan submitted by a State under subsection (b), or any modification thereof, if such a plan in his judgment—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">designates a State agency or agencies as the agency or agencies responsible for administering the plan throughout the State,</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">provides for the development and enforcement of safety and health standards relating to one or more safety or health issues, which standards (and the enforcement of which standards) are or will be at least as effective in providing safe and healthful employment and places of employment as the standards promulgated under section 6 which relate to the same issues, and which standards, when applicable to products which are distributed or used in interstate commerce, are required by compelling local conditions and do not unduly burden interstate commerce,</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/3" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">provides for a right of entry and inspection of all workplaces subject to the Act which is at least as effective as that provided in section 8, and includes a prohibition on advance notice of inspections,</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/4" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">contains satisfactory assurances that such agency or agencies have or will have the legal authority and qualified personnel necessary for the enforcement of such standards,</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/5" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">gives satisfactory assurances that such State will devote adequate funds to the administration and enforcement of such standards,</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/6" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">contains satisfactory assurances that such State will, to the extent permitted by its law, establish and maintain an effective and comprehensive occupational safety and health program applicable to all employees of public agencies of the State and its political subdivisions, which program is as effective as the standards contained in an approved plan,</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/7" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">requires employers in the State to make reports to the Secretary in the same manner and to the same extent as if the plan were not in effect, and</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/c/8" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="8">(8) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">provides that the State agency will make such reports to the Secretary in such form and containing such information, as the Secretary shall from time to time require.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If the Secretary rejects a plan submitted under subsection (b), he shall afford the State submitting the plan due notice and opportunity for a hearing before so doing.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">After the Secretary approves a State plan submitted under subsection (b), he may, but shall not be required to, exercise his authority under sections 8, 9, 10, 13, and 17 with respect to comparable standards promulgated under section 6, for the period specified in the next sentence. The Secretary may exercise the authority referred to above until he determines, on the basis of actual operations under the State plan, that the criteria set forth in subsection (c) are being applied, but he shall not make such determination for at least three years after the plan's approval under subsection (c). Upon making the determination referred to in the preceding sentence, the provisions of sections 5(a)(2), 8 (except for the purpose of carrying out subsection (f) of this section), 9, 10, 13, and 17, and standards promulgated under section 6 of this Act, shall not apply with respect to any occupational safety or health issues covered under the plan, but the Secretary may retain jurisdiction under the above provisions in any proceeding commenced under section 9 or 10 before the date of determination.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall, on the basis of reports submitted by the State agency and his own inspections make a continuing evaluation of the manner in which each State having a plan approved under this section is carrying out such plan. Whenever the Secretary finds, after affording due notice and opportunity for a hearing, that in the administration of the State plan there is a failure to comply substantially with any provision of the State plan (or any assurance contained therein), he shall notify the State agency of his withdrawal of approval of such plan and upon receipt of such notice such plan shall cease to be in effect, but the State may retain jurisdiction in any case commenced before the withdrawal of the plan in order to enforce standards under the plan whenever the issues involved do not relate to the reasons for the withdrawal of the plan.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The State may obtain a review of a decision of the Secretary withdrawing approval of or rejecting its plan by the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the State is located by filing in such court within thrity days following receipt of notice of such decision a petition to modify or set aside in whole or in part the action of the Secretary. A copy of such petition shall forthwith be served upon the Secretary, and thereupon the Secretary shall certify and file in the court the record upon which the decision complained of was issued as provided in section 2112 of title 28, United States Code. Unless the court finds that the Secretary's decision in rejecting a proposed State plan or withdrawing his approval of such a plan is not supported by substantial evidence the court shall affirm the Secretary's decision. The judgment of the court shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon certiorari or certification as provided in section 1254 of title 28, United States Code.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s18/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary may enter into an agreement with a State under which the State will be permitted to continue to enforce one or more occupational health and safety standards in effect in such State until final action is taken by the Secretary with respect to a plan submitted by a State under subsection (b) of this section, or two years from the date of enactment of this Act, whichever is earlier.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s667">29 U.S.C. 667</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 18, 84 Stat. 1608.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">federal agency safety programs and responsibilities </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="19">Sec. 19. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">It shall be the responsibility of the head of each Federal agency (not including the United States Postal Service) to establish and maintain an effective and comprehensive occupational safety and health program which is consistent with the standards promulgated under section 6. The head of each agency shall (after consultation with representatives of the employees thereof)—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/a/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">provide safe and healthful places and conditions of employment, consistent with the standards set under section 6;</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/a/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">acquire, maintain, and require the use of safety equipment, personal protective equipment, and devices reasonably necessary to protect employees;</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/a/3" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">keep adequate records of all occupational accidents and illnesses for proper evaluation and necessary corrective action;</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/a/4" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">consult with the Secretary with regard to the adequacy as to form and content of records kept pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section; and</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/a/5" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">make an annual report to the Secretary with respect to occupational accidents and injuries and the agency's program under this section. Such report shall include any report submitted under section 7902(e)(2) of title 5, United States Code.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall report to the President a summary or digest of reports submitted to him under subsection (a)(5) of this section, together with his evaluations of and recommendations derived from such reports.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Section 7902(c)(1) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">agencies</quotedText>” the following: “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">and of labor organizations representing employees</quotedText>”.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s19/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall have access to records and reports kept and filed by Federal agencies pursuant to subsections (a) (3) and (5) of this section unless those records and reports are specifically required by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of the national defense or foreign policy, in which case the Secretary shall have access to such information as will not jeopardize national defense or foreign policy.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s668">29 U.S.C. 668</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 17, 84 Stat. 1609; amended December 21, 1982, P.L. 97–375, title I, sec. 110(c), 96 Stat. 1821.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">research and related activities </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="20">Sec. 20. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, after consultation with the Secretary and with other appropriate Federal departments or agencies, shall conduct (directly or by grants or contracts) research, experiments, and demonstrations relating to occupational safety and health, including studies of psychological factors involved, and relating to innovative methods techniques, and approaches for dealing with occupational safety and health problems.</content></paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall from time to time consult with the Secretary in order to develop specific plans for such research, demonstrations, and experiments as are necessary to produce criteria, including criteria identifying toxic substances, enabling the Secretary to meet his responsibility for the formulation of safety and health standards under this Act; and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, on the basis of such research, demonstrations, and experiments and any other information available to him, shall develop and publish at least annually such criteria as will effectuate the purposes of this Act.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, on the basis of such research, demonstrations, and experiments, and any other information available to him, shall develop criteria dealing with toxic materials and harmful physical agents and substances which will describe exposure levels that are safe for various periods of employment, including but not limited to the exposure levels at which no employee will suffer impaired health or functional capacities or diminished life expectancy as a result of his work experience.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/4" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall also conduct special research, experiments, and demonstrations relating to occupational safety and health as are necessary to explore new problems, including those created by new technology in occupational safety and health, which may require ameliorative action beyond that which is otherwise provided for in the operating provisions of this Act. The Secretary of Health, Education, and Wefare shall also conduct research into the motivational and behavioral factors relating to the field of occupational safety and health.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/5" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, in order to comply with his responsibilities under paragraph (2) and in order to develop needed information regarding potentially toxic substances or harmful physical agents, may prescribe regulations requiring employers to measure, record, and make reports on the exposure of employees to substances or physical agents which the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare reasonably believes may endanger the health or safety of employees. The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare also is authorized to establish such programs of medical examinations and tests as may be necessary for determining the incidence of occupational illnesses and the susceptibility of employees to such illnesses. Nothing in this or any other provision of this Act shall be deemed to authorize or require medical examination, immunization, or treatment for those who object thereto on religious grounds, except where such is necessary for the protection of the health or safety of others. Upon the request of any employer who is required to measure and record exposure of employees to substances or physical agents as provided under this subsection, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall furnish full financial or other assistance to such employer for the purpose of defraying any additional expense incurred by him in carying out the measuring and recording as provided in this subsection.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/6" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall publish within six months of enactment of this Act and thereafter as needed but at least annually a list of all known toxic substances by generic family or other useful grouping, and the concentrations at which such toxicity is known to occur. He shall determine following a written request by any employer or authorized representative of employees, specifying with reasonable particularity the grounds on which the request is made, whether any substance normally found in the place of employment has potentially toxic effects in such concentrations as used or found; and shall submit such determination both to employers and affected employees as soon as possible. If the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare determines that any substance is potentially toxic at the concentrations in which it is used or found in a place of employment, and such substance is not covered by an occupational safety or health standard promulgated under section 6, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall immediately submit such determination to the Secretary, together with all pertinent criteria.</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/a/7" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Within two years of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall conduct and publish industrywide studies of the effect of chronic or low-level exposure to industrial materials, processes, and stresses on the potential for illness, disease, or loss of functional capacity in aging adults.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare is authorized to make inspections and question employers and employees as provided in section 8 of this Act in order to carry out his functions and responsibilities under this section.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts, agreements, or other arrangements with appropriate public agencies or private organizations for the purpose of conducting studies relating to his responsibilities under this Act. In carrying out his responsibilities under this subsection, the Secretary shall cooperate with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare in order to avoid any duplication of efforts under this section.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Information obtained by the Secretary and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under this section shall be disseminated by the Secretary to employers and employees and organizations thereof.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s20/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under this Act shall, to the extent feasible, be delegated to the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health established by section 22 of this Act.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s669">29 U.S.C. 669</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 20, 84 Stat. 1610.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">training and employee education </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="21">Sec. 21. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, after consultation with the Secretary and with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, shall conduct, directly or by grants or contracts (1) education programs to provide an adequate supply of qualified personnel to carry out the purposes of this Act, and (2) informational programs on the importance of and proper use of adquate safety and health equipment.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary is also authorized to conduct, directly or by grants or contracts, short-term training of personnel engaged in work related to his responsibilities under this Act.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, shall (1) provide for the estabishment and supervision of programs for the education and training of employers and employees in the recognition, avoidance, and prevention of unsafe or unhealthful working conditions in employments covered by this Act, and (2) consult with and advise employers and employees, and organizations representing employers and employees as to effective means of preventing occupational injuries and illnesses.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall establish and support cooperative agreements with the States under which employers subject to this Act may consult with State personnel with respect to—</chapeau>
                <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/1/A" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">the application of occupational safety and health requirements under this Act or under State plans approved under section 18; and</content>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/1/B" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">voluntary efforts that employers may undertake to establish and maintain safe and healthful employment and places of employment.</content>
                </subparagraph><continuation style="-uslm-dtd:continuation-text" role="paragraph">Such agreements may provide, as a condition of receiving funds under such agreements, for contributions by States towards meeting the costs of such agreements.</continuation></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Pursuant to such agreements the State shall provide on-site consultation at the employer's worksite to employers who request such assistance. The State may also provide other education and training programs for employers and employees in the State. The State shall ensure that on-site consultations conducted pursuant to such agreements include provision for the participation by employees.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Activities under this subsection shall be conducted independently of any enforcement activity. If an employer fails to take immediate action to eliminate employee exposure to an imminent danger identified in a consultation or fails to correct a serious hazard so identified within a reasonable time, a report shall be made to the appropriate enforcement authority for such action as is appropriate.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/4" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall, by regulation after notice and opportunity for comment, establish rules under which an employer—</chapeau>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/4/A" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">which requests and undergoes an on-site consultative visit provided under this subsection;</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/4/B" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">which corrects the hazards that have been identified during the visit within the time frames established by the State and agrees to request a subsequent consultative visit if major changes in working conditions or work processes occur which introduce new hazards in the workplace; and</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/4/C" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="C">(C) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">which is implementing procedures for regularly identifying and preventing hazards regulated under this Act and maintains appropriate involvement of, and training for, management and non-management employees in achieving safe and healthful working conditions,</content>
                    </subparagraph><continuation style="-uslm-dtd:continuation-text" role="paragraph">may be exempt from an inspection (except an inspection requested under section 8(f) or an inspection to determine the cause of a workplace accident which resulted in the death of one or more employees or hospitalization for three or more employees) for a period of 1 year from the closing of the consultative visit.</continuation>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s21/d/5" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">A State shall provide worksite consultations under paragraph (2) at the request of an employer. Priority in scheduling such consultations shall be assigned to requests from small businesses which are in higher hazard industries or have the most hazardous conditions at issue in the request.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s670">29 U.S.C. 670</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 21, 84 Stat. 1612; amended July 16, 1998, P.L. 105–197, sec. 2, 112 Stat. 638.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">national institute for occupational safety and health </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="22">Sec. 22. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">It is the purpose of this section to establish a National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare in order to carry out the policy set froth in section 2 of this Act and to perform the functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under sections 20 and 21 of this Act.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There is hereby established in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare a National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health. The Institute shall be headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, and who shall serve for a term of six years unless previously removed by the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Institute is authorized to—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/c/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">develop and establish recommended occupational safety and health standards; and</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/c/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">perform all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under sections 20 and 21 of this Act.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Upon his own initiative, or upon the request of the Secretary or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Director is authorized (1) to conduct such research and experimental programs as he determines are necessary for the development of criteria for new and improved occupational safety and health standards, and (2) after consideration of the results of such research and experimental programs make recommendations concerning new or improved occupational safety and health standards. Any occupational safety and health standard recommended pursuant to this section shall immediately be forwarded to the Secretary of Labor, and to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">In addition to any authority vested in the Institute by the other provisions of this section, the Director, in carrying out the functions of the Institute, is authorized to—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary governing the manner in which its functions shall be carried out;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">receive money and other property donated, bequeathed, or devised, without condition or restriction other than that it be used for the purposes of the Institute and to use, sell, or otherwise dispose of such property for the purpose of carrying out its functions;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/3" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">receive (and use, sell, or otherwise dispose of, in accordance with paragraph (2)), money and other property donated, bequeathed, or devised to the Institute with a condition or restriction, including a condition that the Institute use other funds of the Institute for the purposes of the gift;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/4" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">in accordance with the civil service laws, appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/5" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of section 3109 of title 5, United States Code;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/6" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">accept and utilize the services of voluntary and noncompensated personnel and reimburse them for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized by section 5703 of title 5, United States Code;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/7" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">enter into contracts, grants or other arrangements, or modifications thereof to carry out the provisions of this section, and such contracts or modifications thereof may be entered into without performance of other bonds, and without regard to section 3709 of the Revised Statutes, as amended (41 U.S.C. 5), or any other provision of law relating to competitive bidding;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/8" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="8">(8) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">make advance, progress, and other payments which the Director deems necessary under this title without regard to the provisions of section 3648 of the Revised Statutes, as amended (31 U.S.C. 529); and</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/e/9" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="9">(9) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">made other necessary expenditures.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Director shall submit to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, to the President, and to the Congress an annual report of the operations of the Institute under this Act, which shall include a detailed statement of all private and public funds received and expended by it, and such recommendations as he deemd appropriate.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Lead-Based Paint Activities.—</heading>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Training grant program.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1/A" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Institute, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, may make grants for the training and education of workers and supervisors who are or may be directly engaged in lead-based paint activities.</content></subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1/B" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">Grants referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be awarded to nonprofit organizations (including colleges and universities, joint labor-management trust funds, States, and nonprofit government employee organizations)—</chapeau>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1/B/i" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="i">(i) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">which are engaged in the training and education of workers and supervisors who are or who may be directly engaged in lead-based paint activities (as defined in title IV of the Toxic Substances Control Act),</content>
                        </clause>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1/B/ii" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="ii">(ii) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">which have demonstrated experience in implementing and operating health and safety training and education programs, and</content>
                        </clause>
                        <clause style="-uslm-dtd:clause" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1/B/iii" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="iii">(iii) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">with a demonstrated ability to reach, and involve in lead-based paint training programs, target populations of individuals who are or will be engaged in lead-based paint activities.</content>
                        </clause><continuation style="-uslm-dtd:continuation-text" role="subparagraph">Grants under this subsection shall be awarded only to those organizations that fund at least 30 percent of their lead-based paint activities training programs from non-Federal sources, excluding in-kind contributions. Grants may also be made to local governments to carry out such training and education for their employees.</continuation>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/1/C" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="C">(C) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There are authorized to be appropriated, at a minimum, $10,000,000 to the Institute for each of the fiscal years 1994 through 1997 to make grants under this paragraph.</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/g/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Evaluation of programs.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Institute shall conduct periodic and comprehensive assessments of the efficacy of the worker and supervisor training programs developed and offered by those receiving grants under this section. The Director shall prepare reports on the results of these assessments addressed to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to include recommendations as may be appropriate for the revision of these programs. The sum of $500,000 is authorized to be appropriated to the Institute for each of the fiscal years 1994 through 1997 to carry out this paragraph.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Office of Mine Safety and Health.—</heading>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">In general.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There shall be permanently established within the Institute an Office of Mine Safety and Health which shall be administered by an Associate Director to be appointed by the Director.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Purpose.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The purpose of the Office is to enhance the development of new mine safety technology and technological applications and to expedite the commercial availability and implementation of such technology in mining environments.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/3" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Functions.—</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">In addition to all purposes and authorities provided for under this section, the Office of Mine Safety and Health shall be responsible for research, development, and testing of new technologies and equipment designed to enhance mine safety and health. To carry out such functions the Director of the Institute, acting through the Office, shall have the authority to—</chapeau>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/3/A" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">award competitive grants to institutions and private entities to encourage the development and manufacture of mine safety equipment;</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/3/B" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">award contracts to educational institutions or private laboratories for the performance of product testing or related work with respect to new mine technology and equipment; and</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/3/C" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="C">(C) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">establish an interagency working group as provided for in paragraph (5).</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/4" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Grant authority.—</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">To be eligible to receive a grant under the authority provided for under paragraph (3)(A), an entity or institution shall—</chapeau>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/4/A" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">submit to the Director of the Institute an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require; and</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/4/B" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">include in the application under subparagraph (A), a description of the mine safety equipment to be developed and manufactured under the grant and a description of the reasons that such equipment would otherwise not be developed or manufactured, including reasons relating to the limited potential commercial market for such equipment.</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/5" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="5">(5) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Interagency working group.—</heading>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/5/A" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Establishment.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Director of the Institute, in carrying out paragraph (3)(D) shall establish an interagency working group to share technology and technological research and developments that could be utilized to enhance mine safety and accident response.</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/5/B" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Membership.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The working group under subparagraph (A) shall be chaired by the Associate Director of the Office who shall appoint the members of the working group, which may include representatives of other Federal agencies or departments as determined appropriate by the Associate Director.</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/5/C" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="C">(C) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Duties.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The working group under subparagraph (A) shall conduct an evaluation of research conducted by, and the technological developments of, agencies and departments who are represented on the working group that may have applicability to mine safety and accident response and make recommendations to the Director for the further development and eventual implementation of such technology.</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/6" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">(6) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Annual report.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the Office under this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Institute shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives a report that, with respect to the year involved, describes the new mine safety technologies and equipment that have been studied, tested, and certified for use, and with respect to those instances of technologies and equipment that have been considered but not yet certified for use, the reasons therefore.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s22/h/7" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="7">(7) </num><heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">Authorization of appropriations.—</heading><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There is authorized to be appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to enable the Institute and the Office of Mine Safety and Health to carry out this subsection.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s671">29 U.S.C. 671</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 22, 84 Stat. 1612; amended October 28, 1992, P.L. 102–550, sec. 1033, 106 Stat. 3924; June 15, 2006, P.L. 109–236, sec. 6(a), 120 Stat. 498.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">grants to the states </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="23">Sec. 23. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary is authorized, during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1971, and the two succeeding fiscal years, to make grants to the States which have designated a State agency under section 18 to assist them—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">in identifying their needs and responsibilities in the area of occupational safety and health,</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">in developing State plans under section 18, or</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a/3" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">in developing plans for—</chapeau>
                <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a/3/A" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">establishing systems for the collection of information concerning the nature and frequency of occupational injuries and diseases;</content>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a/3/B" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">increasing the expertise and enforcement capabilities of their personnel engaged in occupational safety and health programs; or</content>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/a/3/C" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="C">(C) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">otherwise improving the administration and enforcement of State occupational safety and health laws, including standards thereunder, consistent with the objectives of this Act.</content>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary is authorized, during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1971, and the two succeeding fiscal years, to make grants to the States for experimental and demonstration projects consistent with the objectives set forth in subsection (a) of this section.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Governor of the State shall designate the appropriate State agency for receipt of any grant made by the Secretary under this section.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any State agency designated by the Governor of the State desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application therefor to the Secretary.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary shall review the application, and shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, approve or reject such application.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Federal share for each State grant under subsection (a) or (b) of this section may not exceed 90 per centum of the total cost of the application. In the event the Federal share for all States under either such subsection is not the same, the differences among the States shall be established on the basis of objective criteria.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary is authorized to make grants to the States to assist them in administering and enforcing programs for occupational safety and health contained in State plans approved by the Secretary pursuant to section 18 of this Act. The Federal share for each State grant under this subsection may not exceed 50 per centum of the total cost to the State of such a program. The last sentence of subsection (f) shall be applicable in determining the Federal share under this subsection.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s23/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Prior to June 30, 1973, the Secretary shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, transmit a report to the President and to the Congress, describing the experience under the grant programs authorized by this section and making any recommendations he may deem appropriate.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s672">29 U.S.C. 672</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 23, 84 Stat. 1613.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">statistics </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="24">Sec. 24. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">In order to further the purposes of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, shall develop and maintain an effective program of collection, compilation, and analysis of occupational safety and health statistics. Such program may cover all employments whether or not subject to any other provisions of this Act but shall not cover employments excluded by section 4 of the Act. The Secretary shall compile accurate statistics on work injuries and illnesses which shall include all disabling, serious, or significant injuries and illnesses, whether or not involving loss of time from work, other than minor injuries requiring only first aid treatment and which do not involve medical treatment, loss of consciousness, restriction of work or motion, or transfer to another job.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">To carry out his duties under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary may—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/b/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">promote, encourage, or directly engage in programs of studies, information and communication concerning occupational safety and health statistics;</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/b/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">make grants to States or political subdivisions thereof in order to assist them in developing and administering programs dealing with occupational safety and health statistics; and</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/b/3" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">arrange, through grants or contracts, for the conduct of such research and investigations as give promise of furthering the objectives of this section.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Federal share for each grant under subsection (b) of this section may be up to 50 per centum of the State's total cost.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary may, with the consent of any State or political subdivision thereof, accept and use the services, facilities, and employees of the agencies of such State or political subdivision, with or without reimbursement, in order to assist him in carrying out his functions under this section.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">On the basis of the records made and kept pursuant to section 8(c) of this Act, employers shall file such reports with the Secretary as he shall prescribe by regulation, as necessary to carry out his functions under this Act.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s24/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Agreements between the Department of Labor and States pertaining to the collection of occupational safety and health statistics already in effect on the effective date of this Act shall remain in effect until superseded by grants or contracts made under this Act.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s673">29 U.S.C. 673</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 24, 84 Stat. 1614.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s25" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">audits </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="25">Sec. 25. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s25/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Each recipient of a grant under this Act shall keep such records as the Secretary or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such grant, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which such grant is made or used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s25/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Secretary or the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients of any grant under this Act that are pertinent to any such grant.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s674">29 U.S.C. 674</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 25, 84 Stat. 1615.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s26" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">annual report </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="26">Sec. 26. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Within one hundred and twenty days following the convening of each regular session of each Congress, the Secretary and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall each prepare and submit to the President for transmittal to the Congress a report upon the subject matter of this Act, the progress toward achievement of the purpose of this Act, the needs and requirements in the field of occupational safety and health, and any other relevant information. Such reports shall include information regarding occupational safety and health standards, and criteria for such standards, developed during the preceding year; evaluation of standards and criteria previously developed under this Act, defining areas of emphasis for new criteria and standards; an evaluation of the degree of observance of applicable occupational safety and health standards, and a summary of inspection and enforcement activity undertaken; analysis and evaluation of research activities for which results have been obtained under governmental and nongovernmental sponsorship; an analysis of major occupational diseases; evaluation of available control and measurement technology for hazards for which standards or criteria have been developed during the preceding year; description of cooperative efforts undertaken between Government agencies and other interested parties in the implementation of this Act during the preceding year; a progress report on the development of an adequate supply of trained manpower in the field of occupational safety and health, including estimates of future needs and the efforts being made by Government and others to meet those needs; listing of all toxic substances in industrial usage for which labeling requirements, criteria, or standards have not yet been established; and such recommendations for additional legislation as are deemed necessary to protect the safety and health of the worker and improve the administration of this Act.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s675">29 U.S.C. 675</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 26, 84 Stat. 1615.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">national commission on state workmen's compensation laws </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="27">Sec. 27. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/a/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Congress hereby finds and declares that—</chapeau>
            <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/a/1/A" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">the vast majority of American workers, and their families, are dependent on workmen's compensation for their basic economic security in the event such workers suffer disabling injury or death in the course of their employment; and that the full protection of American workers from job-related injury or death requires an adequate, prompt, and equitable system of workmen's compensation as well as an effective program of occupational health and safety regulation; and</content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/a/1/B" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">in recent years serious questions have been raised concerning the fairness and adequacy of present workmen's compensation laws in the light of the growth of the economy, the changing nature of the labor force, increases in medical knowledge, changes in the hazards associated with various types of employment, new technology creating new risks to health and safety, and increases in the general level of wages and the cost of living.</content>
            </subparagraph></paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/a/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The purposes of this section is to authorize an effective study and objective evaluation of State workmen's compensation laws in order to determine if such laws provide an adequate, prompt, and equitable system of compensation for injury or death arising out of or in the course of employment.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There is hereby established a National Commission on State Workmen's Compensation Laws.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/c/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Workmen's Compensation Commission shall be composed of fifteen members to be appointed by the President from among members of State Workmen's compensation boards, representatives of insurance carriers, business, labor, members of the medical profession having experience in industrial medicine or in workmen's compensation cases, educators having a special expertise in the field of workmen's compensation, and representatives of the general public. The Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall be ex officio members of the Workmen's Compensation Commission:</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/c/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Any vacancy in the Workmen's Compensation Commission shall not affect its powers.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/c/3" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The President shall designate one of the members to serve as Chairman and one to serve as Vice Chairman of the Workmen's Compensation Commission.</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/c/4" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="4">(4) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Eight members of the Workmen's Compensation Commission shall constitute a quroum.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/d/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Workmen's Compensation Commission shall undertake a comprehensive study and evaluation of State Workmen's compensation laws in order to determine if such laws provide an adequate, prompt, and equitable system of compensation. Such study and evaluation shall include, without being limited to, the following subjects: (A) the amount and duration of permanent and temporary disability benefits and the criteria for determining the maximum, limitations thereon, (B) the amount and duration of medical benefits and provisions insuring adequate medical care and free choice of physician, (C) the extent of coverage of workers, including exemptions based on numbers or type of employment, (D) standards for determining which injuries or diseases should be deemed compensable, (E) rehabilitation, (F) coverage under second or subsequent injury funds, (G) time limits on filing claims, (H) waiting periods, (I) compulsory or elective coverage, (J) administration, (K) legal expenses, (L) the feasibility and desirability of a uniform system of reporting information concerning job-related injuries and diseases and the operation of workmen's compensation laws, (M) the resolution of conflict of laws, extraterritoriality and similar problems arising from claims with multistate aspects, (N) the extent to which private insurance carriers are excluded from supplying workmen's compensation coverage and the desirability of such exclusionary practices, to the extent they are found to exist, (O) the relationship, between workmen's compensation on the one hand, and old-age, disability, and survivors insurance and other types of insurance, public or private, on the other hand, (P) methods of implementing the recommendations of the Commission.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/d/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Workmen's Compensation Commission shall transmit to the President and to the Congress not later than July 31, 1972, a final report containing a detailed statement to the findings and conclusions of the Commission, together with such recommendations as it deems advisable.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/e" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/e/1" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Workmen's Compensation Commission or, on the authorization of the Workmen's Compensation Commission, any subcommittee or members thereof, may, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this title, hold such hearings, take such testimony, and sit and act at such times and places as the Workmen's Compensation Commission deems advisable. Any member authorized by the Workmen's Compensation Commission may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Workmen's Compensation Commission or any subcommittee or members thereof.</content></paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/e/2" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Each department, agency, and instrumentality of the executive branch of the Government, including independent agencies, is authorized and directed to furnish to the Workmen's Compensation Commission, upon request made by the Chairman or Vice Chairman, such information as the Workmen's Compensation Commission deems necessary to carry out its function under this section.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/f" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="f">(f) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">Subject to such rules and regulations as may be adopted by the Workmen's Compensation Commission, the Chairman shall have the power to—</chapeau>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/f/1" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">appoint and fix the compensation of an executive director, and such additional staff personnel as he deems necessary, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, but at rates not in excess of the maximum rate for GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title, and</content>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/f/2" styleType="OLC">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">procure temporary and intermittent services to the same extent as is authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/g" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="g">(g) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The Workmen's Compensation Commission is authorized to enter into contracts with Federal or State agencies, private firms, institutions, and individuals for the conduct of research or surveys, the preparation of reports, and other activities necessary to the discharge of its duties.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/h" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="h">(h) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Members of the Workmen's Compensation Commission shall receive compensation for each day they are engaged in the performance of their duties as members of the Workmen's Compensation Commission at the daily rate prescribed for GS–18 under section 5332 of title 5, United States Code, and shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as members of the Workmen's Compensation Commission.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/i" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="i">(i) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</content>
            </subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s27/j" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="j">(j) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">On the ninetieth day after the date of submission of its final report to the President, the Workmen's Compensation Commission shall cease to exist.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s676">29 U.S.C. 676</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 27, 84 Stat. 1616.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">economic assistance to small business </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="28">Sec. 28. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">Section 7(b) of the Small Business Act, as amended, is amended—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28/a/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by striking out the period at the end of “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">paragraph (5)</quotedText>” and inserting in lieu thereof “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">; and</quotedText>”; and</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28/a/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by adding after paragraph (5) a new paragraph as follows:<quotedContent style="-uslm-dtd:quoted-block">
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="6">“(6) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">to make such loans (either directly or in cooperation with banks or other lending institutions through agreements to participate on an immediate or deferred basis) as the Administration may determine to be necessary or appropriate to assist any small business concern in effecting additions to or alterations in the equipment facilities, or methods of operation of such business in order to comply with the applicable standards promulgated pursuant to section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 or standards adopted by a State pursuant to a plan approved under section 18 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, if the Administration determines that such concern is likely to suffer substantial economic injury without assistance under this paragraph.”</content>
                </paragraph></quotedContent>
</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28/b" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">The third sentence of section 7(b) of the Small Business Act, as amended, is amended by striking out “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">or (5)</quotedText>” after “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">paragraph (3)</quotedText>” and inserting a comma followed by “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">(5) or (6)</quotedText>”.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1636">15 U.S.C. 1636</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28/c" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="c">(c) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Section 4(c)(1) of the Small Business Act, as amended, is amended by inserting “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">&amp;(b)(6),</quotedText>” after “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">7(b)(5),</quotedText>”.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1633">15 U.S.C. 1633</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s28/d" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="d">(d) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Loans may also be made or guaranteed for the purposes set forth in section 7(b)(6) of the Small Business Act, as amended, pursuant to the provisions of section 202 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965, as amended.</content>
            </subsection><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3142–1">42 U.S.C. 3142–1</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 28, 84 Stat. 1618.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s29" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">additional assistant secretary of labor </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="29">Sec. 29. </num><subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s29/a" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="a">(a) </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">Section 2 of the Act of April 17, 1946 (60 Stat. 91) as amended (29 U.S.C. 553) is amended by—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s29/a/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">striking out “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">four</quotedText>” in the first sentence of such section and inserting in lieu thereof “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">five</quotedText>”; and</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s29/a/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">adding at the end thereof the following new sentence, “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">One of such Assistant Secretaries shall be an Assistant Secretary of Labor for Occupational Safety and Health.</quotedText>”.</content>
            </paragraph></subsection>
            <subsection style="-uslm-dtd:subsection" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s29/b" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentDecrease1">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="b">(b) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">Paragraph (20) of section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking out “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">(4)</quotedText>” and inserting in lieu thereof “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">(5)</quotedText>”.</content>
            </subsection><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 29, 84 Stat. 1618.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s30" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">additional positions </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="30">Sec. 30. </num><chapeau style="-uslm-dtd:text">Section 5108(c) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by—</chapeau>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s30/1" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="1">(1) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">striking out the word “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">and</quotedText>” at the end of paragraph (8);</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s30/2" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="2">(2) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">striking out the period at the end of paragraph (9) and inserting in lieu thereof a semicolon and the word “<quotedText style="-uslm-dtd:quote">and</quotedText>”; and</content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s30/3" styleType="OLC">
                <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="3">(3) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">by adding immediately after paragraph (9) the following new paragraph:<quotedContent style="-uslm-dtd:quoted-block">
                <paragraph style="-uslm-dtd:paragraph" styleType="OLC" class="leftIndentIncrease1">
                    <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="10">“(10)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" styleType="OLC" class="inline"><num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="A">(A) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">the Secretary of Labor, subject to the standards and procedures prescribed by this chapter, may place an additional twenty-five positions an the Department of Labor in GS–16, 17, and 18 for the purposes of carrying out his responsibilities under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970;</content></subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph style="-uslm-dtd:subparagraph" styleType="OLC">
                        <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="B">“(B) </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, subject to the standards and procedures prescribed by this chapter, may place ten positions in GS–16, 17, and 18 in carrying out its functions under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970.”</content>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph></quotedContent>
</content>
            </paragraph><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5108">5 U.S.C. 5108</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 29, 84 Stat. 1619.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s31" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">emergency locator beacons </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="31">Sec. 31. </num><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:legis-comment"><b>[</b>Omitted—Section 31 amends section 601 of the Federal Aviation Act of 1958, relating to emergency locator beacons.<b>]</b> </editorialNote>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s32" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">separability </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="32">Sec. 32. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person of circumstance, shall be held invalid, the remainder of this Act, or the application of such provision to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is held invalid, shall not be affected thereby.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s677">29 U.S.C. 677</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 32, 84 Stat. 1619.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s33" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">appropriations </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="33">Sec. 33. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act for each fiscal year such sums as the Congress shall deem necessary.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s678">29 U.S.C. 678</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 33, 84 Stat. 1620.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
        <section style="-uslm-dtd:section" identifier="/us/sComp/91/596/s34" styleType="traditional">
            <heading style="-uslm-dtd:header">effective date </heading>
            <num style="-uslm-dtd:enum" value="34">Sec. 34. </num><content style="-uslm-dtd:text">This Act shall take effect one hundred and twenty days after the date of its enactment.</content><editorialNote style="-uslm-dtd:usc-reference" role="uscRef"><b>[</b><ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651nt">29 U.S.C. 651nt</ref><b>]</b> </editorialNote><sourceCredit style="-uslm-dtd:legis-history-note">Enacted December 29, 1970, P.L. 91–596, sec. 34, 84 Stat. 1620.</sourceCredit>
        </section>
    </main>
</statuteCompilation>
