<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><resolution xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:uslm="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm uslm-2.1.0.xsd" xml:lang="en" meta="slc-id:S1-DAV19K34-MRN-VB-HJT"><!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.--> <meta>
<dc:title>116 SJRES 4 RS: Requiring the advice and consent of the Senate or an Act of Congress to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty and authorizing related litigation, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:type>Senate Joint Resolution</dc:type>
<docNumber>4</docNumber>
<citableAs>116 SJRES 4 RS</citableAs>
<citableAs>116sjres4rs</citableAs>
<citableAs>116 S. J. Res. 4 RS</citableAs>
<docStage>Reported in Senate</docStage>
<currentChamber>SENATE</currentChamber>
<dc:creator>United States Senate</dc:creator>
<processedBy>GPO XPub Bill to USLM Generator, version 0.5 + manual changes</processedBy>
<processedDate>2024-09-09</processedDate>
<dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<relatedDocument role="calendar" href="/us/116/scal/335">Calendar No. 335</relatedDocument>
<congress>116</congress>
<session>1</session>
<publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta>
<preface>
<slugLine>•SJ 4 RS</slugLine>
<distributionCode display="yes">IIA</distributionCode>
<relatedDocument role="calendar" href="/us/116/scal/335">Calendar No. 335</relatedDocument>
<congress value="116">116th CONGRESS</congress>
<session value="1">1st Session</session>
<dc:type>S. J. RES. </dc:type>
<docNumber>4</docNumber>
<dc:title>Requiring the advice and consent of the Senate or an Act of Congress to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty and authorizing related litigation, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<currentChamber value="SENATE">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</currentChamber>
<action><date date="2019-01-17"><inline class="smallCaps">January </inline>17, 2019</date><actionDescription><sponsor senateId="S362">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Kaine</inline></sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor senateId="S377">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Gardner</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S259">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Reed</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S293">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Graham</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S341">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Blumenthal</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S350">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Rubio</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S337">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Coons</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S252">Ms. <inline class="smallCaps">Collins</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S253">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Durbin</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S221">Mrs. <inline class="smallCaps">Feinstein</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S347">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Moran</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S393">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Jones</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S383">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Sullivan</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S306">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Menendez</inline></cosponsor>, <cosponsor senateId="S324">Mrs. <inline class="smallCaps">Shaheen</inline></cosponsor>, and <cosponsor senateId="S369">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Markey</inline></cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee addedDisplayStyle="italic" committeeId="SSFR00" deletedDisplayStyle="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee></actionDescription></action>
<action actionStage="Reported-in-Senate"><date><inline class="smallCaps">December </inline>17, 2019</date><actionDescription>Reported by <sponsor senateId="S323">Mr. <inline class="smallCaps">Risch</inline></sponsor>, with an amendment</actionDescription><actionInstruction>[Strike out all after the resolving clause and insert the part printed in italic]</actionInstruction></action></preface>
<main styleType="OLC"><longTitle><docTitle>JOINT RESOLUTION</docTitle><officialTitle>Requiring the advice and consent of the Senate or an Act of Congress to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty and authorizing related litigation, and for other purposes.</officialTitle></longTitle><resolvingClause><i>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States of America in Congress assembled, </i></resolvingClause>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s1" id="id41789E6DD815443BAF5CBB360CA68B0E" changed="deleted" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="1">SECTION 1. </num><heading>OPPOSITION OF CONGRESS TO SUSPENSION, TERMINATION, OR WITHDRAWAL FROM NORTH ATLANTIC TREATY.</heading><content class="block">The President shall not suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty, done at Washington, DC, April 4, 1949, except by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, provided that two thirds of the Senators present concur, or pursuant to an Act of Congress.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s2" id="id42754341F3AF4000BF2EAC63B9E770F6" changed="deleted" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="2">SEC. 2. </num><heading>LIMITATION ON THE USE OF FUNDS.</heading><content class="block">No funds authorized or appropriated by any Act may be used to support, directly or indirectly, any efforts on the part of any United States Government official to take steps to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty, done at Washington, DC, April 4, 1949, until such time as the Senate passes, by an affirmative vote of two-thirds of Members, a resolution advising and consenting to the withdrawal of the United States from the treaty or pursuant to an Act of Congress.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s3" id="id305BCA5F8062425B99DE9682A7B6109F" changed="deleted" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="3">SEC. 3. </num><heading>NOTIFICATION OF TREATY ACTION.</heading><content class="block">The President shall notify the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives in writing of any effort to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty, as soon as possible but in no event later than 48 hours after any such action is taken.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s4" id="id560E006EABAB4A83AB37F3AE77721D8A" changed="deleted" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="4">SEC. 4. </num><heading>AUTHORIZATION OF LEGAL COUNSEL TO REPRESENT CONGRESS.</heading><content class="block">Both the Senate Legal Counsel and the General Counsel to the House of Representatives are authorized to independently or collectively represent Congress in initiating or intervening in any judicial proceedings in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction on behalf of Congress in order to oppose any effort to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty in a manner inconsistent with this joint resolution.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s5" id="id77F718B88E124C938F89A1866B3180EE" changed="deleted" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="5">SEC. 5. </num><heading>REPORTING REQUIREMENT.</heading><content class="block">Any legal counsel operating pursuant to section 4 shall report as soon as practicable to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives with respect to any judicial proceedings which the Senate Legal Counsel or the General Counsel to the House of Representatives, as the case may be, initiates or in which it intervenes pursuant to this resolution.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s1" id="idbbbfc888-f6ab-4c1a-a7d2-9e111d00d01f" changed="added" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="1">SECTION 1. </num><heading>OPPOSITION OF CONGRESS TO SUSPENSION, TERMINATION, DENUNCIATION, OR WITHDRAWAL FROM NORTH ATLANTIC TREATY.</heading><content class="block">The President shall not suspend, terminate, denounce, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty, done at Washington, DC, April 4, 1949, except by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, provided that two thirds of the Senators present concur, or pursuant to an Act of Congress.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s2" id="id6e482a5c-a935-4fdd-a274-dee54d9127d7" changed="added" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="2">SEC. 2. </num><heading>LIMITATION ON THE USE OF FUNDS.</heading><content class="block">No funds authorized or appropriated by any Act may be used to support, directly or indirectly, any efforts on the part of any United States Government official to take steps to suspend, terminate, denounce, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty, done at Washington, DC, April 4, 1949, until such time as both the Senate and the House of Representatives pass, by an affirmative vote of two-thirds of Members, a joint resolution approving the withdrawal of the United States from the treaty or pursuant to an Act of Congress.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s3" id="id13b5fcba-aef6-49ef-b035-ce14ff9200c2" changed="added" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="3">SEC. 3. </num><heading>NOTIFICATION OF TREATY ACTION.</heading><content class="block">The President shall notify the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives in writing of any effort to suspend, terminate, denounce, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty, as soon as possible but in no event later than 48 hours after any such action is taken.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s4" id="id73b98b38-3e99-4db5-b3b1-35d2b1c82310" changed="added" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="4">SEC. 4. </num><heading>AUTHORIZATION OF LEGAL COUNSEL TO REPRESENT CONGRESS.</heading><content class="block">Both the Senate Legal Counsel and the General Counsel to the House of Representatives are authorized to independently or collectively represent Congress in initiating or intervening in any judicial proceedings in any Federal court of competent jurisdiction on behalf of Congress in order to oppose any effort to suspend, terminate, denounce, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty in a manner inconsistent with this joint resolution.</content></section>
<section identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s5" id="id0360439e-2071-4c76-8ac2-18573c13f509" changed="added" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="5">SEC. 5. </num><heading>REPORTING REQUIREMENT.</heading><content class="block">Any legal counsel operating pursuant to section 4 shall report as soon as practicable to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives with respect to any judicial proceedings which the Senate Legal Counsel or the General Counsel to the House of Representatives, as the case may be, initiates or in which it intervenes pursuant to section 4.</content></section>
<section role="definitions" identifier="/us/resolution/116/sjres/4/s6" id="id2BF0E770971447AF8EA1F129E8BA3480" changed="added" origin="#SSFR00"><num value="6">SEC. 6. </num><heading>DEFINITIONS.</heading><content class="block">In this resolution, the terms “<term>withdrawal</term>”, “<term>denunciation</term>”, “<term>suspension</term>”, and “<term>termination</term>” have the meaning given the terms in the Vienna Convention on the Law of Treaties, concluded at Vienna May 23, 1969.</content></section></main>
<endorsement orientation="landscape"><relatedDocument role="calendar" href="/us/116/scal/335">Calendar No. 335</relatedDocument><congress value="116">116th CONGRESS</congress><session value="1">1st Session</session><dc:type>S. J. RES. </dc:type><docNumber>4</docNumber><longTitle><docTitle>JOINT RESOLUTION</docTitle><officialTitle>Requiring the advice and consent of the Senate or an Act of Congress to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty and authorizing related litigation, and for other purposes.</officialTitle></longTitle><action><date date="2019-12-17"><inline class="smallCaps">December </inline>17, 2019</date><actionDescription>Reported with an amendment</actionDescription></action></endorsement></resolution>