<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><bill xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.0.3.xsd" xml:lang="en" class="mimicGPOPrint">
<meta><dc:title>115 HR 609 ENR: To designate the Department of Veterans Affairs health care center in Center Township, Butler County, Pennsylvania, as the “Abie Abraham VA Clinic”.</dc:title><dc:type>House Bill</dc:type><docNumber>609</docNumber><dc:creator>United States House of Representatives</dc:creator><dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher><dc:format>text/xml</dc:format><dc:language>EN</dc:language><dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights><docStage>ENR</docStage>
<processedBy>GPO Locator to USLM Converter 3.2.6;Stage2.20181004</processedBy><processedDate>2018-10-04</processedDate>
<congress>115</congress><session>1</session><publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate></meta>
<preface><dc:type>H. R.</dc:type><docNumber>609</docNumber><congress style="-uslm-lc:I665502" value="115">One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session style="-uslm-lc:I665503" value="1">AT THE FIRST SESSION</session><enrolledDateline style="-uslm-lc:I665504">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolledDateline></preface>
<main>
<longTitle>
<docTitle style="-uslm-lc:I665505" class="centered fontsize18">An Act</docTitle>
<officialTitle style="-uslm-lc:I665511" class="centered fontsize8">To designate the Department of Veterans Affairs health care center in Center Township, Butler County, Pennsylvania, as the “Abie Abraham VA Clinic”.<?GPOvSpace 08?></officialTitle>
</longTitle>
<enactingFormula style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa­tives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</enactingFormula>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I650146"><num value="1">SECTION 1. </num><heading>FINDINGS.</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I650120" class="indent0 fontsize10">  Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="1">  (1)</num><content> Abie Abraham of Lyndora, Pennsylvania, was stationed during World War II with the 18th Infantry in New York; 3 years with the 14th Infantry in Panama; 15th Infantry, unassigned in China, while the U.S.S. Panay was sunk; 30th Infantry, Presidio, San Francisco; and the 31st Infantry, Manila, Philippines, for 9 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="2">  (2)</num><content> During World War II, Abraham fought, was captured, endured the Bataan Death March and as a prisoner of war for 3½ years, was beaten, stabbed, shot, survived malaria and starvation to be rescued by the 6th Rangers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="3">  (3)</num><content> Abraham stayed behind at the request of General Douglas MacArthur for 2½ more years disinterring the bodies of his fallen comrades from the Bataan Death March and the prison camps, helping to identify their bodies and see that they were properly laid to rest.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="4">  (4)</num><content> After his promotion in 1945, Abraham came back to the United States where he served as a recruiter and then also served 2 years in Germany until his retirement with 30 years of service as a Master Sergeant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="5">  (5)</num><content> Abraham received numerous medals for his service, including the Purple Heart, and had several documentaries on the Discovery Channel and History Channel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="6">  (6)</num><content> Abraham wrote the books “Ghost of Bataan Speaks” in 1971 and “Oh, God, Where Are You” in 1977 to help the public better understand what our brave men endured at the hands of the Imperial Japanese Army as prisoners of war.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="7">  (7)</num><content> Abraham was a life member of the Veterans of Foreign Wars, the American Legion, the Purple Heart Combat/Infantry Organization, the American Ex-POWs, the Disabled American Veterans, and the American Defenders of Bataan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I650122" class="indent1 fontsize10"><num value="8">  (8)</num><content> Abraham was a volunteer at Veterans Affairs Butler Healthcare for 23 years from 1988 to 2011 and had 36,851 service hours caring for our veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I650141"><num value="2">SEC. 2. </num><heading>ABIE ABRAHAM VA CLINIC.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I650120" class="indent0 fontsize10"><num value="a">  (a)</num><heading><inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Department of Veterans Affairs health care center in Center Township, Butler County, Pennsylvania, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the “Abie Abraham VA Clinic”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I650120" class="indent0 fontsize10"><num value="b">  (b)</num><heading><inline class="small-caps">References</inline>.—</heading><content>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the health care center referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the “Abie Abraham VA Clinic”.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</main>
<signatures>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></signature>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Vice President of the United States and  President of the Senate.</role></signature>
</signatures>
</bill>